What was the protocol,
Kosta?
Raymond?
How?
The last time I saw you,
you said you were going to
meet your fate.
You may very well
be about to meet yours.
I don't understand.
Neither do I.
Which is why I'm here.
The plan.
I want to hear
from your lips
how the plan
was supposed to work.
To begin with?
You were supposed to die.
Then Elizabeth would be given
specific instructions
on how to
make her way here.
I would be waiting.
Elizabeth is dead.
For several years now.
You didn't think something was
wrong when she
never showed up?
Well, you never told me
how long to wait.
So I kept
the lanterns burning.
Mm.
The noble lighthouse keeper
at the end of the world.
It would be poetic, if you
hadn't betrayed my trust.
I would never.
The recordings
for Elizabeth.
You saw me put them
inside the safe.
Yes. In the screening room.
No one has
been in there since.
Then why did I find these
on the other side
of the world?
But how?
Bocce balls.
I figure when in Rome.
We're in Montenegro.
Sciatica's acting up.
Haven't been
in this much pain
since I threw out my back
dancing at a sock hop in 1974.
Who is that?
That's your fate.
He and his bocce balls
are here
to find out
what really happened.
I hope you slept well, Kosta.
It's going to be a long day.
Good morning, Director.
Good morning, Director, sir.
Um...
I'm Agent Mojtabai.
I'm-- I'm Mr. Mojta--
No. Okay.
I'm Aram.
How did I forget
how to do this?
I was shocked to see
your name on my phone sheet.
How've you been?
Um... I've been better.
I forgot.
You actually do honesty.
Well, the last couple months
haven't been the best.
Things didn't quite work out
at the Bureau.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear it.
The task force I was on
got shut down
because of the death
of a colleague, and, um...
I just couldn't find
my passion in it anymore.
I meant I'm sorry
to hear you say it to me.
You may not remember,
but commiseration's
not my strong suit.
I mean,
if we're being honest.
Oh, I remember.
In fact, Nick, uh, that--
that's why I'm here.
Because what I remember
is that you are
completely selfish.
And this...
This is
a million-dollar idea.
Okay. I'm interested.
So, you know how most security
systems are defensive, right?
They detect a threat
and shut it down.
Well, this software--
this software is offensive.
When it detects an intrusion,
it activates its own
built-in Trojan rootkit
to attack the intruder.
It then throws out
colossal floods
of junk traffic
to clog them up
while it eviscerates
their operating system
in the process.
That is not
a million-dollar idea.
It's a billion-dollar one.
This won't just
protect people.
It will actively
discourage black hats.
It'll revolutionize
tech security.
Right?
That is what I was going for,
but I have no idea how to
turn my idea into a business,
which is why I'm here.
Of course, um, if, uh--
if you're too busy
or, you know, need, um,
some time to think it over--
I am too busy,
and I've already
thought about it.
I'm in.
You've reached
Naamah Mojtabai.
Leave a message
and have a blessed day.
Hey. Uh, it's me.
Um, I could--
I could really use, um--
I could use a Mom Talk
right about now.
Um, well, I have
my first, uh, briefing
with the Director of National
Intelligence this morning,
and I am low-key freaking out.
Um, if you get this, like,
in the next 10 minutes
and you can call me back
or so, that would be super,
um, super.
So...
Yo! Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Greetings
from El Conejo.
I thought I'd thought
of everything.
A villa that no one knew
I owned.
A place of peace
and quiet.
A place where Elizabeth could
listen and prepare.
She was
to retrieve the box,
sit right here...
And learn the business.
From you.
I put all of it
into these recordings.
Every bit of it.
I knew I wouldn't be there
to help her,
but I thought perhaps
my words could,
that they would provide
whatever might be needed.
And Kosta's job
was to wait for her.
And to bring her here
when she arrived.
So she could
open the safe.
The safe
is one-of-a-kind.
I had it constructed
in Switzerland
to my specifications.
Two thumbprints in the world
could open it.
Mine and/or Elizabeth's.
And you put this box
inside of it.
Yes.
And a few days ago,
I found it
in a dead cop's vault
5,000 miles
away from here.
The safe looks untouched.
How do you think
they got inside it?
I haven't a clue.
Hence the bocce balls.
We've been over it
and over it.
So we just go over it again.
And expect
a different result?
You do know that's
the definition of insanity.
Panabaker gave you a month
to identify who killed
Doug Koster
before all those charges
against you are reimposed.
Now, it would be
insane of us
not to do everything
that we can
to prevent that
from happening.
I feel like I'm living
in purgatory.
Worse, it feels like
Charlene and Agnes
are living there with me.
Hey,
anyone seen Aram today?
He's not in yet?
Haven't seen him, sir.
I think you can
drop the "sir."
To be honest,
I never liked it much.
I prefer "Harold."
Well, Harold, it's not
like Aram to be late.
No, but he had
his first meeting
with National Intelligence
today.
Maybe he had to run home after
and change his shirt.
Hm. Or his shorts.
I know we're on the clock
with the investigation,
but if he needs a pep talk
about what his new
responsibilities are,
I think I'm the one
who should give it.
Mrs. Mojtabai.
Oh.
Are you alright?
What happened?
I don't know.
He called me.
He said he wanted
to have a mom talk.
You said he called.
What else did he say?
We didn't talk.
He left a message.
Please find him.
Okay.
Ah.
My package has arrived.
I thought there'd be
more to you.
Who are you?
What am I doing here?
I am Don Francisco
Luis Marquez.
El Conejo to my best friends
and worst enemies.
I know who you are,
Special Agent Mojtabai.
And you stole from me.
If you get this, like,
in the next 10 minutes
and you can call me back
or so, that would be super,
um, super.
Yo! Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Greetings from El Conejo.
That came
from Aram's mother.
The entire abduction
was recorded.
Who's El Conejo,
and what's he want with Aram?
As to the what,
I haven't the foggiest.
The who
I can help you with.
Dembe and I once chased
"The Rabbit"
along an underground river
in the jungle in Quintana Roo.
El Conejo
is Don Marquez?
The Marquez Cartel.
The cocaine traffickers.
Cocaine
was their business.
Now they traffic
in a different cash crop.
You know what it takes
to grow one of these?
I never used
to interest myself
in such things.
I'm more
of an import/export man.
Avocados are
a multibillion-dollar industry
run by family farming
operations.
Or it was,
before the cartels took over
through kidnapping,
torture, and murder.
Think about that the next time
you order a Cobb salad.
I-I gotta say, I-I'm still,
uh, wondering why I'm here.
You know why,
you magician, you.
You made an entire
tractor trailer of my product
disappear into thin air
on its way over the border.
I did?
Now I'm out half a million,
and my competitors
think I'm soft.
Sir, I have no idea
where your truck is.
If I did,
I would tell you.
Uh, this is--
Uh, this is terrifying.
I put in military-grade
firewalls,
elliptic curve cryptography--
all of it state-of-the-art
to protect my supply chains
and travel lines.
What's terrifying
is that a piece of malware
chewed through it like a--
Like a termite
through balsa wood.
Marquez runs
his whole cartel
through a notoriously
sophisticated server system.
If there's a connection
to Aram,
you have to assume that's it.
That's not much of a lead.
No, but this is.
The Scripps Brothers.
They built the server.
How do you know that?
Because Marquez
wanted my guy to do it,
but my guy's exclusive to me
and has a curfew--
And a very stern mother.
So he recommended
the Scripps Brothers.
I'd pay them a visit myself,
but I'm unavailable
at the moment.
But I'll get you an address
for the Scripps.
They're the best place
to start.
You've got the wrong guy.
Oh, I-I've worked on
a lot of programs,
but I've never designed
anything in my life
to hurt someone
or-- or cause--
Armando.
So--
It took my team
half the day to find it
buried in the malware.
Maybe you acted alone.
Maybe you did it
for the FBI.
I don't particularly care.
But this has your name
all over it.
Impressive stuff.
If I didn't have to kill you,
I'd hire you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Stop, stop!
Please, please.
Stop, stop, stop.
Before you do whatever
you're planning to do,
can I please-- can I please
take a look at that?
You want me to hand you
my computer?
After everything
you've done?
Sir, I have no idea
where your shipment is.
I do not know
what that program is.
But if you give me
that laptop, maybe--
Maybe I can
help you figure this out.
So, Teddy, who did it?
I don't know,
'cause he doesn't know.
Go back in there.
Did I mention
my sciatica?
Teddy.
Like getting poked in
the tenderloin by a narwhal!
Want me to go in?
It won't matter.
If Teddy says
Kosta doesn't know
who broke into the safe,
he doesn't know.
We'll have to find the answer
some other way.
Maybe you
know the answers.
Me?
Not you. You.
The two of you
have been arrested
by the NSA
seven times each?
Eight for me.
Shut up.
And, Ritchie, you can't even
touch a computer in Norway
without the threat
of immediate arrest.
How did you piss off Norway
that bad?
Lawyer. Lawyer. Lawyer.
Look, geek squad, we don't
care about how many gigabytes
you move around
in your mother's basement.
An FBI agent is missing
and the clock's ticking
on his life.
Okay. Suit yourself.
But you're not gonna like
what comes next.
Okay, cop.
Hey, that's all our stuff.
And seeing
how it was used
to help build
a drug cartel's firewall,
the FBI will be
impounding all of it.
But you can't do that.
We just did.
Don't worry, though.
You'll get it all back.
Eventually.
That was a $5,000
8K monitor!
We're real clumsy
around here.
Let me get you a receipt
for that.
No, no, no, no.
We can do this all day long.
Now, you wanna
help us out, fellas,
and maybe we'll give you
this cart of crap back
in one piece.
Some of it, anyway.
Okay, okay.
Just don't bust anything else.
What do you need?
Bad code is--
is like a bad recipe.
A pinch of this,
a dash of that.
To reverse engineer it,
though, you--
You're working
without a cookbook.
You're in the States?
No one told me
you were coming.
It's not a good time, Antonio.
We'll talk about it later.
I hear it
from my brother--
I'm here on business.
Samuel works
in the business.
You go to college.
There. We talked.
Now go.
No.
What happens here, I don't
want you to be a part of it.
What about
what I want?
I-I see you, what?
Twice a year?
Great.
Sic the goons on me.
Drop me a postcard
next time you're around.
Or don't.
Um, Mr. Marquez,
I found something.
Okay, uh, this here,
this building block
is part of a longer code
I wrote for a program
called Greylock.
That is why I signed my name
to it like that.
As a joke.
So this was all you?
No. No, this--
the rest of this isn't me.
Somebody stole my work.
So this is
the Marquez network.
You get in and out
just like that?
We built a back door.
Sue us.
So what do you
want to know?
Anything that tells us
where Marquez took our agent.
Don't even have to look
that hard.
The guy you're missing's
some kind of tech wizard,
yeah?
How do you know that?
There's a user
in the network now
poking around at everything.
It's some serious
bandwidth.
Can you get us
a location?
I wrote some of this,
but someone weaponized
the rest.
The rootkit I wrote
to attack intruders
was used to gut
your firewall
and gain access
to your shipping lines.
There is somebody out there
who targeted you
and they used
my work to do it.
Wait a minute.
What?
Someone built
an apex predator.
You could use it
to rob banks,
to disrupt utility services,
take down power grids.
Right now, I just want
the shipment back.
Who is this? How the hell
did you get this number?
I have your missing product.
Half a million. Cash.
I'll call in one hour
with delivery instructions.
Get Samuel.
And lock up the agent.
I'll deal with him later.
Hello, Elizabeth.
I hope you're comfortable,
sitting down
with something good to drink.
There's always plenty to eat
in the larder.
So please feel free
at any time
to shut me up
and help yourself.
If you're watching this,
I must be dead
and the business
must be yours.
I'm relieved.
And excited for you.
And worried,
as you might expect.
It's strange.
Even with all the gunfire
and killers in my life,
I've never really worried
about myself.
I've been much too busy
worrying about you.
Oh, my God, what a pain
in the ass I've been.
Anyway.
What lies ahead is a glorious,
treacherous, and, I hope,
rewarding journey.
If you'll permit me,
I'd like to share with you
some things that I've learned
over a lifetime of bad deeds
and good intentions.
So let's take a walk
together one last time.
Congratulations,
you genius son-of-a--
We did it.
You know what this means?
It means we can start planning
to sell this thing.
I, uh-- I still think
we should tinker.
There are some diagnostics I
want to take another look at--
Aram, you're killing me.
Well, it's not ready
till it's ready.
When?
The next epoch?
We have
the VitasNow report.
They gave us
a clean bill of health.
We paid a third party
for their assessment--
To find flaws, problems,
data gaps,
things we could've missed,
right?
They're only one company.
Who double-checked
everything.
Our I's are dotted,
T's are crossed.
I read it. You read it.
Relax. It's time to celebrate.
Yeah, but they did, uh,
point out a few glitches
with peripherals--
Oh, please, no jargon.
You know I don't
speak circuit board.
They didn't spot anything that
couldn't be patched up easily.
Bottom line--
they were happy for us.
And I'm happy for us,
'cause we're gonna be
stinking rich.
You know
what we need now?
More champagne
and a strip club.
Oh, I-I can't.
Uh, I, uh-- I actually
have dinner plans
with my parents tonight.
Aram, seriously.
You're killing me.
FBI!
Go, go, go!
FBI! Hands! Hands!
Hey, bud.
How's your morning going?
How'd you find me?
HRT is clearing the space.
No sign of Marquez.
Uh, he got a ransom call
about avocados.
Apparently guacamole
is the new angel dust.
We managed
to bag this one.
Let's hope
he knows something.
There's a lot to the shipping.
But the most crucial part
of shipping--
Sun Tzu wrote,
"The greatest victory
is that which requires
no battle."
I would agree.
If you want to make your enemy
your friend,
create a problem for them
and then solve it.
It's that simple.
You'll want to take notes now.
The following is a list
of 12 wines
that pair with everything.
I've said a lot
about the mechanics
of how to operate my--
uh, your empire.
But much more important
than that
is managing
the emotional reality
of running this enterprise.
And to do that, you must
understand one concept
above all else.
You have thousands
of talented people
who work for and with you,
thousands of people
who you are responsible for.
But at the end of the day,
you're alone.
Nick. Uh, me again.
We need to talk.
Uh, you have my number.
Uh, thank you.
You should go to a hospital.
No, I got a better idea--
Us figuring out
why you were kidnapped
by a bloodthirsty
avocado cartel.
Uh, the why is easy--
Marquez thinks I hacked
into his system,
accessed
his delivery routes,
and stole his product,
but it wasn't me.
But he found your digital
signature in his system.
Yes. Uh, which means
my Greylock source code
was stolen
by our avocado thief.
Who had access to it,
besides you?
Uh, my former
business partner, Nick,
but he doesn't know HTML
from hieroglyphics,
and, for like a second,
this third-party
risk assessment firm
we hired to spotlight
any glitches.
I-It was early on,
but they definitely had a copy
of unlocked source code.
Can I make a suggestion?
Of course.
Well, we have
two avenues here.
Someone set up Aram.
We need to know who.
We also need
to track Marquez.
A man like that is never
in the States long.
This may be our one shot
at getting a cartel leader.
So we divide and conquer.
Aram follows up with
the third-party company.
Someone's in charge there.
Bring them in,
get to the bottom of this.
The rest of you should focus
on getting whatever
information you can
out of our new guest.
What do you think?
Let's do it.
Thank you for that.
Anytime, boss.
Antonio?
It was a long drive
back to Princeton.
I knew the place
was empty--
This is a safehouse,
not a crash pad.
Get out of here.
What is it?
Que paso?
The FBI raided
the downtown warehouse.
They grabbed Machado.
They took back their agent.
Agent? Th-Th-That was an agent
you had captive?
Why do you think
I wanted you
out of there?
For your own good.
A business matter.
The FBI--
Yeah, it is dangerous.
That's why you need
to let us handle it.
You should never
be deceived into believing
that you can really
trust anyone.
My experience is that even
my most intimate partners,
advisers, and friends have
had occasion to betray me.
You must always be
mentally prepared
to separate yourself
from anyone
and anything in your life.
Because people will turn.
You know what
I'm talking about.
You witnessed it
with Mr. Kaplan.
Hell, you've done it yourself.
I'm sorry if I made it sound
all doom and gloom.
Lonely.
It's not.
There's a freedom
in your new role.
Freedom from convention.
From being a follower.
The pack takes its cue
from the alpha wolf.
And when that wolf
is wise and mindful,
the whole pack prospers.
That said, you will
have one blind spot,
one weakness that
can't be willed out of you.
And that's Agnes.
I have no advice
for you there.
All I can tell you is, uh,
do your best,
My company is highly respected
in the industry.
I don't know what you
think happened with
your source code--
You turned my software
into a weapon.
You took something
meant to help
and protect people
and stripped it for parts
until it was dangerous.
Agent Mojtabai,
I've reviewed your file.
Based on what I saw,
nothing you've said here
surprises me,
except that you blame us for
a problem of your own making.
What are you
talking about?
You hired us to do
an independent review
of your source code.
Our conclusions
were clear.
Perhaps you've forgotten
how clear.
You must not have read
our report.
I brought you
another copy.
I read it
cover-to-cover.
My business partner,
Nick, read it, too.
Then you didn't
read it thoroughly.
See for yourself.
Aside from
a few minor glitches,
you gave us
a clean bill of health.
What are these sections?
Implementations?
Vulnerabilities?
I've never seen
any of these.
Dammit, Nick.
See, no one needed to turn
your software into a weapon.
Because I built a weapon
from the start.
What time do Conroy and
the others get here tomorrow?
15, and the buyers should
arrive shortly after that.
You knew
this whole time.
Sorry, you're not supposed
to be in here.
It's okay, Chloe.
This is the godfather
of Greylock.
The man who invented us.
Everything we've accomplished
is because of him.
What happened to you?
You fall off your bike?
Remember this?
I had a little chat
with Walter Sykes
from VitasNow,
and this is
their full report,
with all those sections
you didn't bother to show me.
You know, the ones that said
there's vulnerability
in the Greylock
source code?
I don't know if you took
a look around on the way in,
but we're way
past source code.
Remember Conroy?
All that financing?
That was
just the beginning.
We're pitching
buyers tomorrow.
Sky's the limit.
You lied to me.
I sat right there
and you lied to my face.
I omitted.
I held a few things back.
What did this company know
that you and I didn't?
If something was really wrong,
you would've fixed it.
You know I was too close
to the project.
I couldn't see it.
That is why we hired them.
Do you know how dangerous
this could be?
If the wrong person
with the right know-how
got access to Greylock,
they could strip it down
to its most dangerous parts
and use it
to cripple systems.
Systems have flaws.
So do people.
And I won't destroy
this company
because a bad guy
might misuse what we made.
They make
baseball bats, Aram.
Even though someone
might use it
to crack somebody
over the head--
You can't
keep selling this.
I can as long as clients
want to buy it.
There might be a few bad eggs.
It happens.
I want this program out there
so the rest of our customers
can use it
for the good you intended.
No. You want it out there
so you can be rich.
Chloe was right.
You shouldn't be in here.
You should leave.
It's too soon for Marquez
to have gotten
out of the country.
Where's he hiding?
In the city? Nearby?
I don't know
where he is.
But I know
where he's gonna be.
How would you know that?
I overheard El Conejo
get the second phone call
about his missing shipment.
I know the time and the place
for the exchange.
I'll share it,
for a trade.
What trade?
I want to be sent back
to Mexico for trial.
Oh, let me guess--
Because you've got a friend in
the Fiscalia General's office?
There's not gonna be
any trial, will there?
You wanna worry about
a little fish like me?
Or go after the big fish
like Marquez?
You kidnapped an FBI agent?
You threatened him
over a truckload of,
what, vegetables?
Avocados are a fruit,
imbecile.
You're sick.
The both of you.
This whole thing...
Since the day you were born,
I knew you were weak.
You were built to sit
behind a desk or a library.
I saw it, and I let you
stay soft-- to keep you safe.
But if you ever question
my judgment
or my control again,
so help me, boy,
you will learn a lesson
in what a real man of power
can do.
Now, you wait here,
until we're long gone.
There will come a time,
Elizabeth,
when you are
completely stumped,
a time when you will have
factored in every variable
and you still
won't see the answer.
But it'll be there.
Somewhere.
The answer is--
is always there.
And when you can't see it,
it's because some assumption
that you've made,
something you've taken
for granted is false.
You think you're in a hospital
in France.
It may not be France
or a hospital.
It may be New York
and a warehouse.
The magician
doesn't trick you.
The magician helps you
trick yourself.
That looks fun.
Cheecha's a god-send.
I'm pain free and looser
than a kangaroo's tummy.
I think it's a trick,
an illusion.
He figured it out.
Ooh. Yeah. Oh, baby! Aah!
I wanted to know
who got into my safe.
I should've been asking
whether this is my safe.
They tore mine out.
You can see
exactly where there.
And they replaced it
with a perfect replica.
Then they were free to take
the original safe somewhere
and drill for days
if they needed to.
How did Kosta not know?
Oh.
An afternoon away.
An evening at the opera.
Doesn't matter.
That was then.
The now is in Zurich.
And his name is
Heinrich Zimmerstahl.
I brought your ransom.
But we both know you're never
gonna touch a dollar.
Because
you're not leaving.
This place is now
your graveyard.
I bury you here.
What are you doing?
We don't have
the shipment yet.
Look around.
His only way out of here
is through us,
and he won't even
get that far.
What if I want
to get caught?
Antonio?
What in God's name
are you doing?
Do I still seem weak to you?
Like I belong behind a desk?
You gotta be joking.
How many years of it
do you think I could stand it,
Dad?
Of what?
Of not being allowed to know
about the family business.
Of not getting a phone call
when my own father
is just a few hours away.
You're not strong enough.
You mean
not Samuel enough.
It has nothing
to do with Samuel.
I always wanted
the best for you. Always!
You wanted me gone.
The college boy in America.
I outsmarted you.
I took your truck.
I ransomed it back
right under your nose.
What do you say to that?
Am I strong enough now?
Get down!
FBI!
You think you're
so smart, huh?
Don't move!
Down!
You led the FBI
right to us.
Me? How about you
and your ego?
Kidnapping.
Calling attention to yourself.
Like a fool.
It was you?
This whole time?
I did
what I had to do.
Look.
He's paying attention now.
You want my attention?
You want to be part
of this business?
Okay. Okay, how about
we de-escalate?
There's a cost
to this business!
You can talk about it
in family therapy tomorrow.
And this is what happens
when you cross El Conejo.
Gun!
- Drop it!
- I got it.
Ah!
You're okay.
He needs an ambulance.
Do you?
I'm fine.
But I'm never touching
an avocado again.
I almost died today
because of you, kid.
Twice.
I didn't think
it would go that far.
he would...
How are you even
involved in this?
It was my code you used
to hack your dad's business.
Really?
Th-That's cool.
Cool?
How did you even get ahold
of it to begin with?
Uh, my roommate
at Princeton.
He's a
computer science major.
He saw a beta test version
of the--
Of your software
in his programming class.
He made some minor tweaks,
took the rootkit,
made it offensive,
saw how dangerous
and adaptable it was,
and said he needed
to test it out.
I had the perfect target--
my father.
Your roommate weaponized
my code in a dorm room?
He said it was
the perfect weapon.
You should know.
You built it.
I'm sorry, Kosta.
I would never betray you,
Raymond, but I did fail.
You left this house safe
with me,
and somehow,
I let the enemy slip inside.
I walked by that safe
hundreds of times,
and I had no idea.
You wouldn't have.
I didn't see it.
It was just
a good guess.
When this is over,
the house and everything in it
are yours.
Keep it, sell it.
I don't care.
It's all yours.
You'll forgive me if I let you
see yourself out.
Mr. Zimmerstahl
has arrived.
Raymond.
It's been years.
I was telling
your associate here
about the first time
we met.
The St. Moritz
Snow Polo World Cup, 2005.
I haven't gone near a drop
of peppermint schnapps since.
Come with me.
When I came to see you
all those years ago,
I told you I needed
a particularly secure safe.
I told you that safe needed
to be one-of-a-kind.
Do you remember?
I do.
You're really going through
with it, huh?
I can think of a thousand
terrible things
the wrong person could do
if the Greylock code
went wide,
but what scares me most are
the things I cannot think of.
I have to stop this
before Nick
gets more funding.
You're doing
the right thing.
Watch your step.
Oh, dear.
What happened? Ah.
That box was one of the finest
I'd ever constructed.
I couldn't agree more.
One of the finest.
The problem--
that's not my safe.
My safe is gone, and the one
in its place is identical.
One person is capable
of that kind of craftsmanship.
You.
You built a second safe,
didn't you?
Well, of course I did.
Excuse me?
I made a second.
Identical.
For whom?
Raymond, I made it for you.
Having problems
with your source code, Nick?
Is this you?
Did you do this?
Nothing in Greylock
will respond.
And you didn't even start
the space camp program
for those kids.
What?
It's over, Nick.
I went into the servers.
I undid the architecture,
framework, databases--
Aram, I have a buyers'
presentation in 10 minutes.
Conroy's in there.
Three other angels.
What am I
supposed to tell them?
Tell them the truth.
Dude.
It's not too late.
You can fix it.
I could, but I won't.
And it would take the best
IT team in the world months
to undo what I did.
Oh.
Do you have any idea
what's already been done
with our software?
A couple of idiot kids
in a dorm room
used it to hack
a drug cartel.
What about the next person
who gets their hands on it
and knows how to modify
the rootkit?
I don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
And I don't think
you ever did.
My code was never safe
with you.
You know what you tell them
in the other room?
You tell them that
your ex-business partner
did what he set out
to do.
He tried to make the world
a little safer.
Can you come in a minute?
Reggie Cole is dead.
The trail on the gunman
went cold,
but there is one lead
left to follow.
The lawyer.
What was his name?
Lacroix.
The man must've
had associates,
a legal practice, a family.
Let's find out everything
we can about him.
Sure.
What do we have to lose?
I have everything to lose,
but that's not gonna stop me.
I'm so sorry, Raymond.
I had no idea you were
going to be robbed.
You say you made
the duplicate for me?
Well, no.
Not you directly.
Then who?
A woman.
She came to me and she said
she was your representative.
She knew
everything about you.
She knew everything
about the safe.
She was clear
she wanted it made
to the same specifications
as the original.
She paid with
the same bank accounts.
The only thing different
was using uncoded
ready-to-set biometric panels
for the thumb scan.
So anyone could open
the new one.
At the time, I assumed
you'd simply set it later.
Tell me everything that you
can remember about the woman.
Oof. It was so long ago.
I remember glasses.
She wasn't very tall.
I do remember
one other thing.
Go on.
It happened several times.
She called me "deary."
Deary?
And she called herself
"Mister."
Kaplan?
Yes, Raymond.
Mr. Kaplan.