(DOOR CREAKS)
****
Colleague?
Yes.
And a friend.
****
(CAMERA BEEPS, GUNSHOT)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
(SIGHS)
****
DIENER: Will you be
staying for the autopsy?
No.
****
(PEN CLICKS)
But could I
have a moment?
Of course.
****
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN, CLOSES)
Dear God,
I pray to you for her.
Grant her eternal rest.
Let light shine upon her.
And may her soul
rest in peace.
You're absolutely certain.
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
Yes. Apartment 3B.
Vandyke lived there
or stayed there?
We've gone through this.
Indulge me.
(SIGHS)
The GPS data points
that plotted Vandyke's
whereabouts
the day Elizabeth
was killed...
I went to each one.
Every step he took
that day, I've taken.
Every store, restaurant,
apartment building.
3B.
I showed the super
his photo and my badge.
Vandyke lived there,
off and on.
Helen Field.
Sister? Friend? Girlfriend?
Comrade in arms?
I still don't know yet.
Weecha and I will
take a run at Miss Field.
You have a case to solve.
More important
than solving this?
It might be
to Agent Park.
****
Hey.
What are you
doing here?
Looking at you.
You look good.
Marriage suits you.
How's Perry?
Peter's fine.
Mm.
I was just texting him
to see what he wants me
to order him.
You've introduced him
to our spot.
I can't decide if I should
be jealous or touched.
You should be leaving,
preferably before
he gets here.
****
(SIGHS)
(LIGHTER CLICKS)
I have a job for you.
I already have a job.
I heard you left the Academy.
You heard?
Are you following me?
I'm trying to.
What you're doing now
I can't figure out,
but it can't be as exciting
as what we used to do.
What we did wasn't
exciting. Or legal.
It was extralegal
and necessary,
and you were good at it.
Which is why I'm here.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
I've helped start
an organization...
The Conglomerate.
The answer's no.
(CHUCKLES) You don't
even know the question.
Sure I do. And it's
not about work.
****
Well...
(SIGHS)
In case you
change your mind.
I won't.
****
I hope that's not true.
Hey!
Hi!
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
I'm Peter.
John.
Alina and I used to...
Work together.
Really?
Yeah.
Do tell.
(LAUGHS)
She likes to keep me
in the dark.
Oh, I bet.
(CHUCKLES)
John was just leaving.
See what I mean?
(SIGHS)
Another time.
It was nice to meet you.
Yeah.
Alina, it's always
a pleasure.
(CLEARS THROAT)
****
So, what'd you
do together?
Oh, uh, you know...
Kill people.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Right.
Serves me right
for asking.
Did you order?
I am starving.
I didn't.
But I'm... I'm sorry.
I got a text from work,
and I have to go.
I'm sorry.
(SIGHS) Don't be sorry.
Go. Save the planet.
Or whatever it is you do
that you can't tell me about.
I've been trying
to answer more.
And I'm trying
to ask less.
Look at us.
Quite a team.
****
We all know governments
sanction assassinations
through their intel agencies,
the CIA, MI6, SVR, Mossad.
According to Raymond,
four of these
contract killers
have formed a new organization
called the Conglomerate.
Do any of you know
anything about this?
Me?
No. I mean,
I've heard, uh, rumors,
whispers of a company
of assassins.
Is that what this is,
a company that's privatized
assassination?
Yes. And Raymond says
they're taking on clients.
Does he know the clients?
No.
Only the victims.
(BEEPS)
A supposedly untouchable
arms dealer,
a Kosovan minister
accused of terrorism,
a corrupt police chief.
RESSLER: I don't like it,
but at least they're
targeting the bad guys.
DEMBE: For now.
The Conglomerate serves
any ideology of any country.
If you can pay,
they will kill,
good guys or bad.
I'll reach out
to my contact
at Langley.
If I get his blessing,
we're good to go.
The way Raymond talked,
I thought you'd know more
about this.
No, I don't.
I'm not sure
what he was thinking.
****
(SIGHS)
What were you thinking?
Agent Park.
My wetwork is none
of your business,
or the task force's.
Bad timing, I'm afraid.
I have a pressing
engagement.
Did you know
they approached me?
Is that why
you gave us the case?
Because I'm not doing it
if that's what you're
worried about.
I'm not worried.
I'm late.
But stay.
Raid the fridge.
Why are you
doing this to me?
Wetwork is such
a delightfully
bland euphemism
for the act
of spilling blood.
Leave it to the Russians
to coin a phrase
so dripping
with sangfroid.
Why?
There's a tin
of Beluga caviar
in there.
It'll calm even your
frayed nerves, Agent Park.
Champagne, as well.
Close up
when you're done.
(SIGHS)
****
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
Alina Park?
John Richter.
I hear you've had
some excitement.
Hey!
(GRUNTS)
Do I know you?
The man you assaulted
has decided to press charges.
(SIGHS) The man I assaulted
was in the process
of assaulting a woman.
That's why
I assaulted him.
So if you're his lawyer...
I'm not.
Much to my mother's
disappointment,
I'm not a lawyer at all.
A cop then,
an investigator.
A fan.
****
It's not every day
I meet a woman
who smashes a man
across the head
with a bottle
of Grand Cuvee.
They were out of Jack.
(LAUGHS)
A sense of humor.
That wasn't in your file.
What file?
Are you happy
at the Academy?
Who are you?
****
Most people don't
realize that anger
is the purest expression
of care we have.
Rage comes from
a lack of control.
A fear you can't
protect yourself
or the people
you care about.
From the amount of anger
I noted in your file,
I imagine you're
an incredibly caring person.
(LIGHTER CLICKS)
That's why I'm here.
See for myself.
****
What do you
want from me?
Right now?
I can't think of anything
I don't want from you.
****
PARK: I wasn't honest before.
I do know about
the Conglomerate.
In fact,
I was asked to join it.
Wait. You were asked to join
a team of assassins.
Yes.
Why?
Because I am one.
****
(CHUCKLING) Okay.
Okay, that's funny.
That's funny.
Uh, for a second there,
I thought you actually
had a lead.
I do.
A member of the Conglomerate
gave me that this morning.
He's ex-CIA.
He's recruiting me now
because he recruited me then.
You're with the Agency.
If I told you,
I'd have to kill you.
That's such a bad joke.
Except in this case,
it's true.
Okay, I'll bite.
Why is "not the Agency"
keeping a file on me?
****
(SIGHS)
Aye Su, an infamous
Burmese junta leader.
Aye Su is why the CIA
is interested in me?
He's a repressive
ethnic cleanser.
Okay. He's a monster.
What's that
got to do with me?
Your file suggests you have
a low tolerance for monsters.
Doesn't everyone?
It also suggests
you're willing to do
something about it.
ARAM: Wait. Hold on.
You make it sound like
it was just a pickup line.
Like he sat down
and was like,
"Hey, uh, how ya doing?
"You, uh, wanna kill
a military strongman
for us?"
I didn't want to just "kill"
a military strongman.
I was asked by my government
to assassinate a monster.
And you said yes.
I'm still trying
to understand why.
PARK: Why don't I
want to date him?
Because he's a 30-year-old
who works in a movie theater.
ABBY: Don't play him
like that.
He runs a chain
of movie theaters.
Oh, my gosh,
that's so exciting.
Wait. Let me grab
my lingerie.
Boring is good.
Boring is 2.2 kids, a dog,
and a pension.
Fine. Have Mr. Boring call,
but it's not going anywhere.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
(CELL PHONE DIALS)
(LINE RINGS, CLICKS)
RICHTER: I knew you'd call.
If I say yes, what exactly
would I have to do?
PARK: After Keen died
and the task force broke up,
I was kind of lost.
Acting out, looking for...
Something, for a purpose.
And you found it
by assassinating
a dictator?
You may not
agree with it,
but, yeah, I did.
But only because
it was sanctioned
by the government,
because the people
who made the decisions
could be held accountable.
That's not happening
with the Conglomerate.
We can discuss that
fine distinction later.
For now, all I care about
is your willingness
to help us go after them.
Murder Incorporated?
Absolutely.
Even if it means using
this guy to get the names
of everyone else
in the organization.
Yeah. I'm willing.
Good. Then I want you
to call your contact.
Tell him that you're in.
(FABRIC RUSTLES)
Did you know that camels
have been domesticated
for over 4,000 years?
(CAMEL GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
Who are you?
What do you want?
Who I am is not important.
What matters is that you
are Helen from Apartment 3B.
If this is because of Ken,
I had nothing to do with that.
Amazing animals,
camels.
Their urine is said
to cure hair loss.
Say the word, I'll give
your scalp a tingle.
(LAUGHS)
What is going on?
Why am I here?
Are you two like
a couple of freaks?
Charles Vandyke.
You're here to tell me
about him.
Charlie?
(CAMEL GRUNTING)
I haven't seen him in years.
No, I'm sure.
Probably not since
I killed him.
Please, mister, I don't know
what it is you want,
but whatever it is,
I'll give it to you.
I want names. Friends.
Colleagues. Acquaintances.
And anything
Vandyke left behind.
Papers. Books.
Bank records.
Computers.
You look like
you collect things.
I want what
you've collected
from Charlie.
Okay.
Okay, yeah, sure.
Elizabeth Keen.
I-I don't know
who that is.
He never mentioned her?
(BUCKET THUMPS LIGHTLY)
Never.
Two quarts!
We're good to go.
I swear,
he never mentioned her.
We'll see.
(CAMEL GRUNTING)
(BREATHING QUICKLY)
****
He's here.
ARAM: Of course.
"Of course" what?
Samar's ex, this guy.
What is it with these, like,
supermodel-y assassins?
Hey.
I'm glad
you reached out.
I know what we're doing
is all cloak-and-dagger,
but a parking garage?
Yeah, sorry about that.
I have an appointment nearby,
but I wanted to see you,
so I figured I'd kill
two birds with one stone.
Tell me about
the Conglomerate.
Who's involved?
How's married life?
I'm not signing on
until I know the players.
Are you happy?
Would you hate me if I said
I hope you're not?
Peter and I are fine.
Mm.
You ever think about Cuba?
RESSLER: Cuba.
Let's think about Cuba.
****
Is there any chance
you're gonna focus
on why we're here?
Yeah. In a minute.
(VEHICLE APPROACHES)
****
Who's that?
My appointment.
Be right back.
Park, where is he going?
Is he on a job?
If he is,
we have to stop him.
If he's not and you run
in there, then I'm blown,
and we'll never learn
about the Conglomerate.
RESSLER: But that's a price
I'm willing to pay.
No, I'll go.
If it turns out to be nothing,
he won't be suspicious.
****
(GUN COCKS)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(DOOR CLOSES)
****
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(GUNSHOTS)
(THUDS)
(IN ENGLISH)
Park, are you okay?
We have to go.
I take it this means
you're in.
We have to go now.
****
COOPER: Do you have
any idea what you've done?
I never heard Harold
raise his voice.
Well, here's the reason
why he is.
COOPER: You saved an assassin
by assassinating his target!
Trouble in paradise?
Yeah. Stirred up by you.
(SCOFFS) By me?
Forgive me, I guess I was
under the false impression
that we were
all adults here.
Thank God we're not.
I saw a gun,
and I reacted.
The man you shot
could have been
a whistleblower
or an undercover cop.
He was Vor.
Yeah. But you
didn't know that.
All you knew was
that you were choosing
the life of a killer
over the life
of a stranger.
I don't know what
I'm more disturbed by,
your actions or the fact
that you can't seem
to acknowledge
that this was personal.
It was. It isn't now.
On comms, it sounded personal
to Ressler and Aram.
And before you say
that they're wrong
or there's nothing
going on...
There isn't.
Before you say something
that isn't 100% accurate,
I want you to stop.
Take a moment,
and know that,
given what happened
in that parking garage,
if you say anything
that falls short
of the absolute truth here,
I will let you go.
RESSLER: A turtle statue.
A tortoise.
Hingeback, I believe.
He's tied to it.
Your... Your tech guy.
For the next 36 hours.
Part of some kind of a...
Pledge drive or...
Or a pledge
of allegiance or...
Pledge week.
Yes! That's it.
A week of pledging.
To what,
I have no idea.
The point is,
he's indisposed,
and this can't wait.
It was Vandyke's.
I had a nice chat
with Helen from 3B.
Ah, which reminds me.
****
We brought
camel's milk.
We had some left over.
Do you have any idea
who helped Vandyke find Liz?
Not yet.
I'm hoping there's a lead
buried in here
that Agent Mojtabai
can root out.
PARK: I didn't know Liz
as well as you did.
But I'm only here
because of her.
She saw me,
warts and all,
and, for whatever reason,
embraced that.
Losing her was like losing
my guardian angel,
and whatever rage wagon
I was on, I fell off it.
Until I met John.
He gave me purpose.
(VACUUM WHIRRING)
(SPEAKING BURMESE)
(WHIRRING CONTINUES)
****
(SILENCED GUNSHOTS)
(GROANS)
(THUDS)
(SHELLS CLATTERING)
****
REDDINGTON:
(IN ENGLISH) It's salty.
Very.
A little disgusting.
But sort of delicious.
There's, uh,
nothing encrypted,
but there is, uh, this.
A series of GPS coordinates
from the day Liz died.
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
We already mapped Vandyke
using his phone's GPS.
Right, uh, we did.
And, uh, well,
they might be the same,
but, uh, maybe not,
so I'm putting
the phone coordinates
in blue
and the computer
coordinates in red,
and if I overlay them...
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
DEMBE: They don't overlap.
Except in two places.
The... The cafe where
you gave Liz the letter
and the restaurant
where Liz was killed.
So two people
were following her.
No, only one.
Well, if Vandyke's blue,
then who's red?
Elizabeth.
Train. Safe house.
Coffee shop. Restaurant.
He was tracking her.
Using her phone?
ARAM: I don't think so.
This, uh... This software
received signals
from a next-gen
tracking device.
I mean, if we can find
the tracker,
it might have a signature
or something
that could tell us
who made it.
And whoever made it
either wanted Keen dead
or was working
for the person who did.
We need to find that device.
COOPER: I appreciate that you
were vulnerable at the time.
And it may have felt
that he was giving you
purpose.
But I see it as
taking advantage of you.
Yes, but...
He also
helped get me out.
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING BURMESE)
(IN ENGLISH) You were
gonna wait in the car.
Well, what can I say?
I missed you.
(GUNSHOTS)
****
Come on.
Okay.
Out of curiosity,
if I took a bullet for you,
would you let me
take you out?
That's about
the only way I would.
Hey, hey!
Ohh!
(GUNSHOTS)
You know,
I hear Playa Paraiso's
beautiful this time of year.
(BREATHES SHARPLY)
PARK: He was right.
It was beautiful
that time of year.
You said that Richter invited
you to meet his partners,
that they may
ask you to join.
That's right.
And if they do,
I'll help take them down,
all of them, including John.
Despite everything
you've told me?
Yes, 100%.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Excuse me.
Agent Park, I saw
that you ate some Beluga.
I hope it helped.
Can you give us a minute?
I'll give you as long
as you'd like.
I just need the clothing
that Elizabeth wore
on the night
of the shooting.
I need to examine it.
I, uh... I didn't know
where else to do this.
Uh, you know, with you.
I did, uh, what I could
to clean the room
and make it respectful.
The room is fine.
Chatter I could
do without.
Okay.
****
That's it.
That's what she was wearing.
If there is a tracker,
I'm sure it's no longer
operational.
Detector for GPS signals.
Wireless audio bug.
Wand for foreign objects.
If there was something on her,
I will find it.
Not her.
Her clothes.
She's in the ground.
I presume wearing
something nice.
For what it's worth,
I hope you find
who you're looking for.
I don't want to know
what you're gonna do
with them, but, um...
You deserve peace.
(DEVICE BEEPS)
RESSLER: We have a camera
in your button and a mic,
so we're gonna be able
to see and hear everything.
After Richter
picks you up,
we'll follow you
to the location.
****
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
You look great.
Thanks. I wasn't sure
what the dress code was
for a meet and greet
with assassins.
(SEAT BELT CLICKS)
(CHUCKLES)
****
RESSLER: Once we know
where you're going,
we'll put
the TAC team on site.
After we ID the founders
and get their conspiracy
on tape, then we'll move in.
After you've cleared
the building, not before.
I don't want any of this
blowing back on you.
Nervous?
Confused.
What we did,
Su and the others,
we did it for our country.
Now what are we
doing it for?
Money.
You make it sound like
just business.
(CHUCKLES)
We want job security.
Something people
in our line of work
have never had.
****
It's been a thousand years
since Hassan-I Sabbah
was our first documented
brother in arms,
leader of the infamous
Order of Assassins,
known in Arabic
as Hashashin.
We are hashashin.
Present at turning points
throughout history,
and yet, for our troubles,
we've been freelancers.
Paid by the job. Hurt.
Physically, emotionally,
sometimes killed.
If we're lucky, thanked
in secret and disavowed.
How is the Conglomerate
any different from that?
The target in the garage
was a Vor named Lev Salenko.
The jobs are the same.
The only difference
is the price
and the accounting.
A percentage of what I get
goes to the person
who brought me in.
Once he retires,
he'll continue
to get his cut,
for pension and health.
Sounds like
a pyramid scheme.
(CHUCKLES)
It's more like an incentive
to bring people in.
Yes, that's a pyramid scheme.
Is... Is that why
you're bringing me
into the pyramid?
For an incentive?
Ancillary benefit.
What's the primary one?
To learn why you were
a no-show in Tangier.
I'm serious.
My partners know
the work we did.
They know
it was good work,
and they're gonna ask
why it stopped.
Getting them
to bring you in
may depend on
what I tell them.
So...
What should I tell them?
PARK: I didn't bring
a suitcase to send a signal.
I brought a suitcase because
I have a plane to catch.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Yes, I'll keep in mind
the 2.2 kids,
the dog, the cat,
and the minister
who pronounces us
Mr. and Mrs.
Stupendously Boring.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, love you, too.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
I'm allergic to cats.
As for the 2.2 kids,
I should warn you,
with everything
they'll have to overcome,
0.2 is gonna
be my favorite.
Talk about marginalized.
They'd have their own letter.
LGBTQIAP... For partial.
You know, 0.2 is what...
Maybe a hand?
A finger.
I'm tearing up
just thinking about
walking my little thumb
down the aisle at its wedding.
Listening as
the minister asks,
"Do you, thumb,
take you, index,
"to be your lawfully
wedded digit?
"In hangnail
and dislocation
"as long as you both
shall wave?"
Mm. What if thumb
falls for middle?
You know...
The bad boy.
Eh. Passing thing.
Good for a fling.
Maybe even...
A trip.
But in the end,
she'll end up with index.
How can you be so sure?
Casablanca.
What?
Okay. You may run
a movie theater,
but you know nothing
about the movies.
Ilsa did not go for index
in Casablanca.
Excuse you? Paul Henreid is
the personification of index.
Yeah, but she loved
Humphrey Bogart,
who is completely middle.
So she went away
with one guy
instead of staying
with the guy she loved?
She went
because of work.
It was important
to her, and...
She sacrificed
her happiness for it.
Who would do that?
(CHUCKLES)
RICHTER: That's the reason
you didn't come.
Because he's
an index finger.
That's why
I skipped Tangier.
Mm-mm.
(LAUGHS)
I skipped
everything else because...
He makes me laugh.
****
(BEEPING)
You said
you could find it.
I could. Or would
if it was here,
but it's not.
Someone tracked Elizabeth
until the moment she died,
at which point,
the police came,
took her,
everything was bagged
and tagged.
The chain of evidence,
who was in charge of it?
Park.
You knew Agent Park
was an assassin,
that after Liz died,
she took a job killing people.
I did.
And that
didn't bother you.
Ineptitude bothers me.
A lack of originality.
Margarine.
This and most
everything else
up to and including
Agent Park's trigger finger?
Deck chairs
on the Titanic.
****
RICHTER: Alina Park belongs
in the Conglomerate.
In eight months,
she completed four jobs.
Four jobs
so extraordinary,
she received the Distinguished
Intelligence Cross...
Turn a little more
to the left.
...awarded by the Agency
for "extraordinary heroism
"involving the acceptance
of existing dangers
"with conspicuous fortitude
"and exemplary courage."
And exemplary courage.
SIMMONS: Your record
is distinguished.
But not your commitment.
Eight months.
Nothing before or since.
If you are as able
as Mr. Richter
says you are,
why'd you stop?
Killing was easy.
Laughter was hard.
I needed more of it.
Michael Simmons,
former SAS, 12 targets,
eight kills.
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
Mirko Ibrahimovic,
sniper, DGSE,
answered directly to
the French Ministry
of Defense.
Colleen Riano,
former CNI, Spain.
Responsible for at least
40 deaths that we know about.
Are these people heroes
or terrorists?
SIMMONS: Thanks for coming in.
That'll be all.
****
They look
disappointed.
Are you kidding?
They loved you.
How can you be so sure?
You're still alive.
The vote's just a formality.
They love you.
I love you.
You're very lovable.
(SIGHS)
Hey.
We have to
celebrate tonight.
And by celebrate,
I mean have sex.
Name the hotel.
I'll get us a room.
****
Goodbye.
RESSLER: All right, we have
everything we need.
TAC team's in position.
I will sleep with you
anywhere, anytime.
It's a perk of the job,
like dental.
I'm clear.
****
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
(BEEPS)
(RINGS)
I have nothing to say to you.
I'm not calling
about the Conglomerate.
I know, because thanks to you,
there is no Conglomerate.
The TAC team went in.
They arrested them.
It's over.
I'm calling
about Elizabeth.
It was
the right thing to do.
But I don't like you nosing
around in my business.
John Richter
is a good person.
You were with her
after the shooting.
You rode
with her.
I care about him.
And he cares about you.
He recruited you once
and wanted to
recruit you again.
You said yes
the first time.
I couldn't risk
a repeat performance.
You couldn't risk it?
I have
unfinished business.
We have
Finding Liz's killer.
Yes.
Which may not be possible
without you.
(SCOFFS) That sounds
vaguely complimentary.
I need you,
Agent Park.
That's why I put
the Conglomerate
on the Blacklist.
I can't afford
to lose you.
Yeah, I rode with
her to the morgue.
What of it?
(BREATHES SHARPLY)
The person who orchestrated
the hit put a tracker on her,
a tracker that might give us
a clue as to their identity.
If we can find it.
Aram and I looked through
the evidence on file,
evidence you signed for,
but it wasn't there.
You sure
there was a tracker?
Yes, we have
the coordinates.
Then you already
have your answer.
You want to find
the tracker,
find the last place
it transmitted from.
Thank you.
For proving my point
about how much I need you.
I'm sorry about Richter, but,
clearly, without your help,
I can't seem to see
what's right in front of me.
Thank you, Agent Park.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS, DIALING)
****
(LINE RINGS, CLICKS)
ARAM: Hello?
Aram, I know how to find
what we're looking for.
****
Honey? I picked up dinner
from Biryani Kebab.
I told them you had
a chili allergy,
so if it's not mild,
I don't...
RICHTER: Hi, honey.
Tough day
at the office?
Join us.
I said join us.
****
To a job well done.
Yeah, about that.
It's not done.
Richter's missing.
We clocked six
in the meeting.
TAC team arrested six,
but it turns out
one was a guard
waiting outside.
Have you informed
Agent Park?
Yeah, we've been calling her.
She's not picking up.
You think Richter connected
her to the raid?
I don't know,
but if he has,
she's in danger.
Get to her house now.
****
Why'd you do it?
And don't deny it.
I know it was you.
They're gonna come here.
Did you do it for him?
Because he
makes you laugh?
If you leave now,
you can get away.
(RICHTER SIGHS)
****
Did she tell you
what we used to do?
The work we did?
(CHUCKLES)
(GASPS) Alina,
what's going on?
It's gonna be okay.
Hey, hey!
Focus.
What we did together,
did she tell you?
She said...
You killed people.
Shot. Stabbed. Blew up.
Your wife's
a natural-born killer.
Leave him out of this.
Why?
He's the reason
we're here.
What's he talking about?
He knows what we did
but not what we did?
She left me for you.
Which I came back to rectify,
and here we are.
(GRUNTS,
BREATHING QUICKLY)
If you stay,
you'll get hurt.
Which is it?
Are you concerned
for him or me?
For him.
He's my husband,
and I love him.
You're someone
I care about.
Whatever happened today
doesn't change that.
I didn't want
to see you arrested,
and I don't want you hurt,
especially not by me.
(LAUGHS) You?
You talk so much, you don't
even hear what you say.
You want to be heard,
but you never listen.
Anger is the
purest expression
of care we have.
Rage comes from
the lack of control,
a fear that you can't
protect yourself
or the people
you care about.
And from
the amount of anger
in your file,
I knew you were
an incredibly caring person.
Yeah.
(GUN COCKS)
I know what I said.
But you don't know
what it means.
And what's that?
It means I'm gonna
kick your ass.
(GRUNTING)
****
(GROANS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(THUDDING)
****
I'm so sorry.
If anything had happened
to you...
I'm okay.
Really?
No cuts, bruises,
nothing broken?
Let me see.
Peter, look at me.
I'd rather not.
****
I'm fine.
I'm not so sure
about you.
DEMBE: Alina!
(DOOR CRASHES)
Park, are you hurt?
No.
At least not in the way
you mean.
****
Weecha, hi.
It's, um, Aram,
remember?
Uh, the one you can drink
under the table.
He's in a bad mood.
I had a bad reading.
The flowers.
Apparently, they show...
Ambiguity.
O-Okay.
Uh, well, on the one hand,
I have good news.
Um, I did what you asked,
and the tracker on Liz,
uh, I used
Vandyke's computer
and got the location
of its last signal.
Which means
we have a lead.
Yeah, as I say,
that is the, uh,
good news.
Uh, but I also have
some bad news.
Well, of course you do.
Look at the flowers.
What is it?
The tracker's last signal
came from Rose Hill.
The cemetery
where Liz is buried.
****
MAN: (ON RADIO)
Yeah, we cleared
all access points...
RESSLER: You guys should
get out of here.
Go to a hotel.
CSI's gonna
be here all night.
Which murder
are they here
to investigate?
Richter's
or my marriage?
After tonight,
they're both dead.
RESSLER: Oh, come on.
You don't know that.
I never thought I made
the wrong choice. Ever.
I'm sure he feels
the same way.
(SIGHS)
I'm afraid to ask him.
Afraid?
The CIA gave you an award
for "extraordinary heroism
"and exemplary courage,"
which is all
very impressive,
by the way.
So, go.
Be extraordinary.
****
You don't
have to do that.
****
That was John's.
(SCOFFS) 'Course it was.
What did he smoke,
Gauloises?
On a balcony
in Monte Carlo?
You know what?
Doesn't matter.
I don't care about him.
What I care about
is you.
You once told me that
you weren't honest with me
not because
I wouldn't like
what I saw,
but because you wouldn't,
that you couldn't
expect me to love you
until you learned
to love yourself.
How's that going?
It's a work in progress.
Like us.
But I am
making progress.
(VOICE BREAKING)
And I hope we are, too.
Was tonight progress?
No.
But it is...
The end.
Of my keeping
any secrets from you.
You are my husband,
my partner.
You need
to know everything.
I want you
You're right.
I'm not fine.
And one of the biggest reasons
is because I can't rely
on the person
I rely on the most.
You beat a man to death.
I'm not sure I can
help you with that.
I'm not, either.
But I want to find out.
Do you?
****
Do you know who
Raymond Reddington is?
Of course I do.
Why?
I think
we better sit down.
****
COOPER: I'm afraid
you missed Agnes.
She's already in bed.
I'm glad, actually.
Because I've come to discuss
something with you that...
Perhaps it's best
she not know.
What's that?
I think I know how
to find the person
who killed her mother.
Why wouldn't we want her
to know that?
Because to find them, we need
to exhume Elizabeth's body.
****