. I want to understand
how you move our money. Well, I can be on site
within 12 hours
to begin withdrawing funds
from your Caracas accounts.
I convert to bonds
as an air gap safeguard
so that
the liquid capital
cannot be electronically
tracked.
I then reconvert for deposit,
and the funds are
controlled here digitally.
You can access your accounts
from anywhere in the world.
What guarantees
do we have?
Of safety, of security?
Your reputation
precedes you, but --
We are not men you fail.
Gentlemen, nobody can rob a bank
that's always on the move.
Our portfolios.
You protect them
with your life.
You understand?
I do.
I shall begin setting up
your accounts immediately.
In the meantime, an attendant
will be in with some beverages.
Mierce's worked wonders
for you, Weecha.
Your recovery so far
is absolutely remarkable.
What you both have
accomplished is a miracle.
Maybe it's time for me
to get back to work.
Weecha, you were nearly dead
a week ago.
You need
to continue to rest.
Eat good food, take naps,
read a book, listen to music.
I belong
out there with you.
You belong here getting
stronger with your sister,
if she'll stay.
I'm getting
the cold shoulder.
She told me she still thinks
this place is no good.
For whom?
Any of us.
She needs time.
She said a fire ceremony may
help guide her path.
A fire ceremony
in an Airstream?
Exactly what does
one of those entail?
Can you do it outside
on the grill?
Raymond, stop it.
She said she needs to consult
the other side for guidance.
Who on the other side,
and what other side?
Mierce,
we're right here.
Yes?
Marvin.
Hello.
Oh, this must be
the famous Mierce.
Hello. I'm Marvin.
Raymond has told me
so much about you
and how glad
he is that you're back.
Raymond
says a lot of things.
Oh, did I come
at a bad time?
I've experienced
hostage situations
that are less tense
than this trailer.
I keep visiting,
and the trailer
seems to keep getting smaller
and smaller and smaller, and...
I don't know,
I guess time will tell.
Keep your fingers, legs,
and eyes crossed.
But I sent you on a chase.
I hope it wasn't of
the "wild goose" variety.
This is a statement of
the bank account in question.
The same one used to pay
for the murders
of the Lacroixs
and Reggie Cole.
You were right --
it's a numbered account
held at Caelum Bank.
Heaven's vault.
Marvin, I haven't done
any banking
with Harris Gramercy
in, what?
Years.
And no new accounts have
been opened in your absence.
You still hold several accounts
on that plane.
Those accounts
are still active?
Yeah, we never
closed them.
No place is safer than Caelum
for those funds.
Fair point.
Raymond, someone had access
to this account
and paid for those murders,
and they may also be responsible
for the death
of Kate's sister, Maureen.
Problem is
it's a joint account.
Electronic petty cash,
accessible worldwide
for operational expenses.
Do you know how many
of our people had access?
Where do we start?
We start on the plane.
The scary call
is very much
coming from
inside the house.
So you reached out to me?
Well, we've had experience
together with Caelum Bank.
Before you take on Gramercy,
you better be sure.
Someone paid for the deaths
of Reggie Cole,
Tyson Lacroix,
Michelle Lacroix,
and used a Reddington
account to do it.
This same someone
blackmailed Harold Cooper
and is almost
certainly responsible
for Elizabeth's death
and probably the same
for Maureen Rowan.
Look into my eyes.
I believe
every word of it.
That's your assurance.
It's a bank on a plane,
actually several planes
with one main branch
with a man named Harris Gramercy
as the chairman, president,
and head teller.
It operates like
a ghost plane --
no flight plans filed
and no GPS transponder.
On top of which, its onboard
severs are protected
from outside interference
with elliptic curve
cryptography.
No one is hacking their way
inside there.
I've never been this close
to an answer.
I'm inches away,
and I can't get it.
I need Harris Gramercy to tell
me who accessed that account.
And you and I both know
he's the only person who can.
Caelum works under
strict secrecy.
Both the accounts and clients
are identified by numbers,
and only verified clients
may access the accounts.
Val Messick was the assassin
paid to kill
the Lacroixs and Cole.
He was paid with
Reddington's account 4626329.
So we just need the number
of the client who accessed it.
That's not
gonna be enough.
We need to match
a number to a name.
You can't force Gramercy
to give you information.
That won't work.
Who said anything
about forcing?
By the time I'm finished,
he'll be happy to
give me what I want.
You're gonna run a con
on the president Caelum Bank?
I can't very well put a gun
to his head,
not with
the friends he has.
Once we get him
on the ground,
I'm sure
Harris will be reasonable.
If we help you with this,
once this is over,
the FBI keeps him.
Whatever you want.
What do I care?
But you're losing focus.
Gramercy
isn't the goal here,
finding Elizabeth's
killer is.
My focus is clear
on Harold Cooper's name.
If the information on that plane
helped to vindicate
that man, that's my goal.
So how do we ground him?
Raymond has a plan, but the FAA
isn't going to like it.
Hey, um, can we talk?
I have news.
Of course,
but we're gonna need
to get on it
to find this plane.
Right, I'm sorry,
but I heard from Main Justice.
They processed your review,
and they're revoking
your field status
due to medical liabilities.
I can't let you work this case,
at least --
at least not in the field.
You know I was talking
with a friend
recently about the first time
I ever flew on this plane,
and it was a turbulent
ride then.
Of course that's also
a turbulent friendship now.
I guess no matter
where you are,
you should prepare
for rough air.
Raymond,
you have a lot of money
in this bank,
which is why I was obligated
to take this meeting.
So what
can I do for you?
I need a favor, Harris.
Oh, what's this?
A cricket score?
You know what it is.
You have every account
on this plane
locked up in that safe deposit
box mind of yours.
That one belongs to me.
I need the name
of the last person
who made a withdrawal
from that account.
It's your account.
You should already know
who's accessing it.
It is my account, so you
should have no problem
telling me who made
the withdrawal.
Oh, you know the rules.
No names.
If my clients found out --
I'm a client.
It's my money.
Why would
anyone else care?
If I were to give out one name,
the perception would be
that I'm likely to
give out others.
If someone is accessing
your money,
it's because they had
permission from you.
And if you don't know
who that is, well,
I'm afraid there's nothing else
I can tell you.
How's the tracker holding up?
We've got him pinpointed
within a geographic meter.
You want me to what?
Under Title II of
the Intelligence Reform
and Terrorism
Prevention Act of 2004,
the FBI has authority
to investigate any threats
to national security
pursuant --
What language
are you speaking?
As acting director
of an FBI task force,
I have a credible threat
of terrorist action
to US Route 1.
The Overseas Highway?
Ground all flight traffic.
Now.
I've got six flights
leaving Key West,
I've got a billionaire
landing at Key Largo,
and I've got a soccer team
sitting on the runway
in Marathon.
You want me to --
Ground them all.
Or my next call will be
to the Air Force
to ground them for you.
We can start with a plane that
is not on your ground radar.
I have its coordinates.
Uh, excuse me, sir.
We were just informed
that we are currently over
United States airspace and
must land under its authority.
Have they told you why?
No, sir.
But we were encouraged
to comply under threat
of the US Air Force.
Well, then, by all means,
comply.
Copy that.
Perhaps we
should drink up.
Is this a problem?
No, nothing that a little
talk or time
or perhaps a small donation
can't fix.
I'm not entirely
comfortable with
an unscheduled
stop like this.
It was better
than an F-16
blasting the two of us
out of the sky.
This feels unsafe, Harris.
Please fix it promptly.
I just need a moment to speak
to whomever is in charge.
FBI!
We have a credible threat,
and we've had to ground
all air traffic now.
If you gentlemen would
give us a second.
We'll inspect your plane
and have you on your way.
Happy to
assist a US agency.
Wait, I know your face.
I know who you are!
You're Raymond Reddington.
Who's he talking about?
Me? I don't know that man.
Redmond Rillington?
I don't know.
-Let's go.
0-All right.
Everyone on this plane
is under arrest.
What the hell
is happening here?
. Hello, Val.
How you been? You're the fed
who arrested me.
So what?
You've come to personally
escort me to detention?
See this?
I'm not escorting
you anywhere,
and you're not
going to jail.
This is a transfer order.
You're going to
witness protection
because you snitched
on the people who hired you.
I didn't say anything.
This says you did.
And we had you
on triple homicide,
so you must've really
given up the goods.
What are you doing?
You get
handed over to WitSec,
they begin your paperwork
for induction.
That process is long enough
that anyone paying attention --
like the person who hired you --
can get word that you snitched.
Then WitSec follows up with me,
and I suddenly have no record of
you helping on an active case.
That's when you're cooling your
heels in central detention.
You, a known snitch, sitting
in gen pop the length of time
it takes for me
to make up my mind.
That's
a death sentence.
I'm a man with
a lot to lose, Val.
So I really don't care
about you.
Now, I could misplace
this piece of paper,
and then you go to trial
like you're supposed to,
and no one is the wiser.
Triple homicide?
You'll be a big man on campus.
You might even make some friends
to keep you safe.
What do you
want to know?
Who hired you and everything
you were paid to do.
Spare no detail.
I never got a name, and you know
what I was paid to do.
This van is leaving
in five minutes, Val.
Where do you want it
to take you?
Okay.
There was one thing.
After I killed
Michelle Lacroix,
I was supposed to go
to the Lacroix house,
but you
arrested me first.
And do what at the house?
Burn it to the ground
and start the fire near
Lacroix's desk.
I've had nightmares
that begin this way.
I'm in federal custody.
My plane impounded full of the
most sensitive banking data
in the world.
Raymond, what the hell
are we gonna do?
Calm down.
Federal or not,
they're all just cops.
I can
get us out of here.
How?
We haven't been given
our phone call yet.
A while ago, I won a game
of roque
against the lieutenant governor
of Florida.
He owes me a huge favor.
One call gets the both of us
out of here -- or just me.
I'm not giving up a client
to you.
If the FBI starts
poking around that plane,
you'll be giving up
a lot more than that.
Oh.
You're a real villain,
aren't you?
This villain can have
you airborne within the hour.
One name seems a small price
to pay for your freedom.
You know what?
This situation, as sudden
and horrible as it is,
seems to have greatly
improved your ability
to make requests,
hasn't it?
What are you trying
to say, Harris?
Under no circumstances
known to God or man
will I cooperate with you.
Well, now you're just
being unreasonable.
It doesn't expose any of
your other clients
to tell me about a transfer
from my own account.
No, it exposes me,
because I represent something --
trust.
Trust in me.
Trust in my bank.
People come to me not just
to protect their money,
but to protect
their secrets.
And I do not
divulge names.
I am a man of my word.
And I'm a man of mine.
You should
reconsider, Harris.
Is that a threat?
I'm Redmond Rillington.
I don't have to make threats,
I just have to speak.
This entire arrest is a sham.
I mean, were those even
real agents earlier?
I've got nothing to fear.
Just the man in this cell
with you.
It was a nice speech
you gave --
all that trust
and trusting --
but you're certainly
no paragon of virtue, Harris.
I know where the money
in your bank comes from --
criminals, war lords,
drug dealers,
bankers, and politicians
who've defrauded nations.
Shall we find out
if this 9mm is a sham?
Go to hell.
Oh!
Gee, I guess it's
a real gun after all.
We have to get in there.
That man may have the name
of the person
who ordered
Liz's murder.
So we do nothing?
Give it a minute.
I'm not losing sleep
over some criminal banker.
Oh, where are the police?
Someone must've
heard that.
But you called it, Harris.
There are no police.
This isn't even
an active station.
That's why they brought us
in the back door.
It's just you and me.
I need an ambulance.
I need a name.
I keep a backup log
of all transactions
with a colleague in Riga,
just numbers on paper.
Oh, God.
I didn't want it
to play out like this,
but now that is has,
just get me the name.
It's me.
Ego confido in pecunia 123.
I need
the transfer history
of account number 4626329.
Just -- just give me
the last line details.
Client 4836924, got it.
Okay, 4836924.
You know who it is,
tell me.
Hawkins.
Hedwig Hawkins.
Heddie?
That can't be.
Numbers don't lie.
Wait, I -- I need
an ambulance!
It'll be here.
You followed me down here?
You are absolutely
incorrigible, sweetheart.
Your sister allowed this?
She didn't know I left.
She was out shopping
for her ceremony.
Oh, my God, we are
going to pay and pay.
At least give her a call,
let her know you're safe.
I told you you're
not well enough yet.
If something happens --
You needed
a ride so sit back.
Thank you.
Jesus.
This is
Federal Agent Zuma.
I need an ambulance
for a gunshot wound
at gulf and aviation
right now.
This blood's dark. I think
the bullet hit his liver.
I knew this would happen.
Look, we got the name,
didn't we?
We did.
God help Heddie.
. This is all from
Lacroix's home office? I had an evidence team
bag every shelf and cabinet
near his desk.
It's where Val Messick was told
to start the fire.
It stands to reason
someone wanted
to make sure it burned
more than anywhere else.
I'll start at this end,
you start at that end.
You know why I'm here
helping you
and not down in Florida
with the rest of the team?
I figured you'd tell me
when you were comfortable.
I've been demoted
to a desk role.
The headaches?
I don't blame Aram.
He only did what I asked.
I was honest in my own review.
He did his job
by submitting it.
But I'm frustrated.
Believe me, I know
a thing or two
about feeling
frustrated lately.
We just keep working.
How was Gramercy
when you left?
Headed into surgery.
He'd lost a lot of blood.
It was 50/50.
It gets worse.
He realized it was a ruse
before Raymond shot him.
He didn't think
we were real FBI.
Which means, if he survives,
we have to let him go.
It's the only way to
protect Mr. Reddington.
We need
to protect Heddie.
Is it conceivable she could be
behind any of this?
All we have is an account
that led to her name.
We don't know enough yet.
Reddington will kill her.
He's already left
one person for dead.
We need to
keep Heddie alive.
I told Raymond -- this isn't
just about the person
that ordered
Elizabeth's death.
This is also about that person
framing Harold.
Dembe's right.
Whatever Heddie knows,
whatever she's done --
she is Mr. Cooper's
best chance.
We need to stay ahead
of Reddington.
Does anyone know
where Heddie is?
Miami.
She has a condo in Miami.
There's a helipad
in Islamorada.
I'll send a chopper.
You want that one?
Oh, what a good girl.
One more strawberry.
You want that one?
Good puppy.
All I can hear right now
is Heddie's laugh.
All these years, that laugh.
Oh! No, no, no, no.
It's Heddie.
I guarantee it's unlocked.
Voilà.
She was just here.
And then she was tipped off.
Okay, I-I-I got out.
We'll be on the ground
in five minutes.
We'll pick you up around
the corner at Flamingo Park.
I'm on my way.
Is it true?
Is what true?
I-I don't even know
what I'm being accused of.
Did you have something to do
with Keen's death?
What?
How could you --
Is that what you think?
Is that what Raymond thinks?
Okay, I don't know
what's going on here,
but I never did anything
to hurt Elizabeth.
You have to believe me.
Dembe, come on.
Actually, Heddie, he's the one
you'll have to convince.
Raymond.
I know you have her.
We're just trying
to keep her safe.
Do you know what she might
have been a part of?
What she could be
responsible for?
Raymond, you're blinded
by anger right now.
You'd execute this woman
before you can get answers.
Harold is counting
on those answers,
so is the rest of the FBI,
and so are you.
You cannot kill Heddie
before you get the truth.
I tell you what this
reminds me of.
The coast of
Madagascar in 2010,
on that stunning
Spirit's Loop,
all that beautiful mahogany
bright work.
What was it?
80, 90 feet?
111.
And then we saw the skiffs,
pirates out of Nacala.
I wanted to fight.
We were certainly armed for it.
High seas adventure.
But you insisted
we stand down.
What was it you said to me?
Surrendering loses us
nothing we'll miss
but gives them
the world.
Not one shot was fired.
They took the boat,
the brandy, my Sea-Dweller --
I loved that watch.
You got another.
Spent six hours, us and the
crew in that tiny life raft.
Ah, Dembe, I've always respected
your level-headedness,
your refusal to just say yes,
your willingness to put me
in my place.
I hardly see how what I said
then applies to now.
No, I don't either.
I was just killing time
till we caught up with you.
Hello, Heddie, let's go.
All right.
You're coming with us.
Harold, take
a look at this.
Lacroix had a hell
of a movie collection, right?
Then I opened this one.
All right, there's
some minor security here,
just a password protection.
Give me a minute to go ahead,
and here we go.
It's loading now.
So what is it?
Looks like a digitized record
of payment of some kind.
Both Lacroix and Reggie Cole
were involved
in those
civil settlement shakedowns.
Could this be that?
Oh, a lot of names here.
That scam must've
been a lot bigger
than Lacroix and Cole.
Let's look for the names
with the biggest numbers
next to them.
Here.
Lawrence Knoll
and Angela Sherwood.
Who were they?
Angela Sherwood for sure
and, yep, Knoll, too --
they're both lawyers
at the same law firm.
Let's find out
what they know.
Where are you two headed?
We got a lead.
Maybe promising.
We don't know yet.
Can I come
with you guys?
You don't know
what you're walking into.
No, I can't let you.
It'd be a violation
of bureau protocol.
And I have to pay attention
to that stuff now.
Sorry, Alina,
but you're out of the field.
I can't believe this.
Gramercy died in surgery two
hours ago of a gunshot wound.
Collateral damage
was always a possibility.
News is spreading
like wildfire,
and his people knew
he was meeting with you.
I've got half the criminal
underworld asking me
if my boss murdered
the head of Caelum Bank.
Do you understand?
I do.
I just don't care.
I have what I was after,
and I'm bringing her back.
Her?
It was Heddie, Marvin.
All roads led to Heddie.
And so help me,
she will atone for her sin.
I'm taking her to the warehouse
where I'm going to really
get to know
my old friend, Heddie.
Well, if that's the case,
I might be able to add
to your interrogation.
How so?
When you asked me to look
into that bank account,
that wasn't
the only digging I did.
Now, I don't want to
speak too soon --
I still have to confirm
something first --
but, uh, I may have
a special guest
for you by the time
you're back.
We'll be there
in three hours.
. We have your names here.
We have dollar amounts.Reginald Cole was bringing
cases to Tyson Lacroix
who fraudulently settled
those cases and kept the money.
If the two of you
weren't involved,
then you knew about it.
How long do you thin --
Can we stop you
right there?
We know we're screwed.
We knew we were screwed
the minute
you showed up at the firm.
We'll deal.
We want statutory immunity,
and we'll tell you
what we know.
This isn't difficult.
Give me a sample.
We can give you names, more
names than are in that document.
Lacroix might've kept records,
but he wasn't Claudius.
We can't give you
Claudius, though.
We don't have
that information.
Claudius?
Who's that?
The mastermind.
The architect of the whole
damn spider's web.
He dreamed
the whole thing up.
Forcing settlements while
never repping the clients
and pocketing
all the money?
It was genius.
Every one of us kicked back
a percentage
of every
case to Claudius.
There must have been a way
you kept in touch with him.
Everything was done
through anonymous e-mails,
burner phones -- real
cloak-and-dagger-type stuff.
Personally, I never
believed there really was
a Claudius.
Somebody somewhere would say
they met him or her,
but I never did.
Me neither.
Like I said, we can
give you other names.
We can't help you with the one
name you'd really want.
Raymond, I-I'm innocent.
I-I don't understand what's
going on, but I'm telling you --
No, no, no, please,
I've heard every variation
on that theme before,
and I don't want
to hear it again.
No more bloviating.
What does that mean?
It means I could wax poetic
about the nature of betrayal
or be begging your forgiveness
for the rest of this flight,
and you know what?
Either way, I talk too much
and so do you.
I'm tired.
So, please, do me a favor
and shut up.
What have you done?
You know everything we're
looking for depends
on the answers
Heddie can provide,
not to mention you
almost killed Dembe and Ressler.
I most certainly
did not.
The airbags deployed,
and their egos were bruised.
You can't say that for
Harris Gramercy, I found out.
That was poor luck,
but it provided me
with one of the answers
I'm looking for.
If you kill that woman,
we'll lose everything valuable
she has to say about
that's been going on,
including how to find
this mastermind Claudius.
I could never let her testify
in open court, Harold.
You know that.
What are you gonna do?
I'll hold my own trial.
Don't worry, I'll get
answers for the both of us,
you can count on it.
Agent Park, are you here to make
a claim for Heddie, as well?
I came to ask a favor.
I have a lot on my mind
this evening,
but what can I do for you?
I want to help.
I was thinking,
with all that's going on --
You want a job?
Not a job, just to stay
a part of this.
If you're close
to Keen's killer --
I'm good at what I do.
Hmm, that's quite a bold line
for me to cross.
I admit I made that leap before,
but at the moment,
I'm swimming in hot water with
Harold and the FBI as it is.
The FBI doesn't
want me anymore.
They've made that clear.
Alina, I can see
you're suffering.
And with your maladies
as they are...
...there's no task
I can afford or even feel
right about offering you.
You know, I've had about all
I can stand of people telling me
what I can and can't do.
I'm sorry, I've made enough
mistakes for one day.
You're making another one
right now.
I can't help you today,
Agent Park.
I need to attend
to another matter at hand.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I can
take care of myself.
Raymond,
Heddie is waking up.
We'll talk tomorrow.
You should exit
out the back.
This is it.
Not one stone has been unturned.
The lawyers were a dead end.
Reddington had Heddie.
We can't give up.
I appreciate your faith,
but what else is there to do?
We do it all again.
All of this?
Park found that payout record
on a disc somewhere
where it wasn't
supposed to be.
What else is here
that we might've missed?
We didn't miss anything.
You want to bet
your life on that?
Or do you want to help me
look again?
.
Didn't expect
anyone to be here.
Oh, I guess I just love
my job --
double-checking
Tyson Lacroix's entire
John Grisham
movie collection.
You've been gone a while.
You okay?
I went to Reddington
and offered him my help.
Don't worry.
He rejected me, too.
I don't have a place
there, either.
Of course not, because
your place is here next to us.
I know desk work doesn't have
the thrill of the field,
but what we do in here,
it saves lives, too.
Help save mine. Right now,
I could really use you.
Here.
Take the other half
of this pile.
I think I'm going cross-eyed.
Marvin will be back
in a moment.
Now is the time to speak freely.
You think that I had
something to do
with Elizabeth's death?
But why?
What reason would I have?
History's full of unlikely
characters and unlikely events.
But how?
The coordination alone,
forget about the planning,
and you never found out?
That's something
you actually believe?
You either had help
or you helped someone else.
Well, helped who?
Or helped from who?
From where?
Do I look anything other
than hopelessly alone right now?
Raymond,
this is Micky Croft.
Micky is the arms trade
along the Canadian border.
Yes, I know who he is.
Your reputation precedes you
as reasonable and reliable.
Likewise.
I was looking for any of
our people
who might've been disloyal,
maybe shopped
around their services,
and that's when I found Micky,
heard his story.
She came to me --
has to be three years ago now.
Said she was looking
for employment opportunities,
said she was done
with how you ran things.
She showed me how you
cook your books.
She's a real whiz
with dodging tax law.
Yes, she is.
I only listened 'cause
I thought she was
all the way
gone from you.
Heddie?
What do you
want me to say?
You never thought
I was anything special.
I was overlooked.
So I went
hunting for work.
Should I be killed
for wanting a better job?
Micky, I appreciate
you coming.
I won't forget it.
Now if you wouldn't mind
finding your way back out
to the comfort
of Marvin's car.
Thanks, Micky.
Let's get on with it.
It's late.
Sun will be up soon.
Make it quick.
Do you want a moment?
For what?
Now we have to deal
with the fact
that I killed
Harris Gramercy.
His clients will be out
for blood.
You want to deal
with that this minute?
We'll fly to Latvia.
Several of his biggest clients
are based thereabouts.
If we can call a meeting,
perhaps we can plead our case.
Jet's waiting
on the runway.
Marvin, you coming?
Hey, hon.
I know it's late.
I'll be here a while.
They need me.
I'm watching a wedding video
of two people that are dead.
Hey, you asked.
Okay, I'll text you when --
Hon, I got to go.
One of the videos
was the Lacroix wedding.
Exactly as it was labeled,
right?
Nothing to see there.
Except I watched it anyway.
You were right.
It's not a thrill,
but damn it if desk work
isn't gonna save your life.
Okay, that's enough
embarrassing stories.
And now for someone who's
very special
to both
Tyson and Michelle,
a lifelong friend
and Tyson's best man.
To Michelle and Tyson,
I love you guys so much.
May I only find my own
Michelle one day.
To Michelle and Tyson.
May their marriage
be blessed forever.
Cheers.
So it's00 a.m.
in Latvia.
We have 10 hours
of flying time --
Hold that thought.
Harold.
Where are you?
I'm on the plane.
Red eye to Riga.
Marvin's here, too.
Reddington,
listen to me carefully --
you cannot trust
Marvin Gerard.
Come again?
Tyson Lacroix
and Marvin Gerard
were old friends.
They've known each other
for decades.
Reddington, I can't connect
all the dots,
but something is very wrong.
Harold, I appreciate
the call.
What's Edward doing?
Are we gonna take off soon?
He's probably flipping
switches, checking gauges,
plotting our course.
What -- What's going on?
What is this? I don't --
I don't understand.
I'm sure Heddie is
as interested as I am
to hear how and why
you did what you did.
So I'm gonna
have a drink.
I'll pour.
Hm.
And I hope your story is good.
Your life depends on it.
.
I am the most loyal
to you and always have been.
But I never swore an oath
to Elizabeth Keen.
I never made it a secret
that I didn't trust her.
She was unworthy
and unqualified.
To have her run things?
Over my dead body.
Careful what you
wish for, Marvin.
Everything I did,
I did in the best interest
of your empire.
After Elizabeth's death,
when you took off,
I kept things going
as best I could,
and I did
a pretty damn good job.
When you came back, I --
I thought you'd finally
be over it.
You've lived your life
with so much death and loss.
You've always
gotten over it.
But you were
utterly determined
to get to the bottom
of how she died.
And I couldn't
let that happen.
I tried everything I could
to slow you down, to stop you.
I went after your money.
I had my own
friends killed.
I went after Harold.
Nothing worked.
You just kept coming.
So then you went after me.
Serving you up, Heddie,
was a last resort
to protect my life
with Raymond.
That's all I am anymore.
That's my life --
Raymond Reddington.
What a waste.
What a terrible,
terrible waste.
How did you
figure it out?
I didn't.
I've gone over it
and over it,
thought of it
and thought of it.
I remember the day
Elizabeth died
better than entire years
of my life.
I remember what she wore,
the smell of rain in the air.
The sound of her voice.
The last words she spoke.
The look in her eyes
in that moment,
that last moment
when she looked at me,
as if for the first time
seeing me for who I really was.
But I'd forgotten
about the headache
until today when Agent Park
was in front of me
with her headache
and a glass shattered.
All the time I spent agonizing
over that GPS tracker
that Elizabeth ingested,
where it came from.
But I'd forgotten
about Elizabeth's headache.
The morning of her death,
we stopped by your office
to sign some paperwork,
transfer some holdings.
We had tea.
She had coffee.
What was in it?
She got a headache,
and you gave her aspirin.
That's how you bugged her.
You did it
right in front of me.
Why this ruse with Heddie
at the warehouse,
the -- the gunshot.
I can answer that.
Raymond wanted to make you
feel safe.
Feel safe for what?
To get you on the plane.
It'll be a nice, long flight,
give us time to clear
your offices and apartment,
the place at the beach.
Enough time to sift
through everything
and decide
what to do with you.
Don't you need
to get that?
Actually, it's for you.
Excuse me?
When I drove
to the warehouse,
I didn't know
if I was in the clear yet
so I put a small
insurance plan in place...
just in case.
I sent a panic alert with this
watch five minutes ago.
If my shooter doesn't hear
from me in the next two minutes,
he'll splatter her lovely mind
all over that trailer.
I'm walking
off this plane,
and you are
going to let me.
Oh!
Weecha!
You'll kill him.
Stop it! Stop it.
I never
wanted any of this.
You've had an odd way
of showing it.
You -- You're the one
who showed me the way.
Those recordings you left
for Elizabeth
telling her how
to run things --
I ran them
while you were gone,
I've run them
since you've been back.
May the best man win,
old friend.
Good luck, Claudius.
Oh, Raymond, help!
Please!
Weecha, Weecha, Weecha.
Weecha, Weecha?