(SIGHS)
I can't do it.
That's all right.
I don't want to.
I understand.
(GUNSHOT)
No.
No!
Raymond, we have to go.
Raymond, we must.
I'm sorry.
(ENGINE REVS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
We have company.
It's Ressler.
Lose him.
(TIRES SCREECH)
(HORN HONKS)
COOPER: (OVER PHONE)
I know what you want
to do,
but killing him
will only make it worse.
Donald, listen to me.
You're in no condition
to drive.
(TIRES SCREECH)
(HORN HONKS)
Don't do this.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(SIGHS)
Raymond?
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
(DOOR SLIDES, THUMPS)
I'm being evaluated.
Not on your floricultural
skills, I hope.
(CHUCKLES)
My mental state.
Weecha's sister, Mierce,
is a shaman.
She reads the flowers
for insight into my mood.
I see dried-out and dark.
Bad blood and betrayal.
Is this still about Dembe
joining the FBI?
Because that wasn't
about betrayal.
It was about
upward mobility.
What happened
to Elizabeth,
Dembe shares a significant
responsibility for that.
What are you
talking about?
Townsend is responsible.
He sent Vandyke,
Vandyke pulled the trigger.
I thought
you were with the sister.
I am.
Weecha and I are roommates.
The bed is
much more comfortable
than the couch.
I, being a gentleman,
I offered her the bed.
She being a lady,
she invited me to join her.
Marvin,
you said you had news.
Let's hope
it's decidedly less dry
and considerably more light.
Hess, Ray, Colby.
Tuesday, Wednesday,
Thursday.
Three days, three hits.
No who, no why,
only the what,
which is a disaster.
The only thing worse
is the fact
that I am the first one
telling you this.
Hess was hit on Tuesday.
How could this possibly
be news to you?
You're out of touch.
You need to get your ducks
in a row, Raymond.
AGNES: Pinky!
Oh, my goodness!
Aren't you a bundle of energy
this morning?
I've got orchestra practice
before school,
then a math quiz
and an English presentation.
Then I'm trying out
for the play.
And then you're reading me
some Pippi Longstocking.
You're weeks behind on that,
by the way.
(HORN HONKS)
That's Sadie.
Total frenemy.
Got to go.
Hi, Weecha.
Bye!
(CHUCKLES)
(DOOR CLOSES)
I'd like to think I had
that much energy once.
On the other hand, if I did,
it's depressing
to think about
where it all went.
Perhaps this will give you
a jolt.
It seems
I'm under attack.
In the past week,
a strike team has taken out
three key members
of my organization.
I'm sorry
to hear that.
Thank you, but I'm not here
for your sympathy.
Good, because officially,
you don't have it.
On the record, the Bureau
would be thrilled to know
the Reddington organization
is under siege,
but I'm guessing
you're not here
for my official response.
As a rule,
I police my own business.
In this case,
I need help,
and if you want the blacklist
to continue,
you'll give it.
It's that bad?
The attacks were surgical
and strategic,
requiring an insightful
knowledge of my organization.
And I don't really know
from which direction
this assault is coming.
And there's
one more thing.
Dembe...
I won't work with him again.
Why not?
All that matters
is that I won't.
He'll have
to be replaced.
I won't do that,
certainly not
without knowing why.
Ask him.
He's an honest fellow.
Who knows?
After he tells you,
you may not want to work
with him either.
(KEYS CLACKING)
(BEEPING)
COOPER:
Reddington's worried.
His organization's
under attack,
and he wants our help
to fend it off.
He doesn't have a name
or a motive.
Only this,
three victims in three days.
RESSLER: Who are they?
Ricki Hess.
Jack Ray.
Budge Colby.
Friends of yours?
They were, once.
Good people.
What did they do
for Reddington?
Operations.
Each was responsible
for a different port.
New Jersey, Norfolk, Miami.
These were top people.
Well-protected.
But yet someone got
to all three.
No wonder
Reddington's worried.
I've asked our field offices
in the relevant cities
to forward us
the crime-scene information.
If there's a clue in there
about who did this,
we need to find it.
We already have a clue.
You know who did this?
No.
Just what
they're going to do next.
How happy is Reddington that
you're on the task force?
Not very.
In fact, he wants me
to kick you off it.
What?
Why would he want that?
He said
I should ask you.
Vandyke.
If I was doing my job
even a little bit
that day, that night,
I would've seen him
long before he shot Elizabeth.
I could've stopped him.
And Reddington blames you
because you didn't.
No more
than I blame myself.
RESSLER: You shouldn't.
I don't.
And, believe me,
I tried.
Raymond has
Vandyke's phone.
He had someone pull
the GPS data points
from the day
Elizabeth was killed.
I met Elizabeth at a diner
hours before she was shot.
The GPS data points
and photos on the phone
show that Vandyke
was watching us.
If I was paying attention
at all,
I would have noticed him.
How did he know
you'd be there?
I assume he was following me,
but I'm not sure.
Which is why I had
the phone data sent to me.
I hope that by tracking it,
I'll find out.
I could use your help
plotting the data points.
Of course.
So what's the clue?
I thought
I was being kicked off.
That's my call,
not Red's.
He thought I would agree
with him
once you had
explained yourself.
You have, and I don't.
So the clue,
let's hear it.
This is a macro look
at Raymond's operations
in the Atlantic.
Does he have that many
operations in the Pacific?
DEMBE: And the Indian, Baltic,
and the Mediterranean.
Nothing in the Arctic?
DEMBE: No.
Other than a compound
on the Faroe Islands.
It's official.
Our lives suck.
For shipping
in the Atlantic,
he uses accounts in Hamburg,
Belfast, and the Caymans.
Funds are routed through
the hawala network to Morocco.
He then ships
from Gibraltar, Benin
or Dakar.
You really know everything,
don't you?
I guess I assumed you did,
but you actually do.
I didn't always.
Everything with Raymond
is need-to-know,
but after Elizabeth,
he couldn't function.
So I had to function
for him.
You took over.
I did.
ARAM: What was that like,
going from the man
in front of the man
to the man behind him?
(TIRES SCREECH)
Down!
A nightmare.
So, Benin, Dakar,
Gibraltar.
Goods ship from there
to New Jersey, Norfolk, Miami.
Raymond is a middle man.
He has clients.
They have goods.
If the port of entry
is choked off
and they can't take
delivery,
that costs them money,
which Raymond has to cover.
This is all very educational,
but where's the clue?
Right here.
The port of Baltimore.
(SHIP HORN BLARES IN DISTANCE)
(BIRDS CALLING)
(DOOR OPENS)
That you, Joe?
I know, I know,
no smoking on site.
Don't tell
her royal pain in the...
(SILENCED GUNSHOT)
What the...
Joe?
(SILENCED GUNSHOT)
Baltimore is Raymond's
only remaining port of entry
on the eastern seaboard.
Whoever's doing this
took out
three of his port managers.
It's safe to assume
he'll try to take out
a fourth.
(SILENCED GUNSHOT)
Do you know his name?
Reginald Lawler.
Let's go get him,
and hope we're not too late.
MAN: Hands in the air!
I won't talk.
(SCREAMS)
Oh, I think you will.
Let's start
with the same question
I asked the others,
huh?
This man,
where is he?
MARVIN: What do you mean
Lawler's not answering?
Then go there.
I don't care
that you just gave birth.
(CELL PHONE DIALING)
That is not my problem.
My problem is $106 million
worth of goods...
(LINE RINGING)
...we rerouted to Baltimore
that now can't land
in Baltimore
unless you get Lawler
to land them.
And until he lands them,
we are out 5% a day
in insurance
and carrying charges.
So I suggest
you wrap Junior
in a binky,
shove him
onto your mammilla,
and go find Lawler.
Lawler's out of pocket.
Yoo-hoo.
Did you hear me?
Lawler is AWOL, which means
the East Coast is shut down.
Mierce read the flowers.
Mierce.
The shaman?
She's optimistic.
Is she?
That's great.
The shaman is optimistic.
Fantastic.
I mean, it doesn't mean
there aren't problems.
It just means
we'll figure them out.
Do you value my counsel?
I do.
Good.
'Cause here it is.
You've lost your mind.
The world is falling apart
around you,
and you're all beatific
because your ex-lover
looked at a photograph
of some dead flowers
and said Kumbaya.
She's not my ex.
We're just pausing
until I resolve the issues
surrounding Elizabeth's death.
That is another thing.
You blame Dembe
for something he didn't do.
Elizabeth's death
has been resolved.
Asked. Answered.
As is the reason
we are in this mess.
(SIGHS)
Look, I know
this is third-rail stuff,
but you're the one
getting your flowers read,
so what the hell...
You never should've designated
Elizabeth as your successor.
She wasn't qualified.
And when she passed
and you went away,
there was no one to keep
all hell from breaking loose.
(SIGHS)
Seven days, seven countries.
I am done looking.
I told you
we wouldn't find him.
Oh, well, forgive me
for hoping he might not want
his entire life's work
burned to the ground.
His life's work
was Elizabeth.
Well, my life's work
was him.
And right now,
it is under siege.
Chin in Taipei.
Madrzyk in Dubrovnik.
Baptiste in Haiti.
They're all moving
against us.
And if we don't put them down,
others will follow.
And when I say "we,"
I mean you.
Me?
Starting with Baptiste,
who's in Texas,
meeting with
other turncoats.
Red may have
picked Elizabeth,
but we both know that
you are his natural successor.
(SIGHS)
Now that they're gone,
the organization
is yours to run.
(SIGHS)
And if I don't want to?
Then it gets
sliced and diced.
We weren't equipped
for what came,
least of all Dembe.
Mm-hmm.
My point, my counsel,
is this.
You left us
in the lurch once,
don't do it again.
Call Marybeth.
Tell her to stay home
with her newborn.
If Lawler's
not answering,
it's because
he's been captured,
if not killed.
If that's the case,
we got no play.
Of course we do.
And I'm sure Dembe's
playing it.
Dembe? I thought
you want him
off the task force.
I do.
But I have no illusions
that Harold will abide
by my request.
And you're wrong
about Dembe's abilities.
His not wanting
to run my empire
doesn't mean he couldn't.
Believe me, if you and I
are realizing
that Lawler's
been targeted now,
Dembe's
already realized it.
How can you be sure?
I told you.
Mierce's optimistic.
We're in.
Agent Park reports two guards
down at the perimeter.
She's waiting on EMTs.
We have no intel on the number
of mercs
or where they are
in the building.
A TAC unit is on the way.
Do not engage until we know
what we're dealing with.
DEMBE: I see movement.
I don't know who
or how many.
I need to get closer.
I'm going to give you
one more chance.
Dembe Zuma,
where is he?
I don't know.
(SHUDDERED BREATHING)
(SCREAMING)
Dembe, talk to me.
That can't be.
Where...
What is it?
What can't be?
Not what. Who.
Boukman Baptiste.
We don't know
who that is.
A man I killed.
Daniel.
Daniel!
(BREATHING QUICKLY)
DEMBE: Recon said his boy
would be at home.
This isn't
about hurting Raymond.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
This is about killing me.
(SCREAMING)
If that's true,
I want you out of there.
Is that clear?
Pull back.
Agent Zuma,
do you copy?
Agent Zuma!
Ressler,
we lost contact with Dembe.
RESSLER: Yeah, we split up.
I don't have eyes on him.
Circle back,
then report.
I have your agent.
I assume there are others.
Tell them to stand down.
This is Harold Cooper
with the FBI.
Who am I speaking to?
Tell them.
I will, as soon as I hear
that my agent is all right.
Your agent
killed my son.
I just need to know
that he's okay.
He was 10,
sitting in the back
of a car,
when your agent
murdered him.
That's a tragedy,
but killing other people
will only make it worse.
Did you know that
when you hired him,
that he murdered children?
I'll help you,
but you have to help me.
We have to work together.
I am not a religious man.
But sometimes even
a sinner's prayers
are answered.
Was that Dembe?
Was he hit?
Sir, I don't know.
(GRUNTING)
This does not
make us even!
Only your daughter
does that.
A child for a child!
Aah!
(GASPING)
(WHIMPERS)
RESSLER: Drop it!
Don't move!
Unclip it.
Face the wall.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Baptiste?
Gone.
Who is he, and why was he
so interested in finding you?
To avenge the death
of his son.
(GRUNTS)
I'm sorry
you got hurt in this.
Look, you gotta go
warn Isabella.
He said he was after
his daughter.
Right, I got this.
Call her.
She needs to be called,
just not by me.
Why not?
It's complicated.
I can't explain.
Please, just do it.
202-555-0144.
(CELL PHONE DIALING)
I thought you and Isabella
got past the tough times.
We did.
Until we didn't.
Aah!
ISABELLA:
I don't understand.
You worked
for one white guy,
and now you want to work
for white guys with badges?
I told you,
I haven't decided yet.
That's why I'm here,
to get your opinion.
My opinion
is that I don't want
my father
to be a Judas
to his community.
Isabella,
I know these agents.
They're good people.
I never criticized you
for working for Reddington.
I hated it.
My child almost died
because of it.
But I told myself
that's what you do,
it's not who you are.
It's what I did.
Elizabeth is dead.
Raymond is gone.
I'm alone,
looking for a purpose.
Is this really
who you are?
A Black man
who wants to be a cop?
I'm a man that wants
to helps people
and a man
who's also proud
to be Black.
I think I can do both.
Reddington is one man.
The cops are part
of a system of oppression.
You do this,
people will see you
as a sellout and a traitor.
I don't care
what other people see.
I only care what you see.
You wanna know
what I see?
George Floyd,
Breonna Taylor,
Philando Castile...
I see them, too.
...Freddie Gray,
Eric Garner,
Michael Brown...
I see them, too,
and I know that any day
what happened to them
could happen to me...
Atatiana Jefferson,
Botham Jean,
Alton Sterling...
Isabella, I see them.
I know
there is injustice.
But I also know
justice can be done.
I've seen it done,
and I think I'd find purpose
in doing it.
Isabella.
Isabella!
(SIGHS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
This is Isabella.
Leave a message at the beep.
Thanks.
(BEEPS)
It's Agent Ressler,
again.
I know we keep calling,
but it's incredibly important
that you call me as soon
as you get this message.
Thank you.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Look, we sent agents.
She's gonna be fine.
He got to Hess, Ray
and Colby.
(GUN COCKS)
Inside, quietly.
(DOOR CREAKS)
Isabella!
Hey, check it out.
(DIALING)
(CELL PHONE RINGS, BEEPS)
BAPTISTE:
Consider yourself lucky.
I'm going to let you have
the opportunity
I never got with my boy.
I'm going
to let you say goodbye.
Papa? Papa?
Papa!
Don't do this.
Don't hurt her.
I have no interest
in hurting her.
Only you.
Reddington.
Daniel died because
you wanted his business.
I can help you get
some of that.
Ray, Hess, Colby,
they're middle management.
Essential,
but not important.
I can get you people
who are irreplaceable.
Take them down
and Reddington follows.
I'm listening.
I need two hours.
You've got one.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
You think he believes that
you're gonna really help him
take down Reddington?
He should.
Because it's true.
...as quickly
as you can.
Yes, Marvin,
that's what I want
to talk to you about.
I'll be right there.
ARAM: Hey.
So I plotted the rest
of the GPS data points.
Later.
Uh...
What's going on?
Baptiste has his daughter.
What?
Yeah, he's gonna sell out
Reddington to get her back.
That's a joke, right?
Not to him.
Uh, what can we do?
Got to issue a BOLO
on Baptiste,
a silver alert
on Isabella,
and let's try to keep him
from getting
Reddington killed.
Dembe blamed himself
for what happened to Liz.
He shouldn't.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Let's get out the alerts,
then I'll show you.
Did you know?
Did you know,
when you gave us the case,
that it was Baptiste?
That I would be going in blind
against a man
who wants me dead?
I didn't. In fact,
I didn't know for sure
you were even on the case,
or the task force,
for that matter.
I don't want you
to get hurt, Dembe.
I just want you
out of my life.
He has Isabella.
What? Has he reached out,
made any kind of demand?
He has.
And we've come
to an understanding.
I'm very sorry.
Is there anything
I can do?
You think I betrayed you.
That Elizabeth died
because I let down
my guard.
Fine.
I admit that.
But if you want to do
something for me,
admit that you let down
your guard, too.
That night, and after,
you abandoned your business,
and people died.
That man's son.
I didn't ask you
to carry on.
No.
You just vanished.
I killed that boy trying
to protect your empire.
I was doing it for you,
because you didn't do it
for yourself.
Elizabeth was dead.
I was gone.
And you killed that boy.
Do those dots
really connect?
It seems
a little simplistic.
Excuse me.
I have to make a phone call.
I don't think
he has any idea
what you were left with
after he disappeared.
But I do.
I know all too well.
Isabella
won't speak to me.
She says if I do this, I'll be
a traitor to my community.
She won't be the only one
that tells you that.
That joining the FBI
makes you a cog
in the machine
of institutional racism.
You might remind her
there was a time
when a Black man or woman
wasn't allowed
to wear a badge
or carry a gun.
But thanks to trailblazers
like Bass Reeves,
Big Sam Battle
who paved the way for us,
we have the privilege
of serving our community
and fellow man.
In fact, scratch that.
It's not a privilege,
it's a responsibility.
(LIQUID POURING)
I understand
where Isabella's coming from,
but our people built
this country, died for it.
We deserve justice as much
as anyone, if not more.
I think this is
precisely the place
where people who look like
you and me need to be.
Our people need us here,
fighting for them,
fighting for everyone.
Here, in the system,
boots on the ground,
because sometimes
we're the only ones
standing between them
and the wolves at the door.
In my experience,
there are wolves
on both sides.
Where does Reddington
fit into all of this?
He doesn't,
and I can't ask him.
Because you know
what he'll say?
Because I don't know
where he is.
He disappeared one night
without even saying goodbye.
I'm not sure
I'm staying with the Bureau.
After everything
that's happened,
I may need to step away,
but before I do that,
if you want this,
I promise you,
I'll make it happen.
With Baptiste,
you said you'd come
to an understanding.
That's right.
Tell me about it.
Perhaps I can help you come up
with an even better one.
I would before.
Not now.
I mean it.
I don't want
to see you hurt.
You or anyone
you care about.
It was an honor
protecting you.
But now I have
to protect myself.
RESSLER:
Any word on Isabella?
I know what I need to do.
Yeah,
but does Reddington?
ARAM: Look, you're gonna do
what you have to do,
but if what you have to do
has anything to do
with what's going on between
you and Mr. Reddington...
Look, he's finally
finished mapping
the data points
on Vandyke's cell phone.
Right, and you're gonna
wanna hear what I found.
Will it help me
find Isabella?
Well, uh, no.
Then it will have to wait.
I wish this could help.
Maybe it can.
How? We didn't get to tell him
what we found.
No, but there's someone else
we could.
Dembe, come in.
I am so glad you called.
This business
between you and Raymond,
I want you to know I think
he is completely overreacting.
I appreciate
you saying that.
I mean, the suggestion
that you are in any way
responsible for what happened
to Elizabeth is preposterous.
I agree.
But the reason I'm...
Tell me, what can I do
to help set things right
between you two?
I will do anything.
I need the names
of his banker
in the Caymans,
his arbitrage trader
in Beijing,
and the arms dealer he uses
in Zagreb.
I knew them before,
but he has other ones now.
Yes, he does.
But, uh, how would me
giving you the names
help patch things up
between you two?
Yeah, about that...
I'm not interested
in patching anything up.
All right. Uh, that's, uh...
That's unexpected.
My daughter's life depends
on you giving me the names.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, that's unfortunate,
because I am, uh,
pretty confident
that my life depends on me
not giving them to you.
You know Raymond.
He's a stickler for things
like, oh, I don't know,
say, uh,
not giving the names
of his top three lieutenants
to a guy
like Boukman Baptiste.
I need the names,
Marvin.
I see that,
and I would give them
to you if I could.
I met Isabella.
She's amazing.
(SIGHS)
I need the names.
And this is all of them?
ARAM: Dembe plotted
most of the GPS data points.
I finished mapping them,
then double-checked
what he'd done.
This is every place Vandyke
was the day he shot Elizabeth,
from 12:01 a.m.
until he, and his phone,
ended up in the morgue.
Given everything
that was happening,
how in God's name
did you think to have
Vandyke's phone stolen
from the morgue?
Muscle memory.
It was completely involuntary,
like breathing.
Or an innate desire
for revenge.
In order to get
his daughter back,
Dembe's gonna give Baptiste
damaging information
about you.
What information?
I don't know,
but I heard him
talking on the phone.
Something about getting it
from Marvin Gerard.
Dembe told us what you thought
happened that day.
This...
This tells a different story.
Not entirely, but, yes.
(CELL PHONE DIALING)
He won't help you.
Are you calling to gloat?
Put Marvin on.
Whatever you're looking for,
he won't give you
without my permission.
Why would you give it?
We can discuss that later.
There's no time now.
Put him on.
He wants tier-one names
in the Caymans, Beijing
and Damascus.
Give them to him. I'll get
Chuck and Morgan on him.
Baptiste can have the names
if it means freeing Isabella.
But if he acts on the intel,
I'm bleeding,
so I need to get eyes
on this.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
(GEARSHIFT CLICKS)
Out.
CHUCK:
It's a parking facility.
Deming and Clark.
REDDINGTON: Sit tight.
She's on her way
with Santiago.
Nothing happens
until Isabella is safe.
What about the task force?
You can't go in
with them.
I don't trust anyone else
to go in for me anyway,
so you're on your own.
He's here,
and he's clean.
Car stays, you go.
Level three.
Isabella.
I wouldn't.
Papa...
Everything's
going to be okay.
Did you bring
the names?
Let her go, please.
After I have the names.
Tell me,
where do you feel it,
knowing you are helpless
to save your child?
I know where I felt it.
I'm curious
if you feel it there, too.
My back.
Exactly.
As if the pain
has a weight you can't bear.
Look at us.
So much hatred,
and now so much in common.
You said
you'd let her go.
I need to verify
the names.
That can't be done.
If I couldn't do it,
I wouldn't have asked you
to bring them.
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
Man, the lot's closed.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I don't speak Spanish.
Chuck said
Dembe went up.
We're going down.
(TIRES SCREECH)
Why is this happening?
Did you kill his son?
Did you do it?
After Elizabeth died,
I had to make decisions
for Raymond.
Baptiste
was taking territory.
We had to stop him.
I led a team
that found him
and tried
to take him out.
But you took out
his son instead.
Is that what happened?
Yes.
And after that,
you became a cop?
Yes.
TOGETHER: I do solemnly swear
that I will support
and defend the Constitution
of the United States
against all enemies,
foreign and domestic,
that I will bear true faith
and allegiance to the same.
Congratulations,
Special Agent.
Thank you.
It wouldn't have happened
without you.
Isabella didn't come.
I'm sorry.
The names are correct.
You have what you want.
Let her go.
Nothing you do here
will bring Daniel back.
(GASPS)
The French take billions
from our poor country
every year.
(GUN COCKS)
Corrupt politicians
take from the poor
and open our ports
to people like Reddington.
This is about
more than revenge.
This is about power.
This is about taking
what I am owed.
(ISABELLA SNIFFLES)
What my countrymen
are owed.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
There are two kinds of people
in the world,
wolves and sheep.
The wolves take.
The sheep get taken.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
Unfortunately for you,
I am a wolf.
(TIRES SCREECH)
Whoever you are,
you're a little late!
Somebody's
about to get shot.
I wouldn't have picked
a wolf.
Who asked you?
It may be
an alpha predator,
but they only travel
in packs.
And something tells me you're
not dealing with sheep here.
(GASPS, GROANS)
(GUNSHOT)
It's done.
(GASPING)
A wolf
would put me
out of my misery.
Maybe.
But I'm an FBI agent,
so you're under arrest.
The names you gave them,
were they able
to confirm the identities?
Yes.
(GASPS, GAGS)
Trace the last call
and take care of it.
Raymond has something
he wants to show you.
As soon as you can.
It's good to see you,
Dembe.
You, too.
(CRIES)
(BEEPING)
This is the complete mapping
of Vandyke's whereabouts
on the day
Elizabeth was killed.
I know we've talked
about my lack of awareness
and that
I should have seen Vandyke
watching us
at the coffee shop.
But I wanted to plot this
because I've also
been agonizing
over the fact
that maybe
I was the reason
Vandyke was there
in the first place,
that I led him
to Elizabeth.
Well, as it turns out,
you didn't.
He was nowhere near you
that day,
not before the coffee shop.
Which means
he didn't follow you there.
And we know
where Elizabeth was?
Yes, I've plotted her day
more times
than I care to remember.
So if Vandyke
didn't follow either of you
to the coffee shop,
how did he know where to go?
Someone
obviously told him.
Yeah,
but who could have known?
I mean, I'm as big
a conspiracy theorist
as the next guy,
but this sounds like some
classic Third Man stuff.
REDDINGTON:
Yeah, that night,
I couldn't sleep.
I felt like if I stayed,
I would implode,
that I'd collapse into myself
like a black hole
and cease to exist.
So I left.
I walked away and...
And kept walking.
Until I found
Weecha and Mierce.
And they helped me.
And I helped them.
I'm sorry
that I abandoned you.
Whatever happened,
I shouldn't have done that.
And I'm sorry
that I did.
I know you're upset that
I gave Elizabeth the letter.
Ah. It's done.
And perhaps
it did bring her some peace.
But we can't be fighting
each other
when we have a real enemy
to fight, to find.
You'll have
to forgive Marvin.
He's a professional skeptic.
But someone led Elizabeth's
killer to her that night.
And we need to work together
to find who that was.
But that's a quest
that will have to wait
another day.
I'm late to a very
important engagement.
More important
than finding out
who killed Elizabeth?
I think so.
"Pippi was sure
that her mother
was now up in Heaven,
"watching her little girl
through a peephole
in the sky,
"and Pippi often waved up
at her
"and called,
'Don't you worry about me.
"'I'll always come out
on top.'"
That was so awful.
It was my fault.
It's all my fault.
I want to protect you,
but all I do is seem
to put you in harm's way.
Can you promise me
it's over?
With Baptiste, yes.
With everything.
With what you've done
with Reddington.
Is it done coming back
to us? To me?
I don't know.
I'm going away.
With Elle.
Not forever,
but for now.
Where will you go?
I don't think
I should tell you that.
This isn't a punishment.
It's not about you
being a cop.
I know.
No, really, it's not.
I was upset with you
about that.
And I'd be lying if I said
I still wasn't upset.
But you can be
a police officer
and a man
who's proud to be Black.
I know that because I know
that's who you are.
I want you to feel safe.
And I want us
to be together.
I've missed you.
Yeah,
I've missed you, too.
Can I see Elle
before you go?
Of course.
I was reading her a story.
I'm sure she'd love for you
to finish it.
"'You have plenty of courage,
I am sure,' answered Oz.
"'All you need
is confidence in yourself.
"'There is no living thing
that is not afraid
"'when it faces danger.'"
"Her father,
Pippi had not forgotten,
"he was a sea captain
who sailed
on the great ocean,
"and Pippi had sailed with him
in his ship
"until one day,
her father blew overboard
"in a storm
and disappeared."
"'True courage is in facing
danger when you are afraid,
"'and that kind of courage
you have in plenty.'
"'Perhaps I have,
"'but I'm scared
just the same,'
said the Lion."
"But Pippi
was absolutely certain that
he would come back.
"She would never believe
that he had drowned.
"She was sure he had floated
"until he landed on an island
inhabited by cannibals.
"And she thought
he had become
the king of all the cannibals
"and went around
with a golden crown
"on his head
all day long.
"'My papa is a cannibal king,
"'it certainly isn't
every child
who has such a stylish...'"