You know,
the first stock exchange
started in Belgium, 1531,
and for the next
five centuries,
this flow of capital
transformed the world
more than politics,
religion, war.
And like all markets,
ours depends on rules.
The honest reporting
of profit and loss.
You failed to do that.
You, uh...
You lied
on your disclosure forms.
You raised $78 million
to build a tunnel
under the border
that you never
intended to build.
Five miles of road and rail,
flatbeds, pallets, people,
with entrances and exits
located at warehouses
that you control.
Instead,
you invested the money
in Miami real estate.
Now, on Wall Street,
this kind of Ponzi scheme
would get you a slap
on the wrist
and a Central Park co-op.
Your investors, however,
the often
unscrupulous people
you ripped off...
I think you see where
I'm going with this.
It's nowhere good.
They're very emotional people,
and right now,
their emotions are tending
towards usury and murder.
Luckily for you,
we have rules
that we've all
agreed to follow.
To wit.
You know, I have no idea
what "to wit" means.
I just love the way
that it sounds.
(CHUCKLES) Let's see.
Section 42,
subparagraph C.
Punishments.
To wit. (CHUCKLES)
Punishments are for
the Chairman to decide.
Now, your investors
want you dead.
I'm thinking
more walking dead.
Living, breathing examples
of what happens
when you break our rules.
These are the consent forms
you each signed,
consenting to abide
by my decision.
And my decision is this.
Repayment in full, plus 20%.
And fingers.
Two from you.
Three from you.
From the hand you used
to sign your consent form.
You see,
this is a blood oath.
You broke it, so I get a piece
of what you broke it with.
Beth, you're the ringleader.
Lead the ring.
No. No, please
don't do this.
GUARD:
Too late for that.
No. Oh!
(CRYING)
****
Uh, Joe, that's,
uh, three from Beth.
Just, uh, work backwards
from the pinkie.
No. No, please.
Oh, and, uh, Beth,
feel free to tell anybody
who asks...
If they're gonna cheat,
cheat the stock market,
not the night market.
No.
No. (SCREAMS)
(BEEPS)
You know, MPD has
nothing on the bartender.
After a month.
It's like it never happened.
Well, he was hit
by a pro.
Finding a clue trail's
gonna take some time.
I don't have time.
What I have is some voicebox
who keeps calling
to remind me
he's got a gun to my head.
Yeah, well,
the next time he calls,
you'll be able
to record his voice,
and we'll see if we can't
unscramble the voicebox
and get an ID.
What the hell
are you looking for?
Mimi's missing.
A stuffed bunny.
Yea big. Charred feet.
A bunny?
With charred feet?
It's Agnes'
transitional object.
At her age, isn't that
called a smartphone?
It belonged
to her mother.
It played a key role
in the breakup
of the Soviet Union.
The bunny did?
Thank you, by the way,
for the phone
and for reviewing
the case file again.
Yeah, well,
I've reviewed it
three times.
Then thanks
for reviewing it a fourth.
We have to find out
what happened
to the bartender,
and if the cops can't help us,
we have to help ourselves.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hm.
"Nick's Pizza."
Maybe they have
the bunny.
(CELL PHONE CLICKS)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(DOOR OPENS)
Harold.
Please.
Reading your future?
(LAUGHS)
I don't know.
Mierce.
For me,
it's just...calming.
Is this about Elizabeth?
Her body needs
to be exhumed, Harold.
Aram told me
about the tracker.
That whomever wanted her dead
put it in her, not on her.
And yet you posted guards
at her grave.
She's resting in peace.
I intend on
keeping it that way.
Much of my world
exists right
alongside yours.
People and organizations
in our two worlds
have the same needs.
Security. Medical care.
Air travel.
Corporate infrastructure.
Financial services.
Hence the night market,
a stock market for criminals.
The Sinaloa Cartel
issues stocks?
Cartels, gangs,
crime syndicates.
The Yakuza is no different
than Google.
They both issue stock
to raise money
to pay for R&D,
capital expenses,
to expand
their operations.
Are you in the market?
Of course.
Capital markets are the key
to explosive growth
in your world.
The night market
is no different in mine.
I'd be a fool not to
take advantage of it.
But you want us
to bring it down.
The man in charge is known
as the Chairman.
I don't know
his real name
or where exactly
to find him.
He moves around a lot.
What I do know
is that he
is a one-man SEC.
Judge, jury,
and executioner.
These unfortunates
misled their investors
in advance of an IPO.
The Chairman did this?
To send a message.
Quite literally.
They take a photo
and disseminate it
to the community.
You're wrong
about Elizabeth.
She's not resting
nor in peace.
She's dead.
She can't be disturbed
because she doesn't exist.
We exist.
We hurt.
We are in pain.
And we need answers.
COOPER: What you're looking at
is a black market
stock market.
The night market is made up
of hundreds of companies
raising billions in capital.
But what companies?
What do the initials
stand for?
According to Reddington,
they're a code that he
doesn't have the key to.
RESSLER: Well, if this is
an online trading platform,
why don't we
just pull the plug?
ARAM: Because
the night market
is hosted
on a decentralized
blockchain network,
meaning it runs across
10,000 nodes
all over the world.
Even if we could find one
and shut it down,
the other 9,999
would keep humming.
We'd basically have
to disconnect the entire
Internet to stop it.
The only company Reddington
could identify is this one.
BKRC stands for
Banda Korce.
Albanian.
Specializing in extortion
and money laundering.
Casinos are their
drug of choice.
A fact that
Gaming Enforcement
got wind of.
They opened up
an investigation
into Tremont Casinos.
That's the legitimate company
that BKRC muscled in on.
And as a result,
Tremont's stock
on Wall Street
went down 30%,
and yet...
On the night market,
BKRC's up 25%.
PARK: How's that possible?
The investigation
by Gaming Enforcement
should be bad
for both companies.
Markets price
in information.
If BKRC's stock is going up,
that means the criminal market
knows something that
the legitimate one doesn't.
Like that?
They're gonna be able
to stop the investigation?
The night market
is run by a man
who does this
to people who cross him.
He's known as
the Chairman.
The only way to bring down
the market is to get to him.
Maybe the way to do that
is to get to BKRC first.
Dembe, Park,
go to Gaming Enforcement,
see what they know.
****
Did Reddington say
anything about the guards
posted at the cemetery?
He did. And he wasn't
happy about it.
His concern is our need
for closure,
not hers for peace
and tranquility.
His need or ours?
If what you're asking is
do the guards stay,
the answer's yes.
Great.
Thank you.
Look, I want answers
as much as Reddington,
but not at the expense
of disturbing Liz's remains.
Tremont's stock
is in a nose dive
because our investigation
is rock solid.
We know they're in business
with Banda Korce,
that Banda Korce
is run by Driton Abazi,
and that he is using Tremont's
casinos to launder money.
DEMBE: What's your timeline?
When do you plan
on arresting Abazi?
He's smart.
Insulated.
But we finally got someone
on the inside.
Your inside source,
what's his name?
If we tell you
and you approach him,
he might run scared,
and everything we've
worked on could be lost.
We want to make sure
he's okay.
Why wouldn't he be?
What aren't you telling us?
It's conventional wisdom
in the criminal world
that your investigation
is going nowhere.
Since it rests
on this source,
it stands to reason
that his life may be
in danger.
It's not a he.
It's a she.
And we have no case
without her.
****
Thanks for the Dom, baby.
Lorik just gave it to me,
but he didn't tell me
what it was for.
It's a going-away
present.
(GASPS)
I like the sound of that.
Where are we going?
A toast.
To stupidity.
That's a dumb toast.
Well, we are
dumb people.
I'm stupid for thinking
that you loved me,
and you're stupid
for thinking
I wouldn't find out
what you did.
(SCOFFS) What are you
talking about?
Don't talk. Drink.
If you have enough
before he gets there,
it might not
hurt as much.
If this is a joke,
it's not funny.
It's not a joke.
It's a going-away
present.
Okay, I don't understand.
Where are we going?
We are not
going anywhere.
You are.
To a very painful place.
The champagne may numb it.
That's it.
My present.
To numb the pain.
Oh, it's the classic
love story.
Boy meets girl,
girl betrays boy,
boy has psychopath
dismember girl.
It's so cliched,
it's almost boring.
I didn't betray anybody.
That would be hard
to prove.
Gaming Enforcement encrypts
all of its files.
Unfortunately, someone forgot
to firewall the copy machine.
You don't believe him,
right, baby?
Look, please,
I didn't...
(BODY THUDS)
THE CHAIRMAN:
You know, I love reading
quarterly reports,
examining
financial disclosures,
regulating the market.
The part of my job I detest
is enforcement.
Lately, it seems like
all I do.
****
Two years.
We've spent two years
trying to turn Tsiona Stern.
And then we show up
and she disappears.
McVAY: Disappears?
She's dead.
She didn't miss
a check-in, not one,
until you started
asking around.
Ms. Stern put her life at risk
to help expose Banda Korce.
That was very brave.
And we can honor
that bravery
by carrying on
with her work.
You by going back
to your office,
reviewing your files,
and seeing where the case
stands without her.
We, by looking into
her murder.
We can't do that
without names.
Family, friends.
Who was closest to her?
She had a sister.
Ressler,
get a name and number.
Take Dembe.
See what she knows.
Did you find anything
on the bartender?
Maybe yes, maybe no.
The, uh, bartender was close
with a woman he worked with.
Did the police
talk with her?
Well, they tried,
but she wouldn't
return their calls.
You know,
the cops got busy,
had other leads,
and she fell
through the cracks.
It turned out that she didn't
return their calls
because she disappeared.
She left her apartment
the day after the murder
and hasn't
been seen since.
Do you have a name?
I do.
That's about all I have.
Like I said,
may be a lead,
maybe not.
Hey, uh, by the way,
did you ever find the bunny
that solved the Cold War?
That's a hell
of a bedtime story.
Mimi belonged
to Agnes' mother.
Holding on to it
is like holding on to her.
And, yeah,
it's a hell of a story.
One I'm not sure
I should tell Agnes.
Her mother's part in it
was complicated.
Agnes deserves the truth,
even the parts
that are complicated.
So you think that extends
to how her mother died,
which might be the most
complicated part of all?
Yeah, well,
of all the parts of the story
that you have to tell,
that's the
most important one.
Without it,
she'll never get closure.
Thanks, Lew.
For the advice.
And for this.
Mm. Yeah. Hey,
did voicebox
ever reach out?
Not yet, but it's been
a few weeks,
so it's only
a matter of time.
Right.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS, DIALS)
Hey. I'd like to meet.
No.
At the cemetery.
I begged her
not to cooperate
with the cops.
I told her just to get out.
But she was
stuck on the guy.
Well, if she cared for Abazi,
why'd she inform on him?
It was volatile,
passionate.
Spite. Anger. Jealousy.
The trifecta
of the scorned lover.
So Abazi cheated on her.
He's a thug.
Hurting people,
skimming off casino profits.
She might've gone
against him anyway,
but Felicia sure helped.
Felicia...
Dawson.
S-She's a dealer
he moved
into one of the suites
at the casino.
Tsiona followed him there,
expecting to catch him
with Felicia, which she did,
as well as finding him
having some kind of
business meeting.
You want to bug a suite
at the casino?
The informant's sister
says that's where Abazi
conducted a lot
of his business.
The suite's
rented in the name
of his girlfriend.
His other girlfriend.
A Felicia Dawson.
DEMBE: Former casino employee.
Divorced.
Five-year-old daughter.
Who's now consorting
with criminals,
which should be enough
for us to pull a warrant,
hear what they
talk about.
And hopefully hear enough from
Abazi to get to the Chairman.
Getting a warrant
might not be the problem,
but installing
the bug is.
I do not envy the guy
who has to slip in and out
of the love nest
of an Albanian mobster.
ARAM: Room service.
Hands out.
FELICIA: I'm not doing it.
ABAZI: Doing what?
I'm asking you
to meet some people.
I know what you're
asking me to do,
and the answer is no.
Call me back
when you're alone.
What are you looking at?
(DOOR CLOSES)
ARAM: Oh. Uh, nothing.
I will just
put things out.
Very good.
****
(SNIFFLING)
Oh. Hello.
I'm guessing the hot dog
is for you.
You wanna eat it
down here?
Okay.
One hot dog coming up.
There you go. Voila.
What's wrong?
Parents fighting?
They're not my parents.
He's not.
What's that?
I saw you put it there.
That? Oh, um, that's part
of a magic trick.
And if it's done right,
Mr. Abazi will disappear.
People can't disappear.
Not normally, no.
But, uh, this...
This is a very special trick.
But for it to work,
you can't tell anyone.
Not even your mom.
Think you can do that?
But if he goes,
will he ever come back?
Of course not.
It's magic.
COOPER: Agnes is doing well.
At school, she's getting
mostly A's.
A B+ in math.
She doesn't really like math.
Neither do I.
(CHUCKLING)
She's got lots of friends.
At the moment,
her biggest concern
is that we have
misplaced Mimi.
I'm sure she'll turn up,
but for now, the house
is being turned upside down.
When my father died,
I kept a little
painting of his.
He always wished
he'd been a real painter.
But at least
there was the one.
He took
terrible care of it,
so it's faded and torn.
But it reminded me of him,
so I kept it
in the bathroom.
Every morning,
he and I would have
a little (CHUCKLING) chat.
Why do we do that,
talk to the dead?
They're gone.
Why do we talk to them?
But they're not gone.
As long as we're here,
they're here with us.
Where are the guards?
I dismissed them.
If Elizabeth
is watching over us,
I think she'd want Agnes
to know the truth,
at least as much of it
as we can give her.
Thank you.
I'll get a court order.
If we're gonna do this,
we're gonna do it
the right way.
****
Hello, Elizabeth.
COOPER: Where did you find it?
REDDINGTON: It was
under the seat.
Agnes fell asleep on the way
back from the opera.
She must've dropped it.
I've been
looking everywhere.
You have no idea
what a relief this is.
(CHUCKLING)
Of course I do.
Elizabeth couldn't sleep.
Colicky.
But more often than not,
when she scrunched that bunny
against her cheek,
she was calm, quiet.
You should've taken her
to the opera.
(CHUCKLES)
That'll put anyone
to sleep.
(CHUCKLES)
****
Harold, please instruct
the medical examiner
to be as respectful
as possible.
Why? Because I'm terrified
for my daughter.
Yes, names, dates.
(SIGHS)
That's fine.
Roger's Park, 3:00.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
****
The meeting's set
with King and McVay.
You did good.
Even I believed
you betrayed me.
When I was there, I heard
Abazi and Felicia arguing.
This could be why.
He's using her to set up
King and McVay.
ABAZI: This is how
it's gonna go.
Lorik drives.
You get out,
enter the park.
When they approach,
you drop your sunglasses,
bend down to pick them up.
Lorik does the rest.
Meaning he kills them.
Meaning that
whatever it is,
you don't have to
worry about it.
RESSLER: All right,
Dembe and I
will go to the park.
You let King and McVay know
they're walking into a trap.
(SIGHS)
Does Abazi actually think
killing the two people
investigating him
will stop the investigation?
He's not thinking.
He's reacting.
Like a cornered animal
lashing out.
LILY: Mommy!
FELICIA: Mommy's gonna go
run an errand.
Driton's coming over
to be with you
while I'm gone, okay?
Don't worry, kid.
We'll have a good time.
(BEEP)
Please make him disappear.
Oh, sir, sir,
about, uh, Driton Abazi...
Not now, okay?
Is everything all right?
I'm sure it will be.
It's just...
The exhumation.
I ordered it.
MEDICAL EXAMINER:
Pursuant to an order issued
by Superior Court Judge
Victoria Shapiro,
we are conducting
an exhumation autopsy
on Elizabeth Keen.
The purpose of the autopsy
is to determine
whether Agent Keen
ingested a tracking device
which remains
inside her postmortem.
RESSLER: All right.
Thank you.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Where are we
on King and McVay?
That was their supervisor.
They're not picking up
his calls or mine.
I'm not surprised.
After what happened
to their last informant,
they don't trust anybody,
especially us.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Okay.
All right. This could be
the agents arriving.
****
Here comes King and McVay.
DEMBE: I'll keep eyes
on the driver.
Thanks for coming.
We want to start by saying
we will protect you.
I wish you could,
but you can't
even protect yourselves.
It's a hit.
FBI! Stand back!
Are you all right?
DEMBE: Get away from the car!
Donald Ressler, FBI.
You need to come with us.
No, I can't.
My daughter...
We know about
your daughter.
Is she all right?
She will be.
If you come with us, now.
****
FELICIA: It's done.
But Lorik was shot.
I don't know.
One of the agents, I think,
before they were killed.
(SIGHS)
I-I don't know.
It all happened so fast.
I just...
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Baby, I'm scared.
I need you
to come and get me.
And I need you
to bring Lily.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah.
I know where that is.
Okay.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
He's coming for me.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
But you can't do anything
until I have my daughter.
Where did Abazi
tell you to meet?
****
Hi, baby!
Mommy!
I did what you
asked me to do.
What else would I do?
You had Lily.
Driton, please.
****
You're okay.
Mm!
****
FBI! Hands!
Hands!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
DEMBE: FBI!
You're under arrest.
Hands!
Let's see 'em!
MAN: Turn around.
****
And clear.
Everyone, stand down.
****
Told you
he'd disappear.
Good job.
(SIGHS)
(HANDCUFFS CLICK)
I'll update Cooper
on Abazi's arrest.
Has he talked to you
about Elizabeth yet?
No. Why?
What about her?
COOPER: The ME
found the tracker.
REDDINGTON: I'll get there
as soon as we can.
We should discuss
what comes next.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
(DOOR OPENS)
Is it true about Liz?
That you pulled the guards?
That you dug her up?
I know you feel, but I decided
it was the right thing to do.
You decided?
Yes.
Reddington
put you up to this.
They found the tracker.
All you did was
desecrate her grave.
Elizabeth would've
wanted us to do this.
She would want us
to know who's responsible
for her death.
You wanna know
who's responsible
for killing her?
It was Reddington.
(DOOR SLAMS)
(DOOR OPENS)
****
(FOOT STOMPS)
(GRUNTS)
Contact Pilken.
Tell him we're done
with Abazi,
have him delist Banda Korce.
The stockholders
won't be happy.
We have rules.
When a company
is in legal trouble,
they're sacrificed
to protect the market.
I want you
to clean the place.
Collect every flash drive,
every file,
every Post-it Note.
If it so much as mentions
the night market,
I want it destroyed.
What about Abazi?
Will he talk?
Oh, he's seen how
we deal with informants.
He won't say a word.
He won't talk.
Did he lawyer up?
PARK: No. He's terrified
of the Chairman.
We said we'd protect him.
He laughed.
COOPER: What about Felicia?
DEMBE: I think
she would cooperate
if it meant protecting
her daughter.
But I don't think
she knows anything.
So we're nowhere on connecting
Abazi to the night market.
****
(DRAWER CLOSES)
Oh, hey. Uh, so I,
uh, I've been looking
into the tracker.
And I-I don't suppose
you're interested
in an update.
You supposed right.
ARAM: It is incredibly cool.
I mean, uh, well, not the way
it was used, of course,
but big picture,
this thing is insane.
It has a power supply
and a microprocessor
that is only activated
to transmit data
when it comes into
contact with the target's
digestive enzymes.
I must say, I've, uh,
had my fill of analyzing
the contents
of people's stomachs
of late.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, that's understandable.
Is there a signature
of any kind,
something to identify
where it was made
or by whom?
I don't know yet. Maybe.
I need to keep looking.
Then that's what
I want you to do.
There can't be
that many people
in the world
capable of making
something this advanced.
I'm confident
we'll find him,
more confident than I am
that we'll find the Chairman.
Abazi won't talk.
Of course not.
But you don't
really need him to.
He's our connection
to the Chairman.
A connection we can't make
unless he talks.
So just say
that he talked.
Tell the world
that you've been
investigating
the night market
and are preparing
to shut it down.
None of which is true.
Well, what is true,
Harold,
is that rumor
can drive the market.
That's why Banda Korce's
stock went up,
on the rumor that they'd found
the government informant.
You want to flush out
the Chairman?
Spread the rumor that Abazi
sang like a canary.
Which no one can contradict
because he's in custody.
You want me to lie
through my teeth
at a press conference?
I want you to apply
situational ethics.
Which I find to be
immensely enjoyable
and ruthlessly effective.
And would make for
a fantastic board game.
We got everything.
Notebooks. Tablets.
There's nothing left
that can hurt us.
Yeah, it's me.
We need a circuit breaker.
Level Three.
Yes, now. Before the market
drops another 20%.
(SIGHS)
What's going on?
That's what I'm trying
to find out.
(BEEPS)
Mr. Abazi is wanted
in connection
with extortion
and money laundering.
His company also trades
on a criminal stock market
known as the night market.
Mr. Abazi has agreed
to cooperate fully.
Call a meeting.
All the board members.
I can't believe
he talked.
Because he didn't.
It's a trick.
I need to make sure
nobody else falls for it.
REDDINGTON:
Chum's in the water.
Our shark won't be able
to resist.
I hope you're right.
Take the win, Harold.
You did well.
(CHUCKLES)
(CELL PHONE CLICKS SHUT)
(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
MAN: (IN DISTORTED VOICE)
Andrew Kennison.
I don't know who that is.
I need him to go away.
"Go away"?
Disappear.
New identity.
New life.
Why?
Because I said so.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
****
Yes. Lew,
I'm glad you got a lead,
but the bartender's friend's
gonna have to wait.
He called with a demand.
I can't talk about it now.
Just get here
as soon as you can.
Any word from Ressler?
No.
I reached out to him,
but he didn't answer.
I'm worried about him.
He's upset.
Understandable.
But he'll be fine.
Sir, your bluff worked.
Check it out.
It is a huge sell-off.
The rumor you spread
about Abazi
telling us about
the night market
spooked investors.
The market was down 20%
before trading was halted.
Hang on.
Can you stop it?
Every other stock is down
except that one.
COOPER: An interesting
anomaly,
but I don't see
how one company
bucking the market
is relevant to our case.
Maybe not,
but that is a company
I wish I could invest in.
In a way you do.
COC stands for
Concierge of Crime.
Reddington.
It's his company.
You told your investors
it was a bluff.
That's why
your stock's going up
and everybody else's
is tanking.
You traded on
insider information.
I didn't.
But not on principle,
mind you.
I'd do it if it were
in my interest,
but in this case,
it's not.
You didn't bring us this case
to take down the night market.
You brought it us to drive up
your share price.
Actually, I was aiming
for bankruptcy.
And all the freedom
that that implies.
You know what?
Between the exhumation
and other things
I'm dealing with,
I don't have the bandwidth
for your nonsense.
Other things? Do tell.
Why? You never do.
Harold, the market
is teetering,
but it will recover,
unless you move
on the Chairman.
Thanks to your bluff,
I know how you can do that.
How?
He's called a meeting.
I'm on my way to it now.
Where?
I'll tell you,
but first,
you'll have to give me time
to say my piece and go.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
THE CHAIRMAN: Some of you
are new to the market.
Others have been listed
for years.
But this is the first time
any of us have met in person.
That should
give you an idea
of how important
I feel this meeting is.
Now, together,
your companies represent
15% of our market cap.
What you do matters.
You panic, others panic.
If you don't,
we can weather
any storm.
Yeah, but can we
weather the FBI?
Well, if they have something
on us, maybe not.
But they don't.
Abazi didn't talk.
Now, the FBI
said that he did
because they want
to scare investors,
get them to panic.
If they could hurt us,
they would, but they can't.
So they started a rumor
hoping we'll hurt ourselves,
and that is exactly
what we're doing.
$25 million.
I'll put that
in the market by close
of business tomorrow,
a leadership investment
to calm some obviously
frayed nerves.
Mr. Reddington.
Thank you.
See, that's exactly
what we need.
Send a signal
to the other investors
that the FBI
is all sizzle, no steak.
I do have one condition.
Which is?
The name
of the lead investor
in my company.
Well, I'm afraid
I can't do that.
$30 million.
Mr. Reddington,
I talked about privacy.
We have rules.
Bend them.
35. Give me a number.
You must have one.
But I don't.
You're willing
to risk the market
to protect the identity
of a single investor?
I designed
the market interface
to protect
against this kind of bribe,
or was that a threat?
I anticipated the need
to keep men like you
from hanging me
off the side of a building
every time they felt cheated
by a short sale.
So I made sure the identity
of each and every investor
was shielded,
even from me.
Well, I'm sure you all
have more to discuss,
but I've said what
I came to say
and heard what
I care to hear.
So please excuse me.
****
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
Andrew Kennison.
Who is he?
COOPER:
An MIT grad student.
What his connection
is to any of this,
I have no idea.
And voicebox
wants him disappeared.
A new ID.
A new life.
Okay. So that's
what you do.
Kidnap a grad student?
Buy time.
Keep voicebox happy
until we've had a chance
to talk to
the bartender's friend.
I've got a line on her.
I know that she headed
down south.
Maybe she could tell us
who put him up to doping you,
which would prove
your innocence.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Not a good time.
Then I'll be brief.
3726 Sheridan Road.
They have backup.
So come heavy.
What can we tell Kennison to
convince him to come with me?
My vote, the truth.
I need to speak with my team,
give them an assignment.
Then I'll pay
Mr. Kennison a visit.
****
So, yes,
while a leveraged buyback
will increase the debit
on your balance sheet,
we have a number
of offshore...
FBI! Hands!
Hands!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
****
MAN 2: All right, all right.
(SIGHS) Abazi did talk.
Sang like a bird.
And the melody...
(HANDCUFFS CLICKING)
...it was all about you.
WOMAN: (LAUGHS) Yeah.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(VEHICLE DOOR CLOSES)
Andrew Kennison.
Harold Cooper, FBI.
Whoa. What's this about?
We have reason to believe
your life is in danger.
An agent with the Bureau
has been compromised.
He's being blackmailed,
and for some reason,
the blackmailer wants him
to abduct you.
That's insane. Why?
I was hoping
you could tell me.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
It this
some kind of joke?
I can assure you,
this is deadly serious.
I've contacted
the Marshal Service.
They're prepared to move you
somewhere safe
until the danger's passed.
Move... Move me?
Move me where?
I'll explain it all
in the car.
DEMBE: The codes.
How do you decrypt them?
We have rules.
I don't break them.
Name the companies that trade
on the night market
and you can
help yourself.
Perhaps save yourself.
I'm here
because you lied.
Now you want me
to break my word?
And you're the good guys?
You created a market
that channeled billions
into criminal enterprises.
Enron. Tyco.
AIG. Freddie Mac.
Who channeled billions
to them?
Have you arrested anyone
on Wall Street
who financed
their crimes?
Hey, how about
credit default swaps?
Sub-prime lending.
In 2008, those markets
crashed the world economy,
wiped out over $10 trillion
worth of wealth,
cost 8 million people
their jobs.
Did you arrest anyone
for that?
Oh, yeah.
One guy.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
One.
I may lose my freedom.
But if it's
all the same to you...
(CHAIR SCRAPES)
(SNIFFLES)
...I'll keep my integrity.
REDDINGTON: Harold,
come in. Have a seat.
Can I get you anything?
No, I'm fine.
After Elizabeth died, I...
(SIGHS)
...let things go.
Lot of things.
People, businesses,
trade routes,
landing rights.
Streams of income.
When I came back,
I was illiquid.
So I incorporated
and sold stock
on the night market
and got what I needed.
And something I didn't.
Greenmail.
A hostile takeover.
By whom, I don't know.
But someone courted
my shareholders in secret
and bought a controlling
interest in my...
Company.
That's why you wanted
to drive down the share price.
To force them out.
Yes.
But they refused
to sell.
Whoever it is
has a stranglehold on me
and they won't let go.
That's what you wanted
from the Chairman... A name.
(SIGHS)
The tracking device.
Where are we on it?
According to Aram,
there's nothing
in DARPA's files
or the NSF.
He's still looking,
but we haven't traced it
to anyone yet.
You think
they're connected.
Maybe.
Or had someone
give it to her.
Does it work?
To calm you down.
And if so, can you teach me
how to do it?
The "other things"
you're dealing with.
****
I'm down a path.
It's dark and taking me
to places I don't want to go.
I wanna turn back,
but I don't know how.
I was born
to a dark path.
It's the only path
I know.
I've learned how to
recognize light
when I see it.
To stop and stare.
I reach for it.
In the hope that it'll...
Shed its light on me.
And every once in a while,
I'm able to bask
in its warmth
for a moment
before...
...moving on
in the dark.
****
That's my life.
(SIGHS)
Don't make it yours.
Go home
to your wife and kid.
****
(SIGHS) Hey.
Hey.
You okay?
I'm told they're
bringing her back.
Are you okay?
I didn't fall off the wagon,
if that's what you're asking.
I thought about it.
These last few weeks,
I felt so good.
But this...
I'm not gonna lie.
This was a real gut punch.
Of course it was.
But you need to find a way
to take life's punches
without slipping.
And we're here
to help you do that.
We?
I was worried.
I didn't know
where you'd gone,
so I told them.
Told them what?
Everything.
Back to the pee test.
I get it if you're mad,
but they care for you
and wanna help.
(SIGHS)
It's all good.
None of us are perfect.
(SNIFFLES)
Look, I appreciate
what you're doing,
but we're not
in the same boat.
Okay, I walked away
from a multimillion-dollar
start-up,
after blowing
my life savings
and the life savings
of one of my closest
friend's parents.
I lied to my husband
about being a field agent.
You also lied about
being a paid assassin.
He offered blind loyalty
to the most wanted fugitive
in the world.
I wake up
in strange rooms.
Naked.
Covered in vomit.
You're right. That's a...
That's a different boat.
It's a different ocean.
Which is why
we're here.
You can't
slay demons alone.
None of us can.
****
Look, if you don't want
to do this for us,
then let us do it
for her.
****
(BRAKES SQUEAL)
(ENGINE RUMBLING)
(ENGINE SHUTS OFF)
****
It's what she'd
expect us to do.
(VEHICLE DOORS OPEN)
(VEHICLE DOORS CLOSE)
****
COOPER: Look who I found.
Meems!
(CHUCKLES)
Where was she?
In Pinky's car.
You left her there
after the opera.
You know you can
ask me anything...
About your mom,
your grandparents.
Whatever questions you have,
I'll tell you what I know.
Okay.
About Mimi, too.
Mimi?
She's a very
special bunny.
You see this scar?
She got it after
your grandfather
hid a flash drive
inside of her
that contained
a very important secret.
What kind of secret?
A secret that changed
the course of world history.
The entire world
is the way it is
because of a secret
hidden inside that bunny.
By my grandfather?
Yes.
Raymond Reddington.
That's Pinky's name.
Yes, well,
it's a long story.
But it's my story.
Yes, I guess it is.
Tell it.
****
(AFTER ALL PLAYS)
Once upon a time,
a woman named Katarina
met a man named Raymond.
****
One was Russian,
one was American.
And they spied
for their countries
and on each other,
and they didn't agree
on anything
except that they loved
their daughter...
** But I'm not
the simple-minded boy...
COOPER: ...your mother...
** I used to be...
COOPER:
...more than life itself.
** No, I've learned
to picture life...
COOPER: They weren't
alone in that, by the way.
** In its reality...
COOPER: A lot of people
loved your mother.
** And I found after
all the searching
** Life was only
how you take it
** After all the searching
for a new game to play
** I live my life away **
****