****
(LOCK DISENGAGES)
(SIGHS) Looks like
the FBI already took
anything useful.
REDDINGTON:
The FBI has no idea
what's useful to me.
****
Maybe we'll find
the shooter.
I don't know, we've got
everyone out there,
but a guy on a motorcycle?
That bike's
in pieces by now.
The shell casings
are a dead end.
Shooter could be
anyone, anywhere.
All we can do
is keep looking.
Whoever killed Elizabeth is
going through a lot of trouble
to keep you
from finding them.
Seems like it would just
be easier to take you out.
Perhaps they need me.
Or they're saving me
for something special.
Could be they love you.
Or it could be all three.
This is something.
What is this?
****
Oh, this is an item
that definitely
should not be
in the possession
of a former NYPD officer,
even a crooked one
like Reggie Cole.
What is it?
It's a key to a vault
that's inside one
of the most inaccessible,
enigmatic security facilities
in the world.
How do you know that?
I have one just like it.
****
WOMAN: Oh, wow.
(DOOR OPENS)
That's a long time.
Apparently...
(DOOR CLOSES)
Harold. The judge
is taking the bench now.
She's gonna arraign
Lew Sloan first.
I'll give you guys
a few minutes alone together.
Thank you.
Do you mind giving them
a few minutes?
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(SIGHS)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Is it true?
About the cop?
Mateo said
that he was killed?
He and his lawyer.
We couldn't hold them.
As soon as we left
the Post Office,
they were gunned down.
By who? Why?
I don't know.
Other than somehow
it's connected to
Elizabeth's murder.
Which means it's connected
to Reddington.
Oh, he's not to blame,
if that's what you mean.
I lied for you,
to the cops
to give you an alibi.
I lied for you, not him.
No charges will be
filed against you.
Cynthia gave me her word.
Yeah, well, Senator Panabaker
lets Reddington
do as he pleases.
And as soon as you and
poor Lew try to figure out
who framed you for murder,
she just lets you both rot.
This isn't on her, Char,
this is on me.
Based on my years of service,
my attorney expects
that I'll be released
without bail.
So hopefully I can
return to work.
Elizabeth left Agnes
with us as parents,
role models.
You want to make this
right for me, I understand.
But you have got to
make it right for her.
****
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYS)
(DOOR OPENS)
Thank you, Walter.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Helen.
What a delight to see you.
I've been making
a great effort
not to be seen.
By anyone.
How did you know
where to find me?
The real mystery is
why you're hiding
in the private room
and why you aren't
returning calls.
Too many questions,
Raymond.
Mm.
What can I do for you today,
other than marvel
at your deductive powers
and tolerate
your unwanted presence?
A dead cop was storing
something of value
in Mount Bastion.
I need to know what.
I need to get
inside this vault.
Impossible.
You engineered
the impossible
when you carved out the core
of a granite mountain
to build your
impenetrable facility.
Well, I have more
pressing concerns
than enabling your
criminal mischief, Raymond.
Tell me.
I recently consulted
on a job.
A heist crew needed a way
to steal cargo
from a heavily guarded
container yard.
My rig worked
beautifully,
but the crew
left evidence behind.
Now they're in
federal custody
using my name
to cut a deal.
If I'm not
a wanted woman
already,
I fear I shall be
at any moment.
It seems we both
have itchy backs.
An opportunity to scratch
each other's itch.
JUDGE: Mr. Cooper,
it's not every day
an assistant director
of the FBI graces us
with his presence,
particularly on
the wrong side of the bar.
How do you plead
to the charges
against you today?
Not guilty, Your Honor.
JUDGE: I'll hear
the defense on bail.
Defense asks for release
with no bail, Your Honor.
Harold Cooper's led a long
and distinguished career
in law enforcement...
Long and formerly
distinguished
until 10 years ago.
After that?
Who knows?
No one will say.
Everyone knows
everything
in this town,
but what he does
and how he does it is...
No one has a clue.
DeSOTO: Oh, Your Honor.
Which means he can
go anywhere anytime,
which makes him,
by any
reasonable standard,
a flight risk.
Bail is set at $300,000.
Trial in six weeks.
(GAVEL BANGS)
Honey, we can
get the money.
We can cash out
an insurance policy
if we have to.
****
I'm sorry
I couldn't do more.
You kept Charlene
out of this mess.
That's enough.
We're not stopping
until we find out
who's behind this.
If I had any say in this,
the only Blacklister
we'd go after
is the person
who did this to you.
You do have a say.
The say.
You haven't told him yet?
Until the judge
miscarried justice,
I was hoping
I wouldn't have to.
Have to what?
Give you my job.
What? No.
You have my full confidence
and blessings. And you...
Harold, you have to go.
(DOOR OPENS)
I can't do this.
Probably not.
(DOOR CLOSES)
But Harold chose you.
What about Agent Ressler?
What about him?
You eat life,
or life eats you,
Agent Mojtabai.
You're the boss now,
so bon appetit.
****
This is only until
Mr. Cooper is back,
which I hope is really...
Really soon.
Um, I'm just a figurehead,
like Colonel Sanders.
They need a face
on the bucket.
It should've been
your face, obviously.
Square-jawed, dimpled,
top of the pecking order.
I had my shot.
It's your turn.
You'll be fine.
I understand
congratulations
are in order.
Says the man
who really rules
the roost.
If I may offer
some counsel...
"Do not go where
the path may lead.
"Go instead where there is
no path and leave a trail."
In the spirit of that,
I bring an unusual case.
A Blacklister
not to catch,
but to release.
Ah, here we go.
Good luck.
Helen Maghi,
one of the world's
most accomplished structural
and geotechnical engineers.
ARAM: In the invasion of Iraq,
Maghi designed
a floating bridge
to carry tanks
and heavy-armor vehicles
across the Euphrates River
in the dark of night.
Her crowning achievement
is Mount Bastion.
Using proprietary
drilling techniques,
she carved into
a Pennsylvania mountain
of solid granite
to create
an impregnable
storage facility
favored by
the criminal elite,
with more safeguards
and redundancies
than the U.S.
Bullion Depository.
And you want to
break into it.
Well, we found this key
in Reggie Cole's office.
A key to a storage vault
in Mount Bastion.
Mount Bastion would
never rent a vault
to a former police officer,
but they might
to his employer.
His employer,
Harold's blackmailer,
Elizabeth's killer,
all the same person.
What are we waiting for?
Let's storm the mountain.
Impossible
without Maghi's help.
That's where
the task force comes in.
She provided engineering
services to some heist crew
working the Port of Virginia.
The crew
was just arrested
by the FBI,
and Helen is afraid
they'll sell her out
in a plea bargain.
You want us to make
the criminal case
against Helen Maghi
go away,
in exchange for her help
breaking into Mount Bastion.
How do we feel
about that, team?
Show of hands for yes.
Right. I am in charge here.
Okay, uh, Agent Ressler,
Agent Zuma,
track down the FBI team
that made the arrest.
We'll start by trying
to find out what kind
of case they have.
You got it.
And Harold. How is he?
Not good.
He's stuck in jail
with a bail he can't afford.
They cut open
a shipping container
right in the middle
of the yard,
directly in front
of security cameras,
and nobody saw a thing.
How did they do that?
Look at
the red container.
Now check it out
15 minutes later.
(MOUSE CLICKS)
And after that...
And after that.
Who was moving it?
It was moving
itself slowly.
So slowly,
motion cameras
didn't detect it
and security guards
never noticed.
The heist crew
was hiding inside.
They retrofit the container
with hidden wheels,
then crept it
into position
next to the stolen cargo
to block security cameras.
It was brilliantly engineered,
which makes sense given
the woman who hired them.
Helen Maghi.
Now, our intel says that
she was hired by the crew,
uh, as a consultant.
Someone is playing you.
The crew we're talking about
are high school dropouts.
What did they steal?
Six crates of RPGs.
According to our suspects,
Maghi made plans
to ship them
to separatist forces
in Kazban.
To put it simply,
she's arming terrorists.
Mr. Homan?
I don't know who that is.
Our friend with the hat.
He posted bail?
DeSOTO: All $300,000.
Once payment goes through,
you can go home.
Have you spoken
to the prosecutor
about a deal?
A deal?
A deal for what?
She says
she'll take two years
if you plead guilty
to conspiracy.
No!
Char, it's 15
if I go to trial.
But you were framed.
And to find out why I tampered
with evidence and witnesses
and let you lie
to create my alibi.
You were right,
I have to make this
right for Agnes.
A deal is the best way
to do that.
So, Harold,
tell her we're good?
On one condition.
I won't testify
against Lew.
He wouldn't cut a deal
to hurt me,
and I won't cut one
that hurts him.
Okay.
****
Go ahead,
read the results.
I'm not trying
to read anything.
I'm trying to remember.
I miss Mierce.
****
(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Is it done?
Well, we spoke
to the Bureau
about the heist crew
you say hired her.
Only, uh, they say
she hired them
and that, uh,
she's a terrorist.
While dramatic statements are
effective attention grabbers,
overstatement merely
serves to try your
listener's patience.
I'm not being dramatic.
Or maybe I am,
because, well,
stealing RPGs
to arm extremists
in Kazban is,
well, pretty dramatic,
and apparently what she did.
We need the FBI to lose
interest in Helen Maghi.
It's the only way for us
to obtain information
we need to avenge Elizabeth
and free Harold.
You asked us to look into
Maghi's claims, and we did.
And now I'm asking
you to do the same,
respectfully.
Please?
Another word of advice,
moral relativism.
That's two words.
Yes, but one piece of advice.
****
Did you lie
to me, Helen?
Fresh intel says
you've been arming
the separatists
in a war-torn country,
putting innocent
civilians at risk.
And you know me
better than that.
I do.
But my best contact
in law enforcement
has replaced
by a conscience with ears,
so I am unable
at present
to wave your
federal troubles away.
Then we have little
to discuss.
On the other hand,
I could make you disappear.
I'm sorry.
Is that a threat?
What I'm offering
is a gift.
While I can't stop the FBI
from looking for you,
I can certainly make sure
they never find you.
New papers,
private estates.
Reflexologist on call,
day and night.
I prefer shiatsu.
Done.
If I just help you break
into the mountain fortress
I designed.
There must be something
quite valuable
hidden inside that vault.
I hope so, Helen.
I really do.
****
Can I help?
I got it.
I insist.
What are you doing?
Taking this back
where it belongs.
Raymond gave us a case
that can help find
the person who framed you.
He's the one who should be
on trial right now, not you.
I'm not... On trial.
I agreed
to plead guilty.
Wait, what? No.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
You can't because,
um, you're not.
But I am,
and finding the person
who set me up
won't change that.
Two years.
With good behavior,
maybe 18 months.
Then it's over.
Unfortunately,
so is my career,
so thank you,
but I'll take the box
where it belongs.
****
Ah, Harold. Hello.
Hello, Mr. Homan.
Thank you for my bail.
I'll repay it.
I'm not sure
how or when.
Harold, the deal,
your plea to fall on your
all-too-honorable sword,
have you told Agnes
about it?
Have I told her
her life is being
upended again? No.
Of everything
that's happening,
that's the thing
I dread the most.
Then don't.
You want to repay me
for bailing you out...
Say nothing.
I can't protect her
from this.
No, but perhaps I can.
Then you have my word.
And my curiosity.
All I need
is your patience.
****
Helen Maghi denies
arming terrorists.
Do you know a lot of people
who would admit
to arming terrorists?
I do, yes.
I also enjoy that degree
of honesty with Helen Maghi.
A fact I only mention to put
your righteous mind at ease
about working with her.
I can't make
the heist crew's
testimony go away.
She... She will be indicted.
Yes, wheels of justice
and all that.
Terrible metaphor, really.
Wheels turn,
justice sits.
Nonetheless, Helen
has agreed to help us
break into Mount Bastion.
How did you
make her agree?
The only relevant question is,
will you agree to help?
You do know that's
your chair now, right?
Go on, it won't bite.
****
Uh...
This feels wrong.
Well, I'm sure there's
a knob underneath
you can adjust.
Not the chair.
Oh, well, give it time.
You'll do fine.
No, I don't mean the job.
I mean the case.
Despite what Maghi told you,
I have solid intel
that Kazban rebels
are expecting a shipment of
stolen RPGs from the U.S.
And, well,
Maghi is accused
of stealing RPGs,
so I can't let the team
work with a woman
who is actively
arming terrorists.
I'm right
about Helen Maghi.
You need to trust me on that
and move on with this case.
If for no other reason
than if you don't,
Harold will never be able
to reclaim that seat.
****
Mount Bastion.
How do we get in?
My contract
with Mount Bastion
was to engineer
impenetrable storage vaults
inside a mountain
with one heavily fortified
way in and out.
To hide its existence
from the outside world,
the entire facility
had to remain
unconnected to
the municipal power grid.
Okay.
So to stay off the grid,
Maghi built her own
geothermal power station
inside the mountain,
but this created
a hidden vulnerability
'cause the system needs
a constant supply
of circulating water
to dissipate the thermal load.
That water is piped in
underground from
a nearby lake.
If anything happens
to that water supply,
the entire system,
including security,
will overheat and shut down.
So Maghi provided us
with GPS coordinates
of an emergency valve
hidden on the mountainside.
Once Mr. Reddington
and Agent Zuma
are inside the mountain,
you two need to
close the valve and
cut the water supply.
How do Red and Dembe
get inside Mount Bastion?
I thought the place
was like Fort Knox.
ARAM: Turns out
Mr. Reddington
has a vault
of his own there, and,
as his former bodyguard,
Dembe has
security clearance, too.
This should the enable
the both of them
to clear the three levels
of biometric scanners,
and from there,
it is 30 floors down
to the subterranean vaults.
But, as you know,
the guard will escort you
to your private vault,
so you have to
go there first.
By the time
you reach the vault,
your support team
needs to be in position.
ARAM: Mount Bastion
keeps the water valve
under tight watch
with two guards.
Now, you'll relieve them
just before their shift ends,
which gives us a short window
before the real guards arrive.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
(BUZZER)
Hey, guys.
We got it from here.
You're early. We still got
a half-hour left on our shift.
This is our first assignment
on the mountain.
Didn't want to be late.
Be our guest.
****
(DOOR CLOSES)
When you get the signal,
you need to find
this high-pressure water valve
and turn it off quickly.
Without water for cooling,
the power system
will immediately shut down
and switch to auxiliary power.
When that happens,
the guards are ordered
to lock clients
into their vaults
to keep them safe
and then report
to the perimeter
to provide security
for the facility.
At that point,
the Mount Bastion controller
will call Maghi,
the systems designer,
to figure out what
the problem is.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
****
Hello?
CONTROLLER:
Helen, it's Terry.
We have a Tier One problem
on the mountain.
Send me a remote access code,
and I'll take care of it.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
All right. I have surveillance
running on an endless loop.
How long do we have?
HELEN: (OVER COMMS)
You have six minutes to get
to the other vault and back.
After that,
the system reboots,
and it's shoot to kill.
I'm sorry, I wish I could
give you more time.
You've given us enough.
I hope.
Go now.
****
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
(ALARM BLARING)
****
(LOCK DISENGAGES)
It can't be.
But somehow it is.
We put it in a safe
in Tivat.
Only two people
could open it.
And neither of us did.
DEMBE: If it wasn't
you or Elizabeth,
then who did?
And how?
This was her future.
What she needed to succeed.
She would've been great.
Stronger than me.
****
Hurry.
You have 30 seconds.
We have to go, Raymond.
It's time.
****
(ALARM BLARES)
Nothing serious,
I trust?
Not at all. A venting issue,
but we have the all clear.
And we have
what we came for.
Well, it sounds
like a win-win.
You got what you wanted,
and I got a new contract
to retrofit
the geothermal piping
that caused the shutdown.
(LAUGHS)
A contract you'll be
undertaking in a new life
from an undisclosed location
of your choosing.
Oh, I've chosen.
The Villa Peduzzi
on Lake Como.
REDDINGTON: (LAUGHS)
A stone's throw
from Clooney.
Aram asked me to text him
when we're in the air.
If you see him,
please remind him
he still owes me
a case of tequila
for our wager
on the Palio di Siena.
(TABLET CHIMES)
****
Tac Ops, initiate takedown.
Move.
(DOOR OPENS)
FBI!
Hands up.
MAN: Hands where
we can see them!
No, no, dear.
MAN 2: Don't move.
No need to die
on my behalf.
Don't move.
MAN 3: Back, please.
Not today.
Thank you, Walter.
Pancakes are
not a snack food.
According to whom?
I think everyone.
Well, "everyone"
hasn't tasted my pancakes.
Let's see.
A little butter.
That's
a little-and-a-half.
And a little-and-a-half
of syrup.
(RINGTONE PLAYS)
Go on, sink your
fangs into that
and tell me
it isn't amazing.
Hello?
Harold, we have to talk.
It's about Lew.
What happened?
Is he all right?
He's fine.
You're not.
****
You agreed to testify
against me?
You shouldn't be here.
I would never
sell you out, never.
I was planning to do
jail time to protect you,
two years.
Now the D.A. won't offer me
less than five.
Well, I'm sorry, but I wasn't
prepared to go to jail, okay?
I got two teenage boys
who need their father.
You should have
thought about them
before you
altered the barrel
of my service weapon.
I did that to help you!
I never asked you to.
You made that decision
on your own.
You decided to tamper
with evidence.
You're my friend,
and this breaks my heart.
But I've got a family
I've got to look out for.
So do I.
And thanks to you,
I'm not gonna be able to.
****
We broke into
a mountain fortress
for a box
of homemade DVDs?
That's it? That's all
that was in the vault?
What was
recorded on them?
They are a series
of instructions
recorded by Raymond
for Elizabeth
and advice on how
to run his empire
after he died.
A master class on how
to become a criminal.
And to think I signed up
for a mixology class.
Why would Reggie Cole
steal them?
I mean, what good
did they do him?
And where did
he steal them from?
Those are good questions,
and Raymond can't answer
a single one.
Well, you all
did good work
on the mountain.
Mr. Reddington
got what he was after,
and so did we.
What did we get?
Helen Maghi,
our Blacklister.
She's in holding right now.
How?
While you were all
pulling off the heist,
I dispatched a van
with an IMSI-catcher
to intercept
any mobile phone traffic
emanating
from the mountain.
Once the repair call
went out to Maghi,
it was just a matter
of using her cell signal
to track her location.
So when you asked me
to notify you that
we were in the air...
Yeah, that was the signal
to move on the target.
You should have
notified me.
I'm sorry, but I did not
want to put you
in Mr. Reddington's
line of fire, any of you.
It was decision,
and if there's fallout,
I'll take the heat.
****
(RINGTONE PLAYS)
Looks like
the heat's here.
PARK: Put him on speaker.
You don't have to deal
with this by yourself.
Mr. Reddington.
We had an agreement.
We agreed
you wouldn't act on Helen
unless I confirmed
your intel.
It wasn't
exactly an agreement.
It was
more like an order.
Which you disregarded.
Yes, I did.
Where is she?
Two agents from
the Joint Terrorism Task Force
are on their way
to take her into custody.
And I was just on my way
to take her into hiding,
which I promised to do
in exchange for her help.
I don't break my promises.
It's bad for business,
mine and therefore yours.
I'm, uh, sorry,
but it's done.
Harold Cooper knows
when to compromise,
and he knows
it isn't immoral
because he accepts
moral relativism.
Clearly you do not,
which is a problem
because I can't work with you
until you do.
Then remove me as head
of the task force, please.
I am aging
in dog years here.
But I urge to use
whatever you learned
on Mount Bastion
to help us find
Elizabeth's killer
and prevent Mr. Cooper
from going to prison.
Helen first.
Helen is going
to prison, which,
I am sorry,
isn't about moral relativism.
It is about doing
what's right.
Clearly you do not see that,
which is also a problem
because I can't work
with you until you do...
Sir.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
****
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
You don't have to knock.
Took a lot of, uh,
balls to do what
you did yesterday.
For which I assume
we will all pay
a painfully stiff price.
You gave him
what he wanted,
but without compromising
your principles.
Thanks for the pep talk.
You're welcome,
but that's not
why I came up.
The, uh, agents from JTTF
are here to transfer Maghi
over to Central Detention.
****
Yes.
Agent Mojtabai.
You're here
for the prisoner?
We are. Agents McCoy
and McConaughey, JTTF.
DEMBE: I've reviewed
their paperwork.
Everything's in order.
Park's bringing out Maghi.
RESSLER: Just
a little heads up
on the transfer, fellas...
We have it on good authority
that Raymond Reddington
wants to spring Maghi loose.
The Raymond Reddington?
Thanks for the tip.
She's all yours.
Well, well, well.
After all these years.
You got a lot
to answer for.
Can't wait for our chat.
You'll chat
with my lawyer.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
I trust
everything is in order?
Very good.
(DOOR OPENS)
I'll meet you in a half-hour.
I got the information
you wanted about
your lady friend.
I don't know if we need
to worry about that
anymore, Weecha.
Too late.
I already got
to the bottom of it.
Oh, my.
And whom exactly did you
get to the bottom of?
This is Mehmet.
He received the cargo
from the shipping
container job
Helen engineered.
Well, hello, Mehmet.
So you know what was stolen
and where it went?
Tell me.
Agent Aronson.
How can I help you?
Helen Maghi's a big fish,
and we all reeled
her in together.
I didn't want
to miss this.
These gentlemen are
with the Joint Terrorism
Task Force.
They'll be taking Maghi
into custody.
The JTTF
was already here.
They took Maghi
half an hour ago.
Agents McCoy
and McConaughey.
We are Agents McCoy
He didn't.
He couldn't.
He did.
****
Raymond?
What's going on?
Who are these men?
Imposters.
My imposters,
to be precise.
I told you, Helen,
you had nothing to worry
about from the FBI.
Please, sit.
****
I just had a very interesting
conversation with a young man.
I believe you know him.
Mehmet?
Well, he knows you
anyway.
He says
you sold him six crates
of heavy artillery
that you stole
from the Port of Virginia,
which are now on their way
to a group of extremists
in some faraway desert.
I didn't do it for money,
if that's what
you're thinking.
I'm thinking about survival.
My survival depends
on relationships.
I'm gutted
you've poisoned ours.
You lied to me.
Twice.
Why?
My son.
They killed my son.
Beheaded him.
He was an aid worker
in Kazban,
providing food and shelter
for people with none,
but the state heard a rumor
he was a rebel, so...
(VOICE BREAKING)
They cut off his head.
I'm very sorry
to hear that.
I wish you'd shared
this painful story
from the start.
****
We're not going
to Italy, are we?
You've proven
you can't be trusted.
And you know
much too much.
If you were in my shoes,
what would you do?
What would you do
if you were in mine?
If someone butchered
your only child
for no good reason?
I'm willing to bet
that you would stop
at nothing to scorch
the very earth
they walk on.
That may be.
****
But if I were you
and you were me...
I would never,
ever lie to you.
****
Take her to Como,
see to her needs.
****
I need to talk to you,
honey.
Did I do something wrong?
No, I did.
I did something very wrong.
I lied to a police detective.
I thought I was doing it
for a good reason,
to protect my family
from getting hurt,
but I learned something.
I learned there's never
a good reason to tell a lie.
Well, that's okay.
At least you learned, right?
That's what
you always tell me.
Well, the reason
we teach children
when they are children
is because when
you're an adult,
there can be serious
consequences for bad behavior.
And now...
I have to pay for mine.
****
PANABAKER: Really?
In the Senate
parking garage
you send two guys
to "give me a lift"?
You're the fox
in the henhouse,
and I'm the sheepdog,
which is not a good look.
Harold is scheduled for
sentencing this afternoon.
He's pleading to five years
he doesn't deserve.
I'd help him if I could.
If ifs and buts
were candy and nuts,
oh, what a Christmas
we'd have.
You're not
a sheepdog, Cynthia.
You're Santa Claus.
And you're not going
to give Harold coal.
Harold is clenched firmly
in the jaws
of the legal system.
There is no path forward here
but to let it play out.
Now if you don't mind,
I'll just be going.
"Otherwise Illegal Activity."
Excuse me?
A federal agent,
usually undercover,
fills out an application
that, when approved,
authorizes him or her
to bend laws
with almost no judicial
review or oversight,
all to catch a criminal.
Harold was operating
with no such authorization.
But he was
chasing a killer
who murdered Doug Koster
and framed Harold
to gain leverage over him.
How hard could it be
to backdate
one of those fancy forms
to explain his actions?
As a member of the Senate
Judiciary Committee,
I won't participate
in a cover-up.
If Harold had
nothing to hide,
he shouldn't
have hidden.
Agreed, but he did.
Cynthia, to spare
our loved ones from pain
and to get to the truth,
who among us
wouldn't abandon
a few of our
firmest principles,
like rats
from a sinking ship?
I'm sorry you have such
a dark view of humanity,
Raymond,
but not all of us
would compromise
our ethics so willingly.
Is that a fact?
****
(NURSE BINSTOCK
SCREAMS OVER RECORDING)
(GROANING)
REDDINGTON:
You seem ill at ease.
PANABAKER: Yes, well...
There is a line I have
studiously avoided crossing
in my career, until now.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(RECORDER CLICKS)
That terrible sound
came from a woman
you brought to me
two weeks ago
to interrogate
for information.
You recorded that?
She'd harmed
your daughter-in-law,
who was harming
your granddaughter.
I wonder how that
recording would play
for your judiciary committee.
I thought you were
trying to help me.
I did help you.
And now you can help me.
Or Harold, to be precise.
You son of a bitch.
Okay, but then again,
you didn't know my father.
****
It's time.
(SNIFFLES)
It'll be okay.
I'm not gonna let you go.
You don't have to.
I'm never gonna
let go of you.
But you do have
to let me leave.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
I'll see who that is.
You get your things
and then we'll go.
I'm gonna call you
every day, okay?
I am not going
to let you go.
Ever.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Cynthia, what do you want?
Reddington paid me
a visit today.
If it's all
the same to you,
I really don't
want to hear about
Reddington right now.
Oh, I think you're
gonna want to hear this.
(CHELSEA WOLFE'S
IF YOU HAVE GHOSTS PLAYS)
** If you have ghosts...
What are you
doing here?
We were just on
our way to your
sentencing hearing.
Panabaker
got it postponed.
One month.
To allow me time
to finish investigating.
Why did the senator
change her mind?
I don't have the details,
but I know Reddington
got involved.
Does that mean
you're back?
Please tell me
you're back.
I'm back.
ARAM: You're back.
You're back!
Oh, Mr. Cooper!
Mr. Cooper's back.
I could kiss you.
You know what?
I will kiss you.
You don't understand.
The office, the title,
the headaches,
they are all yours.
I tried to make you proud.
I stood up
to Mr. Reddington.
I showed the courage
of my convictions.
And then he sent
two fake JTTF agents
who trampled all over them.
My convictions and me.
I'm sorry
to disappoint you,
but I'm back
only as an agent.
Unless and until we can
figure out who set me up,
you're still the boss.
Uh, okay, but, uh, you can
just tell me what to do,
and I'll pretend
to boss you
into doing it.
Now I just need
to show results.
Don't worry. This time
you won't be working alone.
We're gonna find
your blackmailer,
all of us.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
****
** If you have ghosts...
There is no more
peaceful sound than
the quiet of a home
with a family tucked safely
under the covers
and fast asleep.
I envy you, Harold.
I'm not sure how safe anyone
is with you in the house.
Nonsense.
I'm a guardian angel
and an angel of death,
all rolled into one
fiercely protective package.
Thank you, for the look
I saw on Agnes' face
when I told her.
Now we have a month
to figure this out.
****
I came here tonight
to tell you that from now on,
I won't be working with
the rest of the task force
on this case or any other.
Aram.
He leaves me no choice.
I don't trust him.
That's ironic,
because you won't find
a more trustworthy soul
on this planet.
Then he has you fooled,
Harold.
Because he deceived me.
The sort of deceit
that gets people killed.
Was it?
Or did he give you a taste
of what you give us
and you didn't like it...
Any more than we do?
I have to operate
the way I do.
I give, but I get.
And nine times out of 10,
my get is the very thing
that enables me
to give you what you need.
And as I explained
to Aram today,
that's why we need
to trust you,
even when you're not
forthcoming with us.
For our team to work,
one side needs to
adhere to rules,
be held accountable.
That's our role
as FBI agents.
I forgot that myself,
nearly went to jail for it.
Don't be too hard
on yourself.
I won't if you won't be
too hard on Aram.
Give him another chance.
He's new to the job,
he'll learn.
He's also my boss,
so I have to back him.
We'll see.
I'll consider your words.
Well, when you're done
considering,
turn off the light,
lock the door behind you.
** If you have ghosts...
Good night, Raymond.
Good night, Harold.
** You have everything
** If you have ghosts
** You have everything **
****