We should've just
stayed at that cute
little B&B in town.
It had great
reviews online.
And beds.
With mattresses.
Where would
the fun be in that?
Where's the fun in this?
It's creepy out here.
We're in the middle
of nowhere.
Come on.
This was my family's spot
when I was little.
Where they terrorized you
with campfire stories
about
the Whispering Woman.
(CHUCKLES) Yes.
She haunted my childhood,
it's true.
Lucky for you,
I'm no longer little.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
What was that?
How should I know?
A squirrel, maybe?
Or it's
the Whispering Woman.
Mm, funny.
(CHUCKLES)
(BRANCHES SNAP)
That was bigger
than a squirrel.
I think it's gone.
Could you just check?
(SCOFFS)
Please?
(GASPS DRAMATICALLY)
Oh!
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
(BOTH SCREAM)
****
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
That was Tadashi.
He finished his dive
into Vandyke's laptop,
as you requested.
Did he discover
any pearls,
like who hired Vandyke
to assassinate Elizabeth?
No.
Well, did he
at least confirm
that Vandyke
was, in fact, tracking her
on the night of her death?
Yes.
Vandyke was using an app
to monitor her location,
but that is not all
there is to it.
I feel a twist coming.
According to the app,
Tadashi believes
the RF device
inside Elizabeth
was designed to perform
two functions.
It transmits
GPS coordinates,
and it monitors
timed medication.
I read
the toxicology report.
It found nothing unusual
in Elizabeth's system.
She wasn't drugged.
Maybe whoever
slipped her the tracker
didn't require full use
of its medical abilities.
But as a medical device,
it was small enough
for her to ingest.
We're talking to
the wrong people.
We don't need tech experts.
We need medical ones.
We need to talk to Herbie.
I already sent a courier
to his home this morning
with the tracker,
but he's not responding
to my calls.
Are you two in some sort
of a disagreement?
A disagreement with Herbie?
The man likes conflict
as much as I like
an overcooked egg.
And it's not like him
to not answer.
Try him again.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Senator, come in.
Please, call me Cynthia.
Cynthia, I'm afraid
we're not fully equipped
for social calls here,
but I couldn't refuse
your request to meet.
Would you like
a cup of coffee?
Well, this is difficult
enough, Raymond.
Let's just cut to the gristle.
I need your help.
I suspected you might.
You know I'd only come to you
if my situation
were desperate.
It's been three weeks
since my daughter-in-law
went missing.
Yes, I've been
following the news.
I'm terribly sorry.
The news you don't know,
because I'm keeping it
from the press,
is that Sheila resurfaced
last night at a campsite.
No help from
the local authorities,
mind you.
She was half dead.
Emaciated, tortured.
Now Sheila is in
a medically-induced coma
while whoever did this
to her is still...
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Is still out there,
living and breathing,
enjoying the sun
on their face
while Sheila's
lying in a coma,
and you're feeling helpless.
When nothing
makes sense
in the light,
we have to search
in the dark.
(SIGHS)
I had a feeling
you'd understand.
COOPER: Police interviewed
the two campers
who Sheila Panabaker found,
but she collapsed
without saying a word.
So no idea
where she came from.
The woods
where she surfaced
are 12,000 acres
of rural, mostly
unincorporated area.
It's a lot of ground
to cover.
Sheila's currently in a coma
at Chesapeake Bay Memorial,
fighting for her life.
I have sympathy
for Panabaker,
but does
an abduction case
in which
the abduction is over
merit this task force's
attention?
It does for me.
I'm surprised the FBI
isn't already on it,
given Senator Panabaker's
position.
She asked for us.
RESSLER: I think
you mean Reddington.
Where is he anyway?
He has a lead
on the tracking device
they found on Elizabeth,
but he assured me that
he will be available
for whatever we need.
Look, Cynthia's gone to bat
for this task force
time and time again.
We owe her this.
Ressler, Aram,
go to the hospital,
talk to Sheila's doctor.
Uh, does it, uh,
have to be me?
I mean, I... I... I...
I kind of have
things to do.
What things?
Oh, uh, you know, just, like,
uh, computer things.
It's all...
It's all technical.
It's boring stuff.
Of course.
Park, go with Ressler.
If we can find out
from Sheila's doctor
what was done to her,
it might help us
figure out who did it.
I still don't understand
how Sheila got out.
Well, maybe it's because
we have too many patients
and I'm spread too thin.
What if she leads
the police to us?
She won't.
She left at night.
That had to have been
disorienting.
She walked for days
and wound up
50 miles from here.
I'm not concerned
about her.
But we now
have an empty bed
that we need to fill,
and lucky for us,
I think I found
a new prospect.
I just said I can
barely handle this.
It's not the right time
to bring in someone new.
You know how important
our mission is.
We can always handle
one more patient.
We always make it work.
DOCTOR: Well, she was
hypothermic when she came in.
She's dehydrated,
malnourished.
I suppose being
lost in the woods
for days in the cold
with no food or water
would do that.
A lot of it,
but not the heart damage.
She has heart damage?
Yeah, it's enlarged,
with a reduced
left ventricular function.
But when
I examined her further,
things got...stranger.
At first I thought these
were just knife wounds,
torture, maybe,
but when
we cleaned away
the blood,
we found this.
Are those names?
Yeah, that'd be my guess.
And they appear
self-inflicted.
Why would she carve names
into her own leg?
(MONITOR BEEPING)
Mom?
Remember what
we talked about.
She can't hear you
right now.
She's really sick, Char.
Y-You'll have to excuse us.
This is the first time
she's seen her since...
No, please.
We were just heading out.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
WOMAN: (OVER P.A.)
Perinatologist to ER, stat.
Let's go
find the bastard
who did this.
(SIZZLING)
MAN: (ON TV) For just
a little bit, all right?
Try to swish it around.
Just one thin layer.
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Honey, do you want mustard
or mayo on your sandwich?
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(MAN ON TV
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Sarah?
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
(SILVERWARE CLATTERS)
Bill! She's seizing!
(VEHICLE DOOR OPENS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(TIRES SCREECH LIGHTLY)
We spoke with her doctor,
and it seems
your daughter-in-law
carved the names
of two women
into her own thigh.
(SIGHS)
Sheila did that?
For God's sake, why?
This is conjecture,
but we believe
she knew she might die
and wanted to send
a message to whoever
found her body,
to let them know
there are other victims
still out there.
ARAM: And the message worked.
We ID'd the names.
Uh, Crystal Flowers
and Maria Holmes.
Now, while both names
are incredibly common,
I was able to
narrow down the search
because of a peculiar
connection to Sheila.
I know those women.
Where do I know them from?
Aram discovered
the connection
when he conducted
a social media search
and saw all three mothers
were featured
on the Tiny Fighters
Foundation website.
Oh, believe me, I remember
the interview. I was there.
It's a fundraising
organization.
They share the stories
of children and their families
facing serious health issues.
I've donated a lot
to Tiny Fighters.
How has no one
made the connection
that these mothers were
going missing until now?
Well, over
600,000 people
go missing in
the U.S. every year,
and these cases
are spread out
over several years,
in different parts
of the country,
and under different
circumstances.
We're bringing in the woman
who runs Tiny Fighters.
Emily Wright.
We'll see if she has
something to offer.
Okay.
Thank you
for the briefing.
And thank you
for your work.
You know the new prospect
that I told you about?
I've been studying
her medical records
that you obtained.
She's got a long
and complicated history
that I think
is a perfect match
for our hospital.
So I'm gonna make
my move tonight.
By morning, we will
have a new patient.
See to it
that her bed is ready.
Yes, ma'am.
EMILY: I don't understand.
Who would want
to hurt mothers,
especially our mothers?
They're the most loving,
selfless people
I've ever known.
Who in your organization
has access to the database
of your families?
We have hundreds
of volunteer contributors.
They all have access
to the database.
I can get you a log
of their names and e-mails.
What were the dates that
the kids of these mothers
were profiled
on the site?
(BREATHES SHARPLY)
(KEYS CLACKING)
October 3, 2020,
Crystal's son.
February 10th
of last year,
Maria's son.
And January 25th
of this year,
Sheila's daughter.
Why?
(PAPER RUSTLES)
All the women
were abducted
within a week
of their children's
profile.
Somebody's trolling
your website for victims.
This can't be happening.
Who did you profile
this week?
Don't you think
this is a bit extreme?
He's not answering
our calls.
You don't just go silent.
Not on me.
Or I'm gonna find out
the reason why.
Herbie?
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
Herbie!
We saw your Vanagon
in the garage, Herbie.
I know you're there.
(BABY CRYING)
It's been 36 hours.
Give me a second.
(CHAIN LOCKS CLINKING)
(CRYING CONTINUES)
My wife's is on
a digital detox retreat,
and I can't
get ahold of her.
I can't do this, man.
I'm not meant to be a father.
I think I'm actually
losing my mind, seriously.
My baby hates me.
Like, ac...
She actually hates me.
No, no, no, no, no.
What's her name?
Sue.
As in A Boy Named...
My wife's a Johnny Cash fan.
Never mind.
Oh, come here, Sue.
Come here, Sue.
All right.
Yes. Come here. Yes.
There you go. Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
(CRYING STOPS)
They're pretty reliable.
Only a few things
cause them strife.
Hunger. Fatigue.
Gas.
(CHUCKLES)
All they need
is close attention
and love.
And it's wonderful to
be able to instantly
give them
everything they want.
Hm.
(SUE BURPS)
Yeah.
(WHISPERING)
Cherish this time.
The simplicity.
Because it gets pretty
complicated, I'm afraid.
Yeah.
(SUE FUSSES)
No, it's okay.
It's okay.
No, no, no, no.
Yeah.
Oh, my gosh.
She senses your fear.
Dear God, Herbie,
you must relax.
Here.
(CHUCKLING) Yeah.
(TO THE TUNE OF
IT HAD TO BE YOU)
** It had to be Sue...
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
** It had to be Sue
** I wandered around
and finally found
** The somebody who...
(SIGHS)
** Could make me
be true **
Can you please stay
for a while?
I'm desperate.
(SIGHS)
That depends on what you can
tell me about my tracker.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
We reached out
to the four mothers
whose children
were just profiled,
and we got ahold
of three.
They're aware of
the circumstances
and are looking out
for anything, or anyone,
unusual.
What about the fourth?
ARAM: Mary Sutton.
We weren't able
to reach her,
but I tracked down
her husband,
who said Mary
and their daughter Sarah
are at George Washington
Children's Hospital today.
Sarah had a seizure.
Ressler, Dembe,
head over to the hospital.
Confirm that Mary's safe
and brief her
on the situation.
Your daughter
is a lovely girl,
and I know it's no fun
being in the hospital,
but I'd like to keep
her for a few days
for observation.
Usually, we only
stay the night
when she has
one of her seizures.
Well, the sodium levels
in her blood are
unusually high.
I'd like to
get her on an IV
to rebalance
that concentration.
Has she been vomiting
or having diarrhea?
She could be dehydrated
or suffering from
hypernatremia.
She's on a very strict
diet regimen.
It wouldn't account
for any of that.
Plus, I care for her
day in and day out.
I know her better
than anybody.
Maybe you want to
rerun the tests?
Mother knows best.
I'll see what I can do.
I'll be back.
Are you the night nurse?
Yeah. I just
wanted to drop off
the wheelchair
for Sarah's release.
I'm assuming she'll be
discharged tomorrow?
I was trying
to tell the doctor that.
Thank you.
(CHUCKLES)
They keep trying to hold her
for days and days.
It's such
an insurance scam.
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
I know the truth.
(GASPS)
(DOOR CREAKS LIGHTLY)
Excuse me.
Agents Ressler
and Zuma. FBI.
We're looking for
Sarah Sutton's room.
(GASPS)
(GROANING)
(GASPS, GROANS)
What are you doing?
I'm doing you a favor.
Trust me.
Somebody, help!
Please help! Please!
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
The room's gotta be
up here on the right.
The nurse,
she hurt my mom.
And where is she?
She just left
with the wheelchair.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
She was medium-build,
white.
It happened so fast.
Well, she dosed you with
a pretty powerful sedative.
Why? Why me?
DEMBE: We don't know that yet.
Only that you fit a pattern.
Pattern?
What pattern?
My entire life
is devoted
to taking care
of my daughter.
I barely have time
to brush my teeth
in the morning.
We will get
to the bottom of this.
And until then, what?
We just stay here
where someone
just attacked us?
We've assigned an agent
for your protection.
He'll be outside
your room 24/7.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATES)
You're in good hands.
Well, I couldn't
ID the woman
posing as a nurse
because the footage
was too grainy.
What about
the injection gun?
Well, she was wearing
latex gloves,
so no prints to trace,
but I did research
the device,
and it is actually
pretty nifty.
I mean, if it, uh,
wasn't being used
to kidnap young mothers.
Instead of a needle,
compressed air shoots
a thin stream of medication
directly into
underlying tissue layers.
The challenge is,
I can't trace it.
It's not legal and seems to be
a much more powerful version
than what's
on the current market.
That means it's on
the black market.
Call Raymond.
He's connected to the best
underground medical resources
money can buy.
I think it was designed
to administer
and monitor medication.
Some conditions require
drugs to be taken
on very strict schedules,
exact dosages,
and patients
with those disorders
aren't always
the most reliable
in taking their meds.
How does it work?
Uh, it has a capsule.
If I'm right, it's pre-loaded
with the patient's medication,
at least one dose,
then sends wireless data
to the patient's doctor
or guardian
to track if the meds
were actually taken
and the patient's
whereabouts.
Well, who uses
this technology?
Uh, as far as I know,
no one yet.
It's a cutting-edge
technology. I...
I did hear about
a medical clinic in Boston
that was considering
a pilot program.
I need the name
of that clinic.
Okay.
(KEYS CLACKING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Harold.
I'm texting you a photo.
The woman who abducted
Panabaker's daughter
dropped a medical device
when she went after
her latest victim.
The problem is,
it's not legal,
and we have
no way to track it.
I think with
a little hard work
and elbow grease,
I can find someone who can
take care of that for us.
I'll be in touch.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
I hate to pile on,
but something else
has come up.
Do you think you can help me
to identify and trace that?
If you keep her happy,
there is literally nothing
I won't do for you.
(CHUCKLES)
MARIA: Oh, my! Oh!
EVA: Oh, you poor,
poor thing.
That...
That pain must be unbearable.
Please, let me go.
Please.
NURSE BINSTOCK: We can't
take on another patient.
Not after
what just happened
at the hospital.
No one got
a good look at me.
I was careful.
You're not careful.
You're out of control.
We need to
slow things down.
Would Chelsea want us
to slow things down?
You always
have to bring her up.
Yes, I do.
Because she is why
we do what we do.
(SIGHS)
(GASPING)
Yeah.
The infection has spread.
Why are you
doing this to me?
No. Shh, shh, shh, shh.
It is because...
Because you're
an incredible mother
who would do anything to
eliminate her son's pain.
That's... That's what
you told Tiny Fighters,
and now we are
giving you a chance
to make good
on your word.
Your boy's getting better
because you're taking
his sickness into your body.
We need to do
something to stop this
from spreading further,
or she's gonna
lose the leg.
Take me to a hospital.
A real one!
No. We can handle
everything right here.
Do we know
who his sponsor is?
Wait. What're you
talking about?
M-My sponsor?
It's Narcotics Anonymous
for a reason.
PARK: What? No. No.
We're just trying to remember
who sponsors...
LeBron James.
Yeah. Uh, I saw him in,
uh, some new kicks
at a game the other night.
Trying to...
Track down a pair.
Some kicks, yeah?
Now, what game was that?
'Cause I don't think I saw it.
COOPER: Reddington
just called back.
His contact ID'd
the manufacturer
of the drug injector.
Apparently, a set of them
were delivered
to a rural address
in West Virginia,
along with secondhand
medical beds and equipment.
I need a team there, fast.
Should we announce?
No. This place
looks deserted.
If there's
someone here,
we don't want
to tip them off.
Do you think Reddington
got the wrong address?
(DOOR CREAKS)
(WHISPERS) Dembe.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Help me. Help me.
(CRYING) Help me! Ohh!
(GROANING)
Ressler!
(GRUNTS)
Drop it.
No!
(SCALPEL CLATTERS)
Ugh!
So, that's the woman
who's responsible for this?
One of them.
She didn't act alone.
There's another
woman out there.
The one who tried
to abduct Mary Sutton
from the hospital.
How are the other
victims doing?
They're all in serious
condition, one critical.
We also found, uh,
remains on the property.
The victims we've ID'd
all have the same profile,
all were abducted while
caring for very sick children,
just like Sheila.
What we didn't know
until now is that,
while they were being held,
they were inflicted with
various medical treatments
to make them
mirror the symptoms
of their sick children.
Which explains why
your daughter-in-law
and granddaughter
both presented signs
of cardiomyopathy.
Why?
Why make these women
relive that terror?
Why inflict on them
the pain they witnessed?
I don't have
a conclusive answer...yet.
But there's light
at the end of the tunnel.
As soon as they're released
from the hospital,
they'll be reunited
with their children.
(DOOR OPENS)
I just hope Sheila gets
that same opportunity
with Charlotte.
(DOOR CLOSES)
We're getting
nowhere with her.
We've had her
in that box for hours.
Now she's asking
for an attorney.
No! Absolutely not.
This is our one chance
with this woman.
Cynthia, we can't
deny her counsel.
(SIGHS)
Then perhaps
we're not the ones
who should be
questioning her.
(NURSE BINSTOCK SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
No, no!
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
You seem ill at ease.
(SCREAMING)
Yes, well...
There is a line
I have studiously
avoided crossing
in my career,
until now.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
I find myself thinking
more and more
about that line lately.
You're looking for someone
who has hurt those
dearest to you,
and the prism through which
you see the world
has completely changed.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
And maybe that line
doesn't exist anymore.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Have you made
any progress
tracking down
Agent Keen's killer?
Actually, yes.
I have a lead.
But you're here with me.
(CHUCKLING) Well,
it's not out of
selflessness.
I'm taking
a reflective pause.
I'm considering the extent
of what I might do
to get to the truth.
Yes, well,
I know what you mean.
Look where devotion
has brought both of us.
My daughter-in-law.
Your Elizabeth.
If you're willing
to go this far,
imagine how far
someone like me
is willing to go.
(DOOR OPENS)
I got what you
needed, boss.
Lucy and Ethel
never fail me.
But, uh,
she's not gonna like
what I got to say.
I promise you,
there is nothing
that can make this
situation worse.
Just rip the bandage off,
Teddy.
Your daughter-in-law?
Sheila, right?
She ain't the victim.
What are you
talking about?
She's been slipping
your granddaughter
a nasty concoction
for years,
making the little girl sick
and keeping her that way.
Munchausen.
That's what
they call it.
That is the most absurd thing
I've ever heard.
I told you
she wasn't gonna like
what I had to say.
(RATS SQUEAKING)
That's a lie.
Sheila would never
hurt her child.
Charlotte
is her entire life.
I want to talk
to that nurse myself.
Wait, Cynthia.
Hold on. Please.
Let's talk.
I want the truth.
And you may very well have it,
I promise you.
What do you
actually know
about your
granddaughter's illness?
It was
a very complicated
diagnosis.
Why am I even
answering that?
This is ridiculous.
Charlotte is sick.
Senator, I urge you to think
with your head right now
and not with your heart.
Has there never been
a moment of doubt?
A red flag?
A few months ago,
I wanted Charlotte
to see a cardiologist
at Walter Reed.
It takes months to
get an appointment.
I was able to use my position
to get on his books.
My son was thrilled,
but Sheila insisted
that a care plan
was already in place.
I pushed and pushed.
Finally, she agreed.
The day of the appointment,
they never showed.
Charlotte was having
so many issues,
and Sheila
seemed so stressed.
I didn't think...
That was one incident.
That can't possibly mean...
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
(SIGHS) It's a text
from my son.
Sheila's off the respirator.
What should I do?
Stay calm.
Obtain the facts you need.
Your greatest resource
is right through that door.
ARAM: Mr. Reddington called,
and it turns out we have
this whole thing backwards.
What does that mean?
They got that nurse,
Binstock, to talk,
and, uh, she insists
she was never
in the business
of hurting
innocent mothers,
because those mothers
were never innocent.
So what
is she guilty of?
Their children
weren't really sick.
The mothers
were making them sick.
Binstock says
she was hurting
the mothers
as punishment
for what they did
to their own kids,
and the longer
she kept them,
the healthier
their children became.
I've read about it.
Munchausen's.
Yeah, well, it's actually
Munchausen's by Proxy,
to be exact.
It's a mental illness
and a form of child abuse.
Sir? Can you...
Can you please help me?
My daughter,
she's had an accident,
and I need some towels.
What for?
Did you page the nurse?
I-I... It's not working.
What are you doing?
There's nothing...
Can you just please
get us a few towels?
Mom!
Please, please, sir?
Okay, okay.
Just give me a minute.
Thank you.
Mom...
The darkness in this world
still manages to surprise me.
Let me remind everyone,
this nurse
is still a murderer.
She came at Dembe and I
with a scalpel.
So, can we trust
anything she says?
No. We can't.
But children's lives
may be at risk,
so we need to act fast.
Park, look into
medical records
of the children
of the abductees.
Aram, reach out
to the agents
with the mothers
being examined.
Have them stall reunification
with their children.
And, Dembe, Ressler,
go to the hospital
and separate Mary Sutton
from her daughter
until we learn more.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
This is Agent Herndon.
We have reason to believe
Mary Sutton
may be a danger
to her daughter.
Can you verify
their whereabouts?
I can't.
What do you mean?
They're gone.
I don't believe it.
I don't believe any of it.
Well, we don't need you
to believe, Mr. Sutton,
but we do need your help.
Your wife slipped
FBI protective custody
30 minutes ago.
(SIGHS)
She fled the hospital
with your daughter.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
You weren't there.
All the nights Mary
sat up with Sarah,
all the dirty sheets,
all the midnight trips
to the emergency room.
When was the last time
you spoke to your wife?
Earlier today. She said she'd
call when I'd get off work.
How long ago was that?
(SIGHS)
Hour and a half.
It doesn't mean anything.
Do you have
another residence?
Somewhere your wife might
have taken your daughter?
Another residence?
With our medical bills?
I had to find a second job
just to get us by.
I-I take care of the money.
Mary takes...
(SIGHS)
Mary is the most
selfless mother
in the world.
She is.
RESSLER: Don't beat
yourself up too much.
Based on what
we're learning,
your wife's been deceiving
an entire medical community,
teachers, friends,
foundations.
Do you mind
if we borrow this?
Take whatever you want.
Just bring
my daughter home.
And my wife.
I know there's
an explanation.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Ooh! Look at this place!
What are we doing here?
Well, I thought
maybe we'd get
some of those cinnamon rolls
you love so much from here.
But we're not
at the hospital.
That doctor said I need
to finish my infusion or...
That doctor's an idiot.
(PILL BOTTLES
CLATTERING LIGHTLY)
You're acting weird.
Why haven't you
called Dad yet?
He'll worry.
Oh, you lay back.
I brought some
of your medication
from home.
It'll help you rest.
Then you'll call Dad?
Of course I will.
There we go.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
MAN: (OVER P.A.)
Dr. Patterson, Code 9340.
Mom.
Can you believe it?
It's a miracle.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
You okay?
(SIGHS)
I'm just...overwhelmed.
I know.
I feel the same way.
Bill Sutton has no idea
where his wife
and daughter are.
Where are we
on medical records?
We don't have them yet.
We're waiting on
DOJ authorization.
Uh, maybe we don't
have to wait.
This is all evidence collected
from that abandoned hospital
where Ressler and Dembe
apprehended
their nurse friend
with the scalpel.
Turns out Binstock
and our Blacklister
kept almost immaculate
records
of the families
they surveilled.
All of the children here
have confusing and extensive
medical records,
a clear indication
of Munchausen's by Proxy.
I can't keep track of
the bad guy here anymore.
We're trying to find
an assailant
who's harming Mary Sutton,
but Mary Sutton
is doing irreparable harm
to her own daughter.
Who am I
slapping the cuffs on?
How about we slap the cuffs
on everyone
until that little girl
is safe?
Ask questions later.
Fact is, we're dealing
with two criminals...
Mary Sutton and the woman
who tried to abduct her.
ARAM: Well, I did
some digging on Binstock.
She worked as
a home healthcare nurse
for a young girl
named Chelsea Mason,
who had a rare GI disorder.
After Chelsea died,
Binstock left
the nursing field,
and Eva Mason,
Chelsea's older sister,
received a fortune
in settlements,
all from hospitals
that performed
needless procedures
that only worsened
Chelsea's condition.
Turns out, Chelsea
wasn't really sick.
Her mother was poisoning her.
COOPER: So, we think
this sister, Eva,
has a personal vendetta
against mothers
who hurt their children
and that she's
the co-conspirator
who tried to abduct
Mary Sutton?
Binstock and Eva
do share a past.
PARK: How do they
ID the mothers?
Well, Eva volunteers for
the Tiny Fighters Foundation,
where she films interviews,
looking for signs
of Munchausen's.
If a mother fits the profile,
then Binstock,
who works part-time as
an insurance claims adjustor,
confirms she's correct
via medical records
that don't add up.
How do we find Eva Mason?
If she's out there,
she's after the Suttons.
Well, I did run
a search and got a hit
on her credit card
being used in Delaware
a few hours ago,
but she could be
anywhere by now.
If she's a videographer
for Tiny Fighters,
I might know
where they are.
I was just
watching this.
(DISC DRIVE WHIRS, CLICKS)
(KEYS CLACKING)
EVA: What do you do to cope
when things get hard?
Gosh, I don't know.
Oh, so many things.
Um, Disney.
And Sarah has
a group of friends
who did a dance-a-thon
fundraiser.
And we really like our
mother/daughter spa trips.
EVA: Oh. Where do you go?
Oh, we go to a place
in Delaware
called
Primrose Grand Hotel.
SARAH: That was
the best girls'...
You said Eva Mason's
in Delaware?
MARY: Oh!
That can't be
a coincidence.
Verify the Suttons
are at that hotel
and get there
before Eva does.
Honey,
I'm gonna get some ice.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
****
(SNIFFLES)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
What are you
doing here?
S-Sweetheart...
Where's my mom?
You need
medical attention.
How would you know?
You're not a doctor.
Oh, no. I'm...
I'm more than a doctor.
I am a miracle worker.
And I am
going to cure you.
Hey! Get away
from my daughter!
It's you.
You tried to attack me!
And I did that
to protect your daughter,
and I failed,
but I won't fail twice.
Oh, this is
s-so much quicker
than you deserve,
but I will use it on you.
Unless...
Unless what?
I call an ambulance.
Sarah goes to the hospital
for treatment.
You come with me.
She doesn't need a hospital.
She needs her mother.
Stop it! Both of you!
Sarah!
Just... No, don't.
Before you do anything,
let me explain, sweetheart.
Sarah! Put that gun down!
Okay, sweetheart, just
listen to me, all right?
FBI! Lower your weapons!
Sarah!
What... What's going on?
All right, put your guns down.
This woman is crazy!
She tried to attack me!
Sarah, your mom
is the one making you sick.
She gives you, what, pills?
How do you feel when
you take them, honey?
You're lying.
MARY: Sarah,
listen to me.
Look at me.
This woman is insane.
I would never try to hurt you.
I love you
more than anyone.
Is my mom making me sick?
Please, put the weapons down.
Nobody needs to get hurt.
This woman
is a child abuser.
DEMBE: And she will
be punished for that.
(SCOFFS) L-Like my mother was?
We know
about your sister.
No, you don't know.
You did not watch my mother
drain the life out of her,
confine her to one room.
(VOICE BREAKING)
Her only friends were dolls.
I knew what she was doing,
and nobody listened to me.
The system is failing
these children!
And they do not
have time to waste!
Their lives are at stake!
Aah!
Sorry!
Sarah!
RESSLER: Don't move.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'm sorry.
I-I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Stay there.
Do not move.
I'm sorry.
Sarah, are you okay?
Get back. Get back.
She's my daughter!
Back!
What is wrong with you?
This is my daughter!
(SHOUTING FADES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Senator Panabaker.
PANABAKER: I-I'm calling
to thank you.
I asked you to help me
find the truth.
You did exactly that.
How is your family
handling things?
My son is devastated.
Took my granddaughter out
for the afternoon.
I didn't want her to be there
when the arrest happens.
She's been through
so much already.
Children have a way
of surprising you.
They're so resilient.
And now she has a chance
at a healthy life.
You gave her that.
Not her parents,
not the FBI,
you, Cynthia.
I am so glad to be
getting out of here.
(SIGHS)
Sheila Panabaker?
Yes?
You're under arrest.
What?
(HANDCUFFS CLICK)
What are you doing?
Stop. Marshall.
Marshall.
Stop it.
Get your hands
off of me!
PANABAKER:
Bottoms up,
little lady.
(SLURPS)
Mmm. Mmm!
Doesn't that
just hit the spot?
You know, I used to bring
your daddy to this very cafe
when he was little
after his hockey practice.
Little, but so fast.
Mom doesn't let me
have sweets.
Because I get so sick.
Charlotte Anne Panabaker,
this hot chocolate
will not make you sick.
That is a guarantee
from Grandma.
(LAUGHS)
That's my girl.
(CHUCKLES)
****
(CLEARS THROAT)
(SIGHS LIGHTLY)
Dr. Jansen?
Of the psychiatry
clinic here?
Yes?
Uh, do we know each other?
No.
(VEHICLE DOOR CLOSES)
But we need a moment
of your time, please.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
Dr. Jansen.
Please, don't hurt me.
I have two kids.
Doctor, I have nothing
but respect
for professionals
who treat mental illness.
It's a neglected epidemic,
and you're doing
exemplary work,
but I don't have time
to be polite.
So, please, tell me what
you know about this device.
Where did this come from?
You tell me,
and we'll both know.
I'm... I'm not
wildly familiar with it,
but it looks to be a prototype
of something I saw last year.
We were going to initiate
a pilot program
with some of
my mood disorder patients.
It, uh, monitors
medication use,
but patient advocacy groups
were worried about privacy,
so the whole thing
just kind of fell apart.
Who developed
the device?
It's a tragic story, actually.
A lot of those
going around.
A young man came to my office
begging to be seen.
His wife suffered from
an acute
psychiatric condition.
I-I-I-I don't
recall which,
but she was
always inconsistent
about her meds.
And then one day, she had
a tragically violent episode
that cost innocent lives.
The man was devastated.
He went back to school,
and he developed
an ingestible tracker
that could monitor
a patient's compliance
so that no one else would
have to live that nightmare.
He pleaded with me
to give the tech a shot.
Like I said, I had every
intention of testing it...
Do you remember
the man's name?
(SIGHS)
It started with a "K,"
I know.
Um... Kennison.
Yes, uh, Andrew Kennison.
(CLEARS THROAT)
You wouldn't have actually
shot me, would you?
If she was
going to shoot you,
she would have
pointed the gun at you.
(SIGHS) Hey.
I got here
as soon as I could.
Is this about the case?
It's not.
Agent Ressler,
did you attend your
NA meeting tonight?
Yeah, of course I did.
I always go...
I'm sorry,
but what's this all about?
I mean...
Does no one trust me?
I mean, first, Aram
doesn't want to go out
in the field with me,
and then you guys are
all talking behind my back
about my sponsor?
I'm doing the meetings.
I'm doing the steps.
I'm clean. (SCOFFS)
I don't need
this intervention crap.
Oh. Well, that's not
what this is.
Oh, no, no. So, what?
I'm crazy now, huh?
Is that it? Great.
So, in case everybody's
lost count,
I just got my two-month chip
yesterday from that sponsor
that you guys definitely
weren't talking about.
Look, I'm trying here.
I'm really trying.
And we couldn't be prouder.
We knew this was
a big milestone for you.
We wanted
your sponsor's name
in case they
wanted to join us.
For what?
Your party.
Ta-da!
Oh, my God.
It, uh, took me a few tries
to, uh, pick up the cake,
but I got there.
Wow. Wow.
Oh, I also made
a killer playlist.
(SNIFFLES)
Oh, God. Not with that
damn playlist again.
DEMBE: He's been
obsessing all week.
I'm really dumb.
Look, I'm sorry.
I, uh...
I know I'm not always
the, uh, feelings guy,
but this really...
Means...
We know what it means.
And you mean
the same thing to us.
Thank you. Truly.
** Ah, invincible...
(SCOFFS)
** When we love...
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
** Ah, invincible...
Do you want
the big slice there?
Sure.
** When we love **
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(LAUGHTER)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
****