(******)
Okay, so, Agents Park and Zuma
are reviewing security footage
from around the site
of the explosion.
Agent Ressler is looking
for anything he can find
on, uh, Reggie Cole
or Lacroix,
but I still need to, uh,
look over the forensics report
from the crime scene.
I sent you my notes
on the report last night.
I'm discussing
the findings with Reddington
later this morning.
Right, sorry, I knew that.
Okay, so, I'll be in
no later than 2:00.
If something comes up
with Mr. Reddington...
...call me.
I will. But don't worry.
Everything's under control.
We'll see you when you get in.
Okay.
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(******)
(CAR HORN HONKS IN DISTANCE)
(MONITORS BEEPING)
(******)
(WEAKLY) Raymond.
(GRUNTING)
Weecha. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Easy, easy,
easy, easy, easy.
(******)
How long have I been down?
Almost four days.
(SIGHS)
Where's Morgan?
I saw him
walking into the room...
Morgan didn't make it.
(******)
I am so sorry.
Weecha,
before the explosion...
(******)
There was the woman.
Was it Kate?
(******)
I don't know.
You should rest.
We're gonna get you home
as soon as we can.
(MONITORS BEEPING)
(******)
How's Weecha?
Tenacious.
I didn't expect her
to last the first night,
let alone three.
Something to drink?
No, thank you.
(GROANS SOFTLY)
What do you have?
Forensics ran the DNA
from the woman
in the apartment
against the sample
you provided for Mr. Kaplan.
The fire caused
by the explosion
degraded the samples
significantly,
but there is an overlap.
As far as the M.E.'s
concerned, it's her.
You're not convinced.
DNA evidence
notwithstanding,
something doesn't add up.
I have a hard time believing
Mr. Kaplan would hire
Reggie Cole
to kill Doug Koster
in order to blackmail me.
I understand why
Kate's involvement
would be difficult
for you to accept, Harold.
We negotiated a stay in your
prosecution on the condition
that you could expose
a broader conspiracy.
If the one person responsible
died in that building...
The only head left to serve
to the Justice Department
is mine.
You stay on Reggie Cole
and his lawyer.
With any luck, you'll find
a connection to Kaplan.
In the meantime, I'm gonna
get a second opinion.
(******)
I've been dealing with anxiety
and OCD and depression
pretty much my whole life.
I've been able to manage with,
um, support and therapy
and medication,
but lately, nothing helps.
I haven't been sleeping.
I can hardly eat,
which is not like me.
I just, um...
I feel like I'm barely
holding it together.
Would you like
to set those down?
Yeah, sorry.
I appreciate
you bringing me in
so early, by the way.
Mr. Homan was
a supporter of some
of my earliest research.
Any friend of his is welcome
anytime they like.
You know, when I, um,
first heard
about psychedelic therapy,
I imagined something
a bit more...
Tie-dye and trance music?
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
We get that a lot.
But the truth is,
Ketamine and other
psychedelic therapies
are revolutionizing care
for people with
treatment-resistant
anxiety and depression.
The treatment we're offering
is experimental,
but it's legal.
Any questions?
(******)
What's your fish's name?
What fish?
(******)
His name is Frank.
That was a joke. (LAUGHS)
Oh.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
(******)
Shall we begin?
Okay.
The medication you will be
receiving today is derived
from psychoactive plants...
Little stick.
Ow.
...and is delivered
alongside an imidazopyridine
class agonist
to induce REM states.
So I'll be dreaming.
In a manner of speaking.
We'll be playing music
to help you relax
throughout the treatment.
Thanks.
But if you see something
that upsets you,
just try to be curious
about it.
(******)
We can always reschedule
if you want more time
to think about it.
No, um...
I'm ready.
Okay.
See you soon.
(******)
(CAR HORN HONKS)
(CONSTRUCTION WORKERS
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Good morning!
Hey.
(******)
(TELEPHONES RINGING)
Oh! Figures!
(SIGHS)
How was your appointment?
Excellent.
Thank you for asking.
Well, at least one of us
is in a good mood.
Some TikToker in a 6 Series
rear-ended me on my way in.
His car was fine,
of course.
If you need a mechanic,
I know a good one.
Fast, cheap, and reliable.
What's the catch?
He used to work
for the Albanian Mafia.
I'll keep him in mind.
You know what I was thinking
on the way over?
We should take a trip,
all of us.
Someone just tried
to blow up Reddington,
so, maybe next week?
(CHUCKLES) Yeah,
obviously for the future.
I just... I think we all
deserve something
to look forward to.
Sounds like fun.
Great.
If anyone needs me, I will be
reviewing these upstairs.
(******)
(WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
IN DISTANCE)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS
IN DISTANCE)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
I know, I know. No knocking.
But Reddington called.
He's on his way in.
Sounds important.
Okay. Um, do you, uh...
Do you know who sent this?
Beats me.
(ALARM BLARING,
PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(******)
What?
What is going on?
Someone tripped the emergency
alarm on sub-section C.
What's wrong with that feed?
PARK: I don't know,
but we have
bigger problems.
(PEOPLE GASPING)
Oh, my God.
We have
small teams moving down
multiple hallways.
Who are they?
Where did they come from?
I don't know,
but they've taken
the elevator entrance.
RESSLER:
Cell reception's down.
We need backup now!
(******)
This is Special Agent
Dembe Zuma.
We are under attack.
I repeat, we are...
Did they hear you?
I don't know.
Look, whoever these guys are,
we need a plan. Now!
Hey, Aram!
There's a phone,
in the storage bay
on sub-section E.
I couldn't integrate it
into our comms system,
because it's connected to
a totally, uh, different...
That doesn't matter.
Okay, if Ressler and I
can get there,
we can call for backup.
What should we do?
Uh, you two stay here.
Everyone, everyone,
take defensive positions!
Let's go.
(******)
Better make this quick.
(LOUIS ARMSTRONG'S
"WHAT A WONDERFUL WORLD"
PLAYING, DISTORTED)
** I see trees of green **
REDDINGTON:
Aram, can you hear me?
Mr. Reddington?
If you want it to stop,
you have to get everyone out.
** I see them bloom
for me and you **
Aram, we've gotta go now!
** And I think to myself **
Mr. Reddington?
Aram!
Okay, okay, okay.
Let's go!
Okay. Okay. Okay.
(******)
PARK: There!
Dembe.
Reloading.
Eleven o'clock!
(******)
Alina!
No, no, no, no, no.
No! No! No! No! No!
I'm sorry.
ARAM: No.
(******)
No. No. Alina.
Oh, my God.
No. God. No!
No! No! No!
Elevator!
(TELEPHONES RINGING)
Figures.
** What a wonderful world
(******)
** Yes, I think to myself
** What a wonderful world
(******)
** Oh, yeah **
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Alina?
You're alive.
So it would seem.
I don't understand.
There...
(******)
There was an attack.
An attack?
It seemed so real.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
If you'll just, um,
excuse me. Just...
I pulled every piece of paper
I could find
on your blackmailer
and his lawyer, Lacroix.
Did you find anything
connecting them to Mr. Kaplan?
No, but I did find
the shell corporations
that Lacroix used
to hide the profits
from their
blackmail operation.
The guy had
seven properties,
a half dozen bank accounts,
even a yacht.
Not exactly the upstanding
lawyer his wife described.
You think she knows more
than she was letting on?
I do.
I called her office.
Her assistant said
she got in 20 minutes ago.
Send me that address,
and I'll meet you there.
And, Donald, thank you.
For everything.
Look, whoever's behind this,
I'm keeping you out of prison.
Whatever it takes.
(PHONE BEEPS)
Ah! (CHUCKLES)
Ernest Glampers.
Glampers, Trout, and Pilgrim
attorneys-at-law.
You have the body
of Ms. Kathryn Nemec,
is that correct?
I'm sorry, sir.
You're not actually...
You see, Ms. Nemec
was a Rosicrucian.
A-A what?
A Rosicrucian.
A member if a small religious
and cultural community
whose laws demand that
the bodies of the deceased
are buried within
24 hours of their deaths.
I'm sorry...
You should be.
This is a copy
of the complaint
which I am prepared to file
with the Superior Court
of the District of Columbia.
It asserts that by denying
Ms. Nemec's family
access to her body,
you and your superiors
have violated
their civil rights.
Now, Ms. Nemec's family
have instructed me
to refrain
from filing the suit,
if you will simply allow me
to perform the rite
of "alure plurot."
You're a "rosarian," too?
By marriage.
So, if you could be
so kind as to show me
to Ms. Nemec's body,
you can get back
to your sandwich,
and we can all avoid
an awful lot
of unpleasantness.
What do you say?
Please, lead the way.
Yeah, hi.
This is, uh, Aram Mojtabai.
I was in the office
earlier today,
and I-I seem to be having
some kind of really,
really intense deja vu,
and I need to speak
to Dr. Idigbe right away.
Hello?
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
I know, I know. No knocking.
Reddington called.
He's on his way in.
Sounds important.
What did you just...
Oh, God.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
(******)
Okay, so, uh, I know
this might sound crazy,
but, um, I think we're
about to be attacked.
Attacked? By who?
I don't know.
That is what I am going
to try to figure here.
I'm sorry.
Aram, what is going on?
(ALARM BLARING)
(PEOPLE GASPING)
How did you know
that would happen?
I've seen it before. At first,
I thought it was a dream
or some kind
of weird deja vu...
We have small teams
moving down multiple hallways.
On the phone, Mr. Reddington
said that to make it stop,
we have to get out
of the Post Office.
When did you talk
to Reddington?
They've taken
the elevator entrance.
ARAM: If I could just
find us a clear path...
Cell reception's down.
We need backup now!
Okay, there, there!
The south-east exit!
(******)
Are you guys seeing this?
This is Special Agent
Dembe Zuma.
We are under attack.
I repeat, we are...
This is a dream.
I'm still in
the doctor's office.
Aram, what is going on?
I don't know.
But there is a clear path to
the south-east exit right now.
So, everyone!
PARK: Aram!
(******)
Okay. I know this
doesn't make any sense, but...
We need to get out
of the Post Office. Now.
Okay.
We trust you.
(******)
We make a left
out of the stairwell.
Then it's 50 yards to the exit
at the end of the hall.
(******)
(MEN GRUNTING)
(RESSLER GROANING)
Aram!
(******)
Thank you.
(RESSLER GRUNTS)
(BEEPING)
It's not working!
That's not possible.
What? I don't...
I don't understand.
I-I wrote the security
protocols myself.
To access those, you'd need
military-grade hacking tools
or...Greylock.
They used your software
to hack the system?
ARAM: I don't know.
I thought you destroyed it.
I did!
(GUNFIRE)
We gotta fall back!
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
We gotta get out.
We don't have a choice!
Let's go!
No! Come on,
we have to get out!
No.
We have to get out!
(PIXIES' "WHERE IS MY MIND?"
PLAYING)
** Ooh
(******)
** With your feet on the air
and your head on the ground
(******)
** Try this trick
and spin it, yeah
** Your head will collapse,
but there's nothing in it
** And you'll ask yourself
** Where is my mind?
** Way out in the water,
see it swimming
(GUNSHOT)
(******)
** I was swimming
in the Caribbean
** Animals were hiding
behind the rocks
** Except the little fish,
bump into me
** Swear he's tryin' to talk
to me, say wait wait
** Where is my mind?
** Way out in the water **
Hey. Hey.
Hey, hey!
(******)
Hey, hey, hey!
(PANTING)
(TELEPHONES RINGING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Figures.
(******)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Excuse me, Mrs. Lacroix.
Donald Ressler, FBI.
I need you
to step out of the car.
(******)
Mrs. Lacroix?
We're gonna need
a crime scene unit.
This is Harold Cooper.
I need a crime scene unit
sent to my location.
(******)
She's still warm.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Don't move. I'm FBI.
Put your gun on the ground.
Slowly.
Whatever you're thinking
about saying, don't.
(******)
Aram, just slow down.
ARAM: Please
just listen to me!
Every time I get off
that elevator,
we have
this same conversation,
and then a few minutes later,
all of you are dead, alright?
This is some kind
of a bad acid trip,
and we're all in it?
Yeah, and I am sorry
about that,
but what matters is that
I heard
Mr. Reddington earlier,
and he told me
to get everyone out.
Look, I know
how this must sound,
but I think to make this stop,
I need to get us
out of the Post Office...
Aram...
Look, I can prove it.
You were in a car accident
earlier this morning, right?
Rear-ended by a guy
in a 6 Series.
How did you...
But it's no big deal,
because Dembe knows a mechanic
who used to run guns for...
The Albanians.
Look, I would love to discuss
the metaphysics of all this,
but any second now,
they are going to come
through sub-section C...
Who's coming through
sub-section C?
I don't know.
There is, like, a guy
in a bear mask
with, like, a bunch
of mercenaries,
and it's like
we're in a maze.
And if I can't find a way
to get us out,
it's gonna
start all over again.
It's... It's a loop.
Aram, just breathe.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I can't watch you all
die again, okay?
Listen, I know
you've been under
a lot of pressure lately.
There's nothing wrong
with taking some time...
ARAM: The sewer.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
I saw workers accessing it
on my way in.
(ALARM BLARING)
(******)
(PEOPLE
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
My God.
There's a mechanical room
in sub-section C
that runs alongside
an old Water and Sewer
service shaft.
We have small teams
moving down multiple hallways.
They've taken
the elevator entrance.
ARAM: They staged in the shaft
and blew through the walls.
All the other exits
are locked down,
so the only way out
is the way they came in.
(******)
I don't understand. I thought
Mr. Kaplan died years ago.
So did I, but the authorities
weren't able
to definitively determine
whether the woman who died
in the explosion
was Kate or not,
so I went to the morgue
to collect a sample
for you to analyze.
I don't want to keep you
from your vacation, Vlad,
but I have to know for sure.
I need eight hours.
Edward will be waiting for you
on my jet
with the engines running.
So, just assuming
you're right, and this is all
a hallucination,
what happens if you die?
Does everything reset?
I don't know,
and honestly,
I'd rather not find out.
MAN: Aah!
How did you...
Duck.
How many times
have you done this?
Enough.
(******)
There. There.
This is how it stops.
Come on. Go.
Go. Go now! Come on.
(******)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Sorry, bear-face.
Not this time.
(******)
(ELEVATOR DOORS CLANK)
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
Figures.
I got everyone out.
(STATIC)
REDDINGTON: (ECHOING)
Can you hear me?
(STATIC)
(SPEAKING IN REVERSE)
(LIGHT FIZZLING, TWINKLING)
(PEOPLE SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(******)
PARK: Figures.
DR. IDIGBE:
The medication you will be
receiving today is derived
from psychoactive plants...
Little stick.
(ECHOING) Wait!
Mommy!
Oh!
** I see trees of green,
red roses, too
Please.
** I see them bloom
(GUNSHOT)
** For me and you
** And I think to myself
(ECHOING) This isn't real.
This isn't real.
** What a wonderful world **
(******)
Who are you?
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh...
(******)
(GASPS) Oh, no.
(GRUNTS)
(******)
I'm you.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
COOPER: Anything?
Nothing. Guy won't say a word.
Maybe he won't have to.
We found confirmation
of a secure payment
for $25,000
on our suspect's phone.
We think it was down payment
for the hit on Mrs. Lacroix.
Any idea
who made the payment?
Not yet, but it came from
a numbered account
which we've traced to
the Hatem Trust Bank
in Lebanon.
The only problem is
Hatem Trust Bank
closed
over three years ago.
How was a payment
made from an account
at a shuttered bank?
We're not sure,
but the payment
was time-stamped
for the morning
of the bombing,
so it's possible
Mr. Kaplan was the one
who made the transfer.
The timing might work,
but the motive doesn't.
Why would Kaplan bother
killing Mrs. Lacroix
when the plan was
to kill herself?
Maybe she has co-conspirators
that she wanted to protect.
COOPER:
The only way to know for sure
is to identify
the owner of that account.
Contact former bank clients
and employees.
We need a name.
REDDINGTON: Okay.
(WEECHA GRUNTS)
Okay.
There you go.
I'm not an invalid.
No, you're not,
but you suffered
a major percussive trauma
and pretty severe burns,
and you need to rest.
I'm tired of rest.
Remember what you told me
on the Brazo Morales
the night we met?
Be quiet.
Go to sleep.
There you go, sweetheart.
You get the sample
to Cvetko?
Yes, I did.
(VEHICLE APPROACHES)
What is it?
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Ah, Mierce.
(DOOR SHUTS)
Oh, I'm so glad you came.
I wasn't sure if...
I came to help
Weecha get better.
That's all.
Okay.
It would be bad enough
if you were the only one
to suffer the consequences
of your decisions.
(******)
But vengeance
is like a virus...
In time, everyone close to you
becomes afflicted.
And still, you won't stop,
will you?
(******)
Mierce...
Then we have nothing
left to discuss.
Excuse me.
(DOOR OPENS, SHUTS)
(******)
(GROANS)
ARAM X: Remember junior prom?
Came back from the bathroom
to find Linda Beckman
making out
with Dominic Angelella.
You should have hit him
in the face.
This isn't happening.
You're not...
Real?
Oh, I think I am.
I'm part of you.
And I've been waiting
a long time for this.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
No point running.
Can't escape yourself.
(******)
I got 'em out...
(IMITATES BUZZER)
Wrong.
Getting everyone
out of the Post Office
was a lie you made up
because you can't
face the truth.
And you want to know
why you believed it?
Because Reddington said so.
Gotta love the comforting
voice of authority
when you're too weak
to trust yourself.
But, hey,
I don't blame you.
I wouldn't
trust you, either.
(******)
Nick was my friend.
I didn't know...
(MOCKING) "I didn't know!"
You know they thought you were
the smart one, right?
(GRUNTS)
Admit it, man.
Deep down,
when it really
matters most,
you'll always be a day late
and dollar short.
I mean, if you weren't,
she'd still be alive.
(GUNSHOT)
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYING)
She was right
in front of you...
(SIGHS)
...and you were too scared
to stop her.
But, hey, at least you managed
to make Agnes Keen an orphan.
(******)
And then there's Samar.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Come on!
(GASPING)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
You know, I don't actually
know what happens
when you die in here.
But the truth is,
I don't really care.
Because in here
or out there,
I'll be waiting.
And it's only a matter of time
before you realize
you need me.
(GASPING)
(******)
You know
the most amazing part
about all this?
I can't do a thing in here
that you don't want me to.
(******)
It would be sad,
if it wasn't so pathetic.
(GUNSHOT)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUD)
God, I thought
he'd never shut up.
(******)
Samar?
(GROANING)
This is just
another hallucination.
Yes, and yet here I am.
You look incredible.
You look like hell.
Yeah.
Well, it's, um,
kind of been a rough day.
Seems like it's been
a rough couple of years.
If I knew all it took
to see you again
was a medical-grade
acid trip...
You've been
living a lie, Aram,
and I couldn't sit back
and watch it any longer.
What lie?
The one you've been
telling yourself
since I went into the water.
The one you repeated
when Liz died
and when Nick
hijacked your code.
The one convincing you
that you'll fail as leader
of the task force.
(GRUNTS)
I don't...
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Yes, you do.
And I need you to see it.
The man in the mask
had your face.
Why?
Why'd you leave?
Aram, please,
we don't have much time.
I would've taken care of you.
Even if you forgot everything.
I just wanted
to be near you.
Why did you make yourself
into a Blacklister, Aram?
Because it's my fault.
All of it.
If I had just
gotten to you sooner,
you'd still be here with me,
instead of wasting away
alone on some island.
It was my choice, Aram.
(CRYING) I was supposed
to protect you, and I failed.
Just like I failed Liz
and I failed Agnes
and I failed Greylock and...
Just like I'm gonna
fail the task force.
That's what he wants you
to believe.
That doesn't make it true.
He wants you to believe
that if you were only stronger
or smarter or more ruthless,
that you could have stopped
everything from happening.
But no one has
that much control.
Not Cooper, not Reddington,
not you.
(******)
It wasn't your fault.
(CRYING)
Samar. Samar.
(******)
For what it's worth,
the savior complex
was more charming
when it wasn't
completely homicidal.
(GASPING TEARFULLY)
Oh, God.
You've always been enough.
It's about time
that you see it.
(******)
(WHIMPERING)
Welcome back, Aram.
Where are you going?
I thought I'd give you
some space.
You can always reach me
on the usual number.
Oh, Raymond.
I don't know
what you want me to say.
You don't need
to say anything.
You warned me that if I
continued down this path,
terrible things would happen.
And they did.
I knew they would.
They always have.
I want so badly
to be angry with you.
I think
you want me to be, too.
But the truth is, I'm not.
I'm just sad.
Yes.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Vlad.
Ah, Vlad.
Am I interrupting?
No.
Mierce, this is
Vladimir Cvetko.
Vlad, this is Weecha's sister,
Mierce.
Mucho gusto.
VLAD: Encantado.
Vlad, you have
a plane waiting.
The woman in the apartment...
Was she Kate or not?
No. After compensating for
the damage caused by the fire,
I found that the samples
were a 50% match.
This means the woman
in the apartment
was not Mr. Kaplan.
It was...
Her sister. Maureen.
(******)
Thank you, Vlad.
Adios.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
Raymond, go.
Do what you will.
(DOOR SHUTS)
So, that's not normal?
It's not uncommon for patients
to encounter feelings of shame
and grief or even experience
radical confrontations
with the self, but...
Murder loops?
Not something
I've heard before.
I'm not sure I'd put it
in the brochure.
How do you feel?
(SIGHS) I don't know.
Um...
It's like I was certain that
it was just a matter of time
before everything
fell apart,
and so I fought as hard
as I could to stop it,
even though
I knew I couldn't.
And now,
for the first time
that I can remember...
...I don't feel like
I have to fight anymore.
I'm glad, Aram.
It's not uncommon to feel like
one has a new lease on life...
But?
This treatment
isn't a cure-all.
Do you understand?
I understand
about as much
as anything that happened
to me today.
So, 50%?
(CHUCKLES)
Good enough.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
That night,
before the explosion...
(******)
...I was wondering
what I would do
if all this
really was Kate's doing.
I remember knowing
with absolute certainty
that Elizabeth would have
wanted me to show her mercy.
I can still hear her voice.
Me, too.
Before the bomb went off,
I thought maybe...
...I just might rise
to the occasion.
At least now we know
Mr. Kaplan wasn't responsible
for Liz's death.
You have something new
on Mrs. Lacroix?
Mystery, really.
The assassin was paid
via wire transfer
from an account
at a Lebanese bank.
The only problem is that,
according to public records,
that bank has been
closed for years.
Trying to figure out
how the payment was made now,
but so far, we haven't been
able to find out
anything about
the account holder...
And you never will.
That account is part
of a financial network
more secure
than any other bank on earth.
That's why
I opened the account
in the first place.
The payment for
Mrs. Lacroix's assassin,
it came from your account?
It did.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Our enemy is closer
than I ever imagined, Harold.
(******)
(TELEPHONES RINGING)
How was your appointment?
Oh, it was...
You weren't in a fender bender
this morning, were you?
No. Why?
No reason.
Uh, look,
before we get started,
I need you to do me a favor.
This is gonna sound strange,
but I need you to
slap me in the face. Hard.
I know that's a weird...
Ow.
Okay.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Thank you.
Happy to help.
Ever since I got back,
I've been wondering why now?
I've been feeling guilty about
Samar, about Liz for years,
and what happened with Nick
and Greylock was awful, but...
Why did I choose that moment
to totally fall off a cliff?
I'm not sure
you chose anything,
but I'm curious
if you have any ideas.
Well I can't be sure,
but I actually think
it's all your fault.
(CHUCKLES)
I mean, with you in charge,
I always had
someone to rely on.
To make the hard calls.
Take the blame
if things went wrong.
I knew I wasn't ready,
but I was hoping
I'd handle it
a little better.
You're handling it fine.
I've been so anxious
and depressed,
I took an experimental
hallucinogen.
You got help.
And I'm proud of you
for that.
This place is a crucible.
Of course
you were overwhelmed.
You remember
you were kidnapped
about a month ago, right?
This job demands
that you recognize
the things you can control
and the things you can't.
You make the best choices
you can,
then you find a way
to forgive yourself
so you can move forward.
That sounds completely
impossible.
I know.
But you'll learn.
And I'll have your back
while you do.
We all will.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)