(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
****
(CHUCKLES) Hey!
Oh, my goodness!
WOMEN: Sam!
SAM: Hey!
Hey, I love you, too!
WOMAN: Sam!
SAM: We'll see you
at the match on Sunday!
Ah, y-you're too kind.
WOMAN: Sam! Sam.
Hey.
What's your relationship
to Razmik Maier?
Sorry. I already
did the presser.
And m-my dad says
you're too old
to win against Grishov.
I hope your pops
didn't bet the house.
Otherwise, you're gonna be
sleeping in a tent!
How are you so sure?
One word, my guy.
Practice.
Are you working
with the doctor?
Do you know who else
he's working with?
SAM: Thank you, everyone!
Sam!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Thank you!
Do you know who else
he's working with?
Sam!
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
****
She knows.
That reporter.
I don't know how she knows,
but she does!
Which means it's only
a matter of time before
everyone else does!
She's persistent,
but unimportant.
What matters is you
and the goals you are
close to accomplishing.
She is a reporter!
She's one reporter.
Everyone else thinks
you're aging like fine wine.
Aging like fine wine
is fine for wine,
but when you're a tennis pro,
people start asking questions.
Let them. You've never
failed a drug test,
and with me,
you never will.
We've talked about this.
You know how uncomfortable
it makes me.
All of it.
Besides, I-I feel good.
I am... I'm winning.
I want you
to keep winning.
Look, my dad is gonna
be here any minute,
so you cannot be here.
I'm sure Ken's happy
you made the finals.
He'll be even happier
when you win.
Come.
We have work to do.
****
(SIGHS)
DR. MAIER: Good.
Now close your eyes.
Visualize the match,
what you need
to do to win.
To be the best there is.
The best
there ever will be.
****
Sammy?
Sammy! It's Dad!
Yo, Sam!
****
Come on, sleepy head.
Up and at 'em.
****
No! Sam!
My boy.
Sam!
****
What's this?
Proof that I'm innocent.
I took a blood test.
The lab misplaced
the results.
I didn't want
to draw attention
by getting another,
so I couldn't confirm it
until now.
You were drugged.
GHB.
Well, that explains
why you can't remember.
The perfect drug
to give someone
you're trying to frame
for the perfect murder.
Yeah. The homicide
detective, Heber,
you show this to him?
I didn't. I can't.
Why not?
You said it yourself,
it proves that
you're innocent.
Remember when you told me
you worked a little magic
on my service weapon
to make it look like
it wasn't used
to kill Doug?
We ran the ballistics.
We know the truth.
But they don't,
and they never will.
We were being watched.
****
Ugh.
Coop, you got
to tell Heber.
Whoever killed Doug knows that
you tampered with evidence,
and I know that he knows
because he called me.
He called you.
What does he want?
I don't know.
But he wants something.
'Cause I've roped you
and Charlene into a cover-up,
he thinks he's
got the leverage
to get me to do it.
Any idea who it is?
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
COOPER: None.
Only way to get us out
of the hole that I've dug
is to find out who he is
and prove what he's done.
Once we do that,
then we go to the cops.
Mmm. Where do we start?
Is everything alright?
Are you expecting a call?
This belonged to the man
who shot Elizabeth.
Why do you have it?
That night, when everything
was falling apart,
I guess muscle memory
or instinct told me
to have a guy get it
from the morgue.
In case there were
loose ends.
I see.
Yes. I know you do.
I see what you're doing.
I'm less clear why.
I now know Dembe
gave Elizabeth that letter
before she died,
but in the past two years
I've never really asked
any questions about
what happened that night.
And now you are.
My young friend Tadashi
will be coming here
in about an hour.
And I want you
to give this to him.
I've asked him to hack into
and pull the phone's
GPS history
from that day, that night.
Once I know where
the killer went,
I'll know if there's more
to the story.
If you look hard enough,
you'll find
there's more
to every story.
But that doesn't mean
you should.
****
It's your present that demands
your attention, not your past.
(CELLPHONE VIBRATING)
You're right, Mierce.
(CELLPHONE BEEPS)
But please give it
to him anyway.
Harold?
I missed your call.
Sorry for all
the back-and-forth.
That's why I was calling,
actually. Back-and-forth.
What do you know
about professional tennis?
Sam Rhode.
Number eight in the world.
At 36, he was playing
the best tennis
of his career.
Now he's dead.
Well, there was rumors
he was juicing.
I guess now we know.
Not according to Reddington.
The M.E. said Rhode OD'd
on a synthetic oxygen carrier
designed to increase stamina,
but it gave him
a heart attack instead.
The M.E.'s focused
on how Rhode died,
not why.
Reddington says the "why"
involves this man,
Dr. Razmik Maier.
A German pharmacologist
whispered to be responsible
for keeping two generations
of world-class athletes
a step ahead of WADA.
Giving East Germans steroids
during the Cold War,
EPO to U.S. cyclists
in the '90s,
and hemoglobin-based
oxygen carriers
to the Russian Federation
in 2014.
If Maier devoted his career
to helping athletes win
and if they were
his clients,
why would he suddenly
want to kill one?
Because that's what
his biggest client
wants him to do.
Who's bigger than
the 8th-ranked
player in the world?
The Boswell Syndicate,
a family-run sports book
catering to the decidedly
criminal element
who are unable or unwilling
to satisfy their predilection
in the betting parlors
of Vegas, Macao, or Monaco.
And Maier is in business
with them?
Rumor has it the Boswells,
James and Junior,
pay Dr. Maier
a significant fee
in exchange
for inside information,
who's doping,
where they are in their cycle.
Inside information
is one thing.
Murder's another.
A generation ago,
the Boswells controlled
the nation's sports book.
But betting on sports
has exploded since then,
in casinos, online.
Three years ago,
the Supreme Court
struck down laws
prohibiting states from
authorizing sports betting.
As a result, the Boswells'
once-hefty profit margins
all but evaporated.
To retain business,
they cut their vig,
but their ability
to survive an outcome
that exposed them
to large losses
was terribly compromised.
So instead of putting a finger
on the scale,
I'm told they enlist
their German friend
to put the full weight
of everything he knows on it.
Supposedly Dr. Maier
still provides
the Boswells
inside information,
but, in what Reddington says
are a few select cases,
he "accidentally"
overdoses a player
whose performance
might wipe them out.
Players like Sam Rhode
who were already working
with Maier,
so it was easy to make
their murder look accidental.
Aram, review Reddington's
theory with the M.E,
see if it holds up.
Ressler, Park,
talk to Rhode's parents.
See if they know anything
about Dr. Maier.
Reddington's gonna
take the lead
with the Boswells,
and he asked you
to join him.
Did he say why?
He did not.
Maybe he wants to talk
about the good old days?
(TELEPHONE RINGS IN DISTANCE)
So, you went to visit Liz.
How was that?
It was good.
Long overdue.
What I mean is, I know
you're still struggling
and I'm hoping that going
to the cemetery...
I'm hoping it helped.
You know what? It did.
I thought it was gonna have
the opposite effect, but, uh,
I'm good. I'm...
Well, the fancy word for it
is, uh, "titrating."
I'm weaning myself off.
It's hard, but, uh,
the light at the end
of the proverbial tunnel,
I can see it now.
And I can see your face.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm glad you shaved.
I'll take it as a sign that
you've got nothing to hide.
(DOOR OPENS)
****
Ani, got a sec?
No, I don't,
definitely not for you.
Any comment
on Sam Rhodes?
Seriously. I told you
to stop contacting me!
Tell me what you know
before someone else
"accidentally" dies.
I'm not gonna
tell you again.
Leave me alone.
Or I will call the police.
STELLA: Is winning
that important to you?
That you'd cover
for Maier?
I'm not gonna
tell you again.
Ani!
Ani, come on!
(DOOR CLOSES)
(GRUNTS)
You have too many questions.
I know about the letter,
that you showed it
to Elizabeth.
It made her happy.
And hours later,
she was dead.
All the more reason
to have told her.
Unless telling her is one
of the reasons why she died.
What does that mean?
****
(FINGERS SNAPPING)
Hey. Hey! Stella!
You got 10 minutes to give me
everything you've got
on your doping story.
Ten minutes,
or the 20 milliliter
of iron
I gave you will kill you.
You give me your notebooks,
your laptop, your passwords,
I give you adrenaline.
I get what I want, and you get
the antidote you need.
****
Go up to 10,000.
It's got to be now.
MAN: It starts at 3:00.
(BROKERS CHATTERING)
(TELEPHONES RINGING)
Junior!
That's right.
On his shoes coming untied.
You! Go out!
Oh, dear.
Here I was hoping time
would heal this wound.
If we set the odds right,
people will bet
on his hair
lighting on fire.
Speaking of odds.
What are the odds
you take one more step,
I blow your head off?
What's this?
Bartman.
That ball was destroyed.
Uh-huh.
And the moon
is made of ribs.
This doesn't make up for
Professor Tannenbaum's
disappearance.
(CHUCKLES)
The man was an alcoholic.
Plying him with mai tais
and getting him to place
his hard-earned money on ships
that would never come in
was not your finest moment.
Yes, my relocation of him
cost you some ill-gotten gain,
but now he's sober,
you have the Bartman ball,
peace on earth,
goodwill toward men.
You got authentication
for this?
I do.
And I'll give it to you
right after you've
heard me out.
****
Wakefield City
starts in ten.
You got five.
It'll only take one.
Is the Wakefield game
on the level?
As far as I know.
Why?
Junior, this is Kenny Mills.
We're associates.
Or were, until we had
a falling-out
over a mutual friend.
After her death, he spiraled
and, like our friend
Tannenbaum,
turned in sorrow
to your fine establishment.
If you check your records,
you'll see he placed
a $50,000 money-line wager
on the Wakefield City match.
As a down payment
on what I hope will be
our renewed friendship,
I promised Kenny
I'd make sure
you weren't artificially
sweetening the outcome.
You or Dr. Maier.
Maier?
I haven't heard from him in,
oh, at least two years.
And here I've heard
you were working together.
Well, you heard wrong.
Whatever he's doing,
he's not doing it for me.
Forgive my ignorance,
but who is Bartman?
An innocent man
wrongly accused.
His life gets ruined.
Then time heals,
people apologize.
Kind of like
me and Red here.
Sounds like maybe
you guys, too?
Maybe. Maybe not.
****
Make sure you give me
everything.
****
(GROGGILY)
The truth will come out.
Perhaps, but it won't be
from you.
****
(GROANING)
(WHEEZES)
****
We're very sorry
for your loss,
but we do appreciate
you speaking with us.
Thank you
for saying that.
We're just, um...
(VOICE BREAKING)
Sorry.
It's too much.
(SOBBING)
Losing him,
then you telling us
he might have been killed?
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
Who would do that?
I'm sorry I'm late.
LOREEN: Oh.
KEN: No, please.
Come in.
This is our dear friend
Walker Burgos.
Yeah, my, uh...
My company sponsored Sam.
Athlanta.
The, uh, shoes, right?
And athletic wear, yes.
But, uh, when I met Sam,
it was just shoes, yeah.
He was
our first endorsement.
He felt like
a little brother of sorts.
This man's name
is Razmik Maier.
We have reason to believe
he provided Sam
with the drugs
used to kill him.
Do you know him?
No.
(SOBBING)
Let me get you some tissues.
Uh, is your restroom
this way?
It is. Thanks.
Thank you.
Anything?
BURGOS: I know of him.
Yeah. Everyone
in my business does.
And anyone with any sense
knows to stay away from him.
(DOOR CLOSES)
****
Oh. Thank you.
You said, uh...
(CLEARS THROAT)
You said you had
"reason to believe"
all this.
Who gave you that reason?
Was it that reporter?
Reporter?
She was always
asking questions,
making accusations.
Sam, he wouldn't
jay-walk as a kid.
He was a rule-follower.
There's no way
he'd be involved with
someone like that.
The reporter.
Do you know her name?
No idea.
We refused to talk to her.
Walker, help me out here.
Sam told me about her.
Um, said she was a doctor
of some sort.
Uh, worked for
medical journals,
uh, did pieces
on health and fitness.
Uh, he said her name was, um,
S-Stella. Stella Huang.
LOREEN: She the one
trying to convince you
that our boy used drugs
to cheat?
We haven't spoken
to Miss Huang,
but if she knows anything
that'll help us figure out
what happened to Sam,
perhaps we should.
Do you have her number
or know where she works?
She could be in danger.
I don't,
but it's possible
my office does.
Yes, I'll...
Let me give them a call.
Thanks, Walker.
Yeah. Of... Of course.
And if there's anything else
that you can think of
that I can help you with,
then please feel free to call.
****
Stella Huang. FBI.
Miss Huang?
****
I'm having trouble
feeling a pulse.
RESSLER: It's clear.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(CELLPHONE BEEPS AND DIALS)
This is Special Agent
Alina Park.
We need EMTs.
2440 Junior Terrace.
(BREATHING SHARPLY)
****
PARK: What is that?
What are you
talking about?
Show me.
And if you say "what,"
I swear on my mother's grave
I'll report you as a thief.
Alright, alright. You win.
Put it back.
I preferred the beard.
At least you were honest
about having something
to hide.
Hang on, Stella.
Help's coming.
Stella Huang died
on her way to the ER.
What do we know about her?
Not much.
She was an M.D.
who did health reporting.
She also had
a sports-medicine podcast.
When I asked Sam Rhode's
parents about Maier,
they assumed it was
because I had spoken
to Huang.
It was clear that
she had figured out
there was a connection.
Maier was so good,
the doping agencies
couldn't catch him.
But Stella Huang did,
so it makes sense that
he killed her because of it.
So how do the Boswells
fit into this?
They don't.
Raymond was right.
They did work with Maier.
But that ended years ago.
Maier acted alone?
If she had evidence
that Maier was doping
Sam Rhodes
or anyone else,
whoever killed her took it.
Stella was drugged.
Not a PED, but, still,
it points to Maier.
I agree. She knew
about his involvement,
so he silenced her.
ARAM: But, uh,
he didn't silence her.
Was something
in the apartment?
No. Or her clothes
or her car.
But there was
something in her.
In her?
Yeah.
Like inside her.
The M.E. found
this flash drive
in her intestinal tract.
Can you extract any data?
Uh, maybe.
Give or take
a little gastric acid.
Let us know
when you have something.
Dembe, Ressler,
go back to the family
and see if they can
tell you any more
about the connection
between their son Sam
and Dr. Maier.
It was clear their family
didn't know much.
But there was someone there
who might, Walker Burgos.
The CEO of Athlanta?
Yeah. How do you know
about him?
Uh, his company.
Last year I signed up for
a triathlon. I didn't do it.
The whole "peeing while
riding your bike" thing
was just, uh,
too intimidating.
But, anyway, I got really
into the idea of running
and bought sunglasses,
those sunglasses.
The ones
Sam Rhode endorses,
along with everything else
he's wearing.
Burgos said he spoke to Sam
about the reporter.
He offered to help us
in any way he could.
That's a generous offer.
I think you should
take him up on it.
Do you mind if I punt this
to Aram and Dembe?
Alina's having another
one of her, uh, headaches.
I want to make sure
she's okay.
Of course.
I'm sure she'll
appreciate your concern.
****
(DOOR OPENS)
How's your headache?
I don't have a headache.
I told Cooper I did
so I didn't have
to be around you.
(SIGHS)
I don't have an excuse.
But I do have
an explanation.
I'm sure you do.
I'm sure you have
a thousand explanations.
But not one that
could explain how
you could be such a dick.
You do know my marriage
is hanging by a thread,
that I got zapped
by a next-gen weapon
that can kill people
through walls,
that I had a miscarriage
for God's sake,
but still I found the time
to invest in you,
in your problem,
in trying to fix it,
which, of course, is the last
thing I should have done,
helping you
cheat the drug test
so you wouldn't
lose your job to addiction
like my mom lost hers.
(SIGHS)
She fell apart after that,
so I figured,
if I helped you,
you wouldn't.
Well, I'm done
helping you.
And if you
don't help yourself,
I'll tell Cooper
about the drug test.
Yeah, you tell Cooper
that you helped me cheat,
you're gonna be in just
as much trouble as I am.
That's right. It's called
taking responsibility
for your actions.
Something you're
clearly incapable of.
Shut the door
on your way out.
****
(DOOR OPENS)
(MOUSE CLICKS)
LEW: Fast forward
to 13:34.
Stop.
Now play it from there.
And the second you look away
you see you look away,
look what he does,
the bartender.
(MOUSE CLICKS)
Why?
I see it, but I still
can't believe it.
Or understand it.
Yeah, well,
our plan was to I.D.
who did it
and then find out why.
And now we have a lead.
His name is Abel Judge.
You find him,
and you're one step closer
to finding out
who's threatening your life
and your livelihood.
****
Before we go any further,
I just want to thank you.
What has happened
is unimaginable,
and the attention
that you are giving it
means the world to me
and to my company.
We were talking about
Stella Huang.
Sam talked to me
about her,
that she was alleging
he worked with Maier.
He denied it, but...
You believe he was doping.
I do.
At his age, what he was doing.
I should have said something.
But when he won,
my company won,
so I didn't.
And I have to
live with that,
not having the courage
to speak out against
the doping
that is such a cancer
on sports.
And apparently Stella Huang
had the courage that I lack
because what she was doing,
trying to expose
a man like Razmik Maier,
I admire her
for doing that.
Do you know anyone else
who Maier might be
working with?
Any of the other athletes
that you sponsor?
I don't. I'm sorry.
You might not know,
but whoever's doing this does.
They stole Stella's
notes and computer.
We're gonna need a list
of all the athletes
you sponsor.
Of course. If you'd like,
I can call the office
right now
and have them
send the list over.
Thank you.
We'll give you
some privacy.
When you're finished,
we'll be outside.
(DOOR OPENS)
Thank you.
(CELLPHONE BEEPS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hey. Can I please get
a list of all of the athletes
we sponsor?
Names and numbers.
Oh, also, um, Ani Bolin.
Does she still live in Philly?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CHUCKLING)
No, no, no, no, no, no.
(CHUCKLES)
(SPEAKING ENGLISH)
What's going on?
Cosecha Mayas.
Your favorite restaurant.
Sorpresa! Ha!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(LAUGHS)
(SPEAKING ENGLISH)
Since we can't be in Flores,
I thought we'd bring it here.
Raymond called,
said you missed home,
and my tamales.
The next thing I know,
a car shows up,
takes me to the airport,
and here I am.
I'm missing
some coriander.
Weecha can take you
to the market.
You can get
whatever else you need.
I hope you're hungry.
I plan on making a feast.
(CHUCKLES)
** De ti ya no quiero saber
****
(DOOR CLOSES)
** Anda y da la media vuelta
You were so down
this morning.
I'm hoping this will
raise your spirits.
** Agarra tus cosas
y vete de aqui
** Y Fuiste mala conmigo**
Tadashi left you this.
He said he found
what you asked for.
The rest of the story.
You want to raise my spirits?
Don't look.
Nothing good
will come from it.
Why does it bother you?
It's important to me.
But it upsets you.
Why is that?
I appreciate what you did,
bringing Herman.
But I don't want us to be
eating his food here.
I want us to be there.
The way we were.
And you think that this
prevents that.
I think it will.
If you open it.
****
Burgos gave us a list of
the Athlanta-sponsored
athletes.
So far, no one knows,
or is willing to say
they know,
anything about Maier.
Well, Reddington
was wrong about
the Boswells.
Maybe he's wrong
about Maier, too.
And what,
there's another
explanation
for why Stella Huang
was killed?
Well, we have a theory
why she was killed
but not an explanation.
She was killed by Maier
because he was afraid
of being exposed,
of being found out.
DEMBE: But what about
the tennis player?
You think that's reason enough
for Maier to kill an athlete
when he's devoted his life
to helping them?
I do. In my experience,
people will do almost anything
to hide
what they're ashamed of.
Well, experience is one thing,
and facts are another.
At this point,
we don't have any.
Okay. Okay, okay.
The way she swallowed
the flash drive?
Uh, first of all, wow, right?
Talk about dedication.
Based on where it was found
in her intestinal tract,
the M.E. says she swallowed it
five minutes before she died.
PARK: While her killer
was destroying evidence,
she was hiding some.
ARAM: You want evidence?
Check this out.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Now, most of the information
was destroyed by
her stomach acid.
Fun fact,
did you know that acidity
is measured on a pH scale
from zero to 14,
with stomach acid
clocking in at a one,
just above battery acid?
Were any of the files
uncorrupted?
Oh. Yeah. Right, right.
And they showed this.
****
COOPER: So, what do
these tell us?
PARK: That Maier
was the killer.
And he's not done killing.
Who's the unsub?
Ani Bolin,
a top middle-distance runner
and one of Athlanta's
biggest stars.
Now, during my flirtation
with being a triathlete,
I studied her form.
Kind of got obsessed
with it, actually.
The length of her stride,
pounds per square inch
every time she pushed off.
Basically, the way she flies
was so depressingly impossible
for me to approximate
that I decided
to stick with
what I'm good at.
Cycling, right?
Orange sherbet.
Dembe, Park,
get Bolin's address
and roll out.
Ressler, call Burgos.
Have him contact his athlete
and get her to sit tight.
There have been two victims.
There isn't gonna be a third.
(CELLPHONE DIALING)
Mr. Burgos.
Donald Ressler.
I need you to reach out
to Ani Bolin.
It's Maier.
He's targeting her,
isn't he?
We think he might be.
But that's why I'm calling.
I want you to let her know
that there's nothing
to worry about.
We're on our way.
I'll call her right now.
Thanks for the heads-up.
(CELLPHONE RINGS AND BEEPS)
Hello?
Ani. It's me.
I just spoke to the FBI.
Thank God. It's about time
they get involved.
I-I don't want
to get caught,
but I don't want to end up
like Sam, either.
You won't end up like Sam.
Or Stella.
She was a pain in the ass,
but, oh, my God!
Ani, listen to me.
I told the FBI
that I would stay with you
until they got here.
H-Here?
What, are you in Philly?
I am, for an important meeting
that involves you, actually.
Okay, I'm not interested
in meetings.
I just want to know
why this is happening.
Do you even know
where Maier is?
No.
I haven't heard from him
at all.
Just sit tight.
Help is on the way.
(CELLPHONE BEEPS)
****
(RUSTLING)
(DRAWER SLIDES)
You're packing.
I want to go home.
I love you,
but I'm afraid
of this place,
what it does to you
and to Weecha.
I can't watch what
it's turning you into.
****
I want you, Mierce.
Yes.
And you want this.
****
Can't they co-exist?
In some people.
Not in you.
It consumes you.
It'll be over soon.
It was over when we met.
****
I thought it was.
I was wrong.
You're better than this.
This should not define you.
You know what Elizabeth
was to me,
who she was to me.
Yes.
Which is why I know
you have to let go.
Not of her,
but of your anger.
Your need for revenge.
It's going to kill others.
I don't want it
to kill you.
****
Please let go.
Don't do it for me.
Do it for you.
****
If I do that,
will you stay?
I would.
But if I stay, you won't.
****
I should finish packing.
ANI: What the hell
is going on?
The reporter, Stella Huang,
found out about Maier,
started asking questions.
Maier got spooked.
He started covering
his tracks.
By killing Sam and Stella?
That's insane.
Well, of course it is.
But he's not going
to find you.
I promise you we're safe.
I will protect you.
Yeah, until the whole
world finds out that
I was one of his clients.
Everyone will know
that I was doping.
And there's no keeping me
safe from that.
Ani, you don't
have to worry.
Wait.
You're the one
who hooked me up with him.
You said that my contract
was contingent upon results,
knowing that the only way
I could get those results
was through Maier.
Are you telling me
you didn't like
those results?
I'm not...
The sub four minute 1,500?
The prize money,
the added attention?
You became famous.
I sold more shoes.
But the only difference is now
he's coming after me, not you.
I told you, you don't
have to worry about Maier.
But you also told me that
he's covering his tracks.
Sam. Stella.
He got to them.
How can you be so sure
that he's not gonna
come for me, too?
Because I am here
and I won't let anything
happen to you.
Okay?
Come here.
****
Is that Maier's bag?
I thought you said
you hadn't heard
from him...
(GRUNTING)
****
I'm afraid
I lied about that.
****
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
BURGOS:
Open up. It's me.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Open up.
The FBI knows.
Not everything, but enough.
They're coming to talk to her.
I bought us some time,
30 minutes, no more.
I got everything.
All her work.
Ani's the only one left
who knows.
(SIGHS) Ani...
And you.
Wh... What are you doing?
The FBI asked me about you.
They know you're involved.
People have been after me
for years.
The FBI will find out,
and when they do,
they could find me.
And that's not
gonna happen.
Let's go.
Burgos...
Move!
****
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
PARK: Miss Bolin! FBI!
Miss Bolin?
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
(DOOR OPENS)
Miss Bolin? FBI!
Ani?
****
Please tell me
we're not too late.
Low pulse.
Loss of consciousness.
(SNIFFS) Okay.
It's chloroform.
We're late.
But we're not too late.
Call the paramedics.
I'm going after Maier.
(CELLPHONE DIALING)
Okay, this is Special Agent
Aram Mojtabai with the FBI.
We need a team
at 32 Cottage Grove Ave.
(DOOR CLOSES)
No. It's...
It's me, Walker.
I came as fast as I could.
****
What happened?
Maier.
We came in, he went out.
Well, don't let him
get away. Go.
I-I've got her. I'll call 911.
I already called them.
The paramedics
should be here soon.
Go! Please.
Thank you. Thank you.
RESSLER: So, we've been going
through Stella Huang's files.
There weren't just photos.
There was documents, receipts.
She knew who Maier
met with and who was
paying for his work.
That's Maier
with Walker Burgos.
Yeah, and these
are the e-mails
and text threads proving
that Maier was on Burgos'
payroll, that his supplies
and the facility
he worked from were paid for
by an Athlanta slush fund
controlled by Burgos.
The reporter
knew everything,
that Burgos paid Maier
to juice the athletes.
Publishing that would destroy
Burgos and his company.
Alert Park and Aram,
let them know
there's another suspect
we have to be on
the lookout for.
Burgos is with her now.
Anything?
No. Which is weird.
The way the apartment looked,
I would've sworn
he could not have gotten far.
(CELLPHONE RINGING)
It's Ressler.
Ani should be fine,
but Maier's gone.
It's not just Maier.
It's Burgos. They're
working together.
Say that again.
Burgos played us.
He got us to tell him
everything we knew
about Bolin.
But it's a good thing that
you got there before him.
ARAM: Oh, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
Aram, what is it?
Did you copy?3
****
(GRUNTS)
(GUN COCKS)
Drop it! Put it down.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
****
Now!
(GRUNTING)
****
(GUN COCKS)
It's over.
(PANTING)
****
(SIGHS)
She's just running an errand.
She'll be right back.
(DOOR OPENS)
Great! Just in time.
Herman,
it looks delicious.
****
Have you looked?
We can talk
about that later.
You looked.
I told Weecha to get
a new bouquet each week
and put them in water.
After five days,
send me a picture.
Depending on
what they look like,
I'll know
what to do for you.
(WATER RUNNING)
(WATER STOPS)
****
How are you
going to leave?
Do you want me
to drive you somewhere?
I called a car.
I'll drive you.
I'd prefer not.
****
I need you, Mierce.
I know, Raymond.
****
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
****
When I was a child,
my parents took me
to Greece,
to see the wonders
of the world.
I slept through
the Parthenon,
I was bored to tears
at Thermopylae,
but when I got to Olympia
and saw the remains of
the first Olympic stadium,
I was overwhelmed.
If you're ramping up
to ask me a question, don't.
I'm not saying anything
without a lawyer.
As a general rule, yes,
questions are part of
interrogating a suspect,
but in your case,
a lot of our questions
have been answered.
Well, then, as I'm not
the least bit interested
in your summer vacations,
there's nothing to discuss.
Sports predates math.
History began with writing,
and sports began
7,000 years before
people learned to write.
Sports isn't just
as old as man.
It is essential
to mankind.
And you perverted it,
you and Maier and everyone
who takes something
so pure and elegant
and... And fair,
and cheats.
(DOOR OPENS)
Thanks, Louis.
Yeah, we found your car.
And Maier.
And all the evidence
you took from Stella Huang.
There is evidence here
that shows
you were juicing
thirty-two athletes.
See, you thought Stella Huang
only knew about Sam and Ani.
But she knew everything.
And now so do we.
Why don't you start
from the beginning?
****
Going to the cemetery only
made things harder,
not easier.
I mean, if there was a light
at the end of the tunnel,
visiting Liz only
made it harder to see.
When I put back
the prescription pad,
I had already
torn off a page.
I used it to get these.
****
You can't do this alone,
weaning yourself off,
titrating.
It's like handcuffing yourself
to your desk at night
just to keep from
falling off the wagon.
You need help,
help I can't give you
because I don't know how,
so when I try,
I only make things worse.
I know you're
going through a lot,
and I don't want
to add to your burdens,
but it's just,
I'm asking you, please,
don't give up on me.
Okay?
****
(KNOCKING AT DOOR
AND DOOR OPENING)
We executed a search warrant
on Athlanta.
And Ani Bolin,
her doctors say
they expect her
to make a full recovery.
This came for you,
from Reddington.
Thanks.
Was I right? About why
he wanted you to work
with him?
Was it about
the good old days?
It was definitely
about the old days.
Good? Not so much.
Well, you did good work
on this case.
You all did.
Thank you.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
****
REDDINGTON: That's where
you told Elizabeth.
In a coffee shop.
Based on when I asked you
to give her the letter
after I'm dead
and the time stamp
on the photos,
it took you just over an hour
to betray me.
We already discussed this,
that I told her.
The photos came
from Vandyke's phone.
I asked Tadashi
to pull GPS coordinates,
to see where Vandyke
had gone
in the hours
before he shot Elizabeth.
Tadashi found the coordinates,
but then he found these.
And, yes, the images
themselves only confirm
what you and I have
already discussed.
What we haven't discussed,
what the photos really show,
is that the man who killed
Elizabeth, a man you knew,
was 20 feet from you,
taking your picture,
and you were so intent
on your betrayal
that you missed him,
and in missing him,
you failed to protect
both me and her.
****
How did Vandyke know
where we'd be that night?
How is it that he was waiting
for us at the restaurant?
No one knew
we'd all be there
except for Elizabeth
and you and me.
Yet there he was,
and now we know why.
Your job
wasn't to tell my story
the way
you wanted it told.
Whether or not you were
at peace with my decision
was irrelevant
to what I hired you to do.
You had a job.
And for decades,
you did it better
than anyone
possibly could.
Until you didn't.
You could sense a threat
a mile away.
But the biggest threat?
Standing 20 feet away?
You missed him.
And Elizabeth is dead
because of that.
****
Elizabeth is dead
for many reasons.
Pull over.
But it looks like as if
one of those reasons is me.
****
Get out.
** Tear it down
****
(VEHICLE DOOR CLOSES)
** Bring that rotten tree
** To the ground
****
Should we go home?
Do you think
she'll come back?
Not unless your investigation
into Elizabeth's death
is over.
Is it?
****
It's just beginning.
** All these apples
bad as they can be
****
** Blood in the soil
** Bitter seed
** Tear it down
****
** Mmm
(CELLPHONE BEEPS AND DIALS)
(LINE RINGS)
PARK: Hi. This is Alina.
Leave a message,
and I'll call you back.
(BEEPS)
First of all,
you don't make things worse.
You call me out,
hold me responsible.
(SIGHS LIGHTLY)
I need that.
I also need you to try
to get to work early tomorrow.
Doesn't matter what time.
I'll be here.
Thank you.
****
(CELLPHONE CHIMES)
** Pull it up
** Rip it out
** From the root
****
** Mmm
** Got an axe in my hand
and the truth on my side
****
** And I'm gonna swing it
for every tear that I've cried
****
** Your shade is darkness
** It's no shelter for me
** Rotten tree
** Oh
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
** Oh **
(RINGING CONTINUES)
** Oh
MALE VOICE:
Congratulations, Harold.
Now you have the blood
of two men on your hands.
Who are you?
Who is...
(LINE CLICKS AND BEEPS)
** Bring that rotten tree
(RECEIVER CLATTERS)
** To the ground
****
** Tear it down **