Who exactly
is your client?
Jorge De Guzman.
I quit Schweikart & Cokely.
Pro bono means no money,
so what's the plan here?
Put your phone down
so I can hear.
Tell me what happened.
You have bigger problems than
if you trust Saul Goodman.
Change of plans.
I think we should
get out of here.
He took Varga with him.
We should find a way
to pull him out of there.
He's earned
some consideration.
He's a man
on the inside.
Our actions
must be unimpeachable.
Lalo Salamanca
is going to die.
So we're safe?
Yeah.
What if Howard does something
terrible, like misconduct?
You know what that'd mean
for Sandpiper?
You could help a lot of people.
I-I get it.
But you would not
be okay with it.
Wouldn't I?
Yeah.
Where are you?
I don't know.
I've been --
I've been heading north
for about two hours.
I crossed a river
maybe an hour ago.
Anybody see you?
No.
Keep it that way.
You're in
Salamanca territory.
Everybody's gonna be
on the lookout for you.
And I mean everybody.
That includes
the Federales.
Is it done?
Yeah. He's dead.
There were some, uh,
regular people
at that house.
Some old folks.
What about them?
Got no information
on that.
When we hang up,
take the battery
outta your phone.
Head north.
Stay out of sight.
I'm fixing up a place
for you to lie low.
In an hour, you put
the battery back in.
And I'll call you,
tell you where to go.
Don Eduardo!
Ahh.
ZZ?
Hey, Mateo.
No.
Hey.Hey.
So, uh,
what's on the agenda?
Uh, well,
I just got 20 new clients
from Grant, so...
Twenty.
Yeah.
I have meetings
with four of them this afternoon
and a preliminary hearing
with Flaherty first thing.
Juvenile.
What about you?
Mm.
Same thing.
Huge day.
Yes, your mother
and your grandmother.
If they can take time off
from work, both of them...
Do you have
any uncles or...
Oh, yeah.
That would be great.
Do you have anything nice
to wear...?
Like a sports coat
or a...
Hey.
A collared shirt...?
You know what?
I'll bring something
for you.
That's too nice.
No. It's no problem.
Do you know
how to get there?
Tijeras and Fifth.
That's right.
Yes.
Alright.
I will meet you
at30 sharp.
It's gonna be fine,
Ronnie.
Well, tell them
it's gonna be fine.
Because it will be.
Okay.
Thanks.
I'll bring it
back clean.
Do you have any cash
for the taxi?
Crap, all's I've got
is five bucks.
Um...
You think the cabbie'll
break a hundred?
Good morning, Don Juan.
Lalo Salamanca
is dead.
Gunmen broke into his hacienda
last night.
Hired operators
from the look of it.
It was messy.
Very messy.
As for the Salamancas...
"Sangre por sangre."
Yes.
That is the Salamanca way.
We are on the verge
of chaos.
But who did this?
One minute, I hear talk
of the Colombians,
the next...traitors.
Traitors close to home.
We know this much.
Ignacio Varga is a rat.
Don Eladio has put a price
on his head.
Every man we have
is searching for him.
When Varga's found, we'll know
who he was working for.
I assume Don Hector
has been told.
I called him myself.
As for if he understood me,
quién sabe.
Listen to me.
You must be careful,
Gustavo.
This is
a dangerous time.
No one
is above suspicion.
I understand.
Good.
Tell me again
about the sicario
who made the final report.
He was already wounded
when he talked to our cut-out.
Federales found him
dead at the scene.
But they got Salamanca.
The mercenaries
are dead.
To a man.
And yet their mission
was a success.
It has been known
to happen.
I could go down there and
get Varga, bring him home safe.
There's ways to do it
on the quiet.
Unless you already have
something in the works.
Speak your mind.
Loyalty goes
both ways.
Varga has done everything
you asked him.
He wasn't given a choice.Maybe so.
But he played a tough game
and he played it on the square.
And?
When all is said
and done...
The kid deserves
your respect.
He has it.
Is there more
you wish to say?
I hope this brings your guy
more luck than it brought me.
You good?
I'm great.
Detective!
Miss Khalil.
Good morning.
I've been calling you
for two days.
Oh.
My girl's out sick.
What can I do you for?
Tomorrow morning.
00 a.m.
Brunch?
With just you and me, right?
I mean, won't the big fella here
feel like a third wheel?
You and I are meeting Parson
in chambers.
I am asking
for an emergency hearing
to alter the terms
of De Guzman's release.
Sounds like a blast.
Unfortunately,
I'm booked solid.
I checked your client's
place of residence.
The address he gave?
It's a Dairy Queen
in Alta Monte.
The family that showed at the
bail hearing can't be located.
No driver's license,
no tax rolls,
no school records.
Nothing.
Fact is, there isn't
a single Elizabeth McKinnon
under the age of 73
living in New Mexico.
Well, this is --
this is surprising.
Your client
has disappeared,
and I'm not waiting six weeks
to start looking for him.
Hey, my guy put up
seven million in bail.
You think he's just
gonna walk away from that?
Who comes up with
seven million bucks in cash?
You know what I think?
I think
the family was fake,
and I think you knew it
the whole time.
Hold on. Look, just get real
for a second.
The hearing
didn't go your way,
and now you're trying
for a do-over.
You say my guy ran?
I say he's got seven million
reasons for showing up --
when he's legally required
to do so.
So, no,
I won't be, uh,
due process window dressing
at any crash meeting
with Parson.
And if you try throwing
any of this crap around
in front the judge
without my presence --
here's an accusation.
Prosecutorial
misconduct.
Career-ending
prosecutorial misconduct.
None of that changes the fact
the guy's not
who he said he was.No, no, no. Hold on.
You guys got caught with
your pants around your ankles
and somehow
that's on me?
I don't think so.
You've got two dozen lawyers
up there,
you got investigators, you got
the whole damn police force --
and it's my fault
you can't keep track of Lalo?
That is not my job!
Lalo?
Who's Lalo?
What?
What did I say?
I meant De Guzman.
I have more than one client.
So
I will see you at
the preliminary in six weeks.
As scheduled.
Until then,
I have clients who need me.
Nice threads.
Uh, thanks.
Hey.
How'd it go?
The suit
definitely helped.
This kid,
he's a high school senior,
good grades,
works two jobs.
Has this so-called "friend" --
some snot-nosed brat
who drives a brand-new
Mustang convertible.
One Saturday night
Richie Rich says,
"Hey, you wanna
drive my car?"
How can my guy resist?
The "friend" tells him
to pull over at a liquor store.
Rich kid goes in, robs the place
with his uncle's Bowie knife.
No.Yeah.
My guy's out in the Mustang
playing with the radio --
he's got no idea.
Rich kid comes out
with $425 in cash,
a bottle of Jagermeister.
Tells my guy to floor it.
Which he does. Happily.
Because he's completely
in the dark about the robbery.
Yeah, but when they pick them
up, your kid is driving --
He's driving!Of course he's driving.
Yes!
My guy ends up
with the public defender.
Rich kid's family brings in
a top-dollar defense
from out-of-state,
if you can believe it, Denver.
And they're trying to dump
the whole thing on my guy.
It was my client's idea,
he was forcing the rich kid
into it -- the whole deal.
Oakley's going for
aggravated robbery and assault.
Oakley? That dick.Yeah.
But your kid was never
even inside the store!
Flaherty forced joinder --
but I -- I think
I can make it work for us.
Trial's next month.
This was really good.
Have some.
You want anything?
Uh...
You should definitely
try these.
Uh, yeah, sure.
Excuse me,
can we get a menu and another
order of sopaipillas?
You got it.Thank you.
And then there was
a homeless woman
that I had to
get out of MDC.
That's another story.
Sounds like the day from hell.
It was one of the best days
of my life.
My professional life.
How about you?
I...rented us a car.
It's -- It's the Ford.
So, Saul Goodman drives
a brown Ford Taurus?
Detroit calls that taupe,
I believe.
Don't you think
Saul Goodman
would drive something
with a little more...flair?
Such as...?
I don't know.
Definitely American-made.
Something showy.
And Saul Goodman
has an office.
Something eye-catching,
good location.
By the courthouse?
Yeah!
A cathedral of justice.
Oooooh.
Okay. Yeah.
We should start looking
for something for you --
I mean for "Saul."
Sold!
When do we start?
Saturday's good.
Saturday it is.
I was thinking about
our first move.
On the Howard front.
I think there's a way
to get Sandpiper settled
and leave him standing --
bruised, maybe,
but still standing.
Maybe the trick is, we're not
working on Howard, not at first.
Maybe we start
with Cliff Main.
So, uh...
We're doing that?
I thought we were.
Aren't we?
Wh--
You think we shouldn't.
Well, I-I didn't
say that.
Um...
Here we are.
Did you decide
on anything?
Oh, not yet.
Can I get you a drink
while you're thinking about it?
Uh, yeah. A Coke.
Thanks.
All right.
Here you go.
Okay.
So, the, uh --
the Howard thing.
What --
What were you thinking?
You sure?
Yeah.
What's the harm
in listening?
Well...
it has to
be paced right.
We move too fast,
they'll see us coming.
And it has to make sense.
It doesn't have to
stand up in court,
but there has to be a reason
for everything.
Yeah.
I'm at the motel.
No one saw me
but the lady who runs it.
Alright. We're working on
getting you out.
It's gonna take
a couple of days.
I'll call you
when our guys are set up.
They're gonna be driving
a farm truck.
When they pass you,
jump in the back.
It's gonna happen fast,
they're not gonna wait for you.
There's some clothes
in the closet -- wear them.
What happens
between now and then?
Stay out of sight.
Eladio put a price
on your head.
Anyone comes through that door,
you shoot.
You got it?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Thanks!
See, you build it
too high,
your marble's gonna
run off the track.
It's not finished.
When it's finished,
it'll work.
Okay.
May I please have
some more lemonade?
No. You drank about
a gallon already.
Please, Pop-pop.
Alright.
One more and that's it.
Thank you, Pop-pop!
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Oh, wait.
There they are.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
They're on the fourth hole.
Assuming they're
playing nine,
that should give you
about 45 minutes safely.
You gotta teach me
to play golf.
A lawyer should be able
Any time.
You all right?
Yep.
Piece of cake.
Excuse me, sir.
Are you a member or a guest?
I'm just here
for a tour.
Ah. Welcome.
Front desk
is straight ahead.
Hi. I called
about a tour?
Oh, if you'll follow me
to the members' lounge?
Hi. Norm Wakely.
I understand you're
in the market for a tour?
That's right.
Saul Goodman.
Great to meet you,
Mr. Goodman.
Ah, please, call me Saul.Great.
So, Saul, can I get you anything
before we get started?
The coffee here
is just unbeatable.
Uh, well, I'm fine.
I'm fully caffeinated.
Well, Saul, you and I are
standing on hallowed ground.
Five Presidents have played
on our course...
...starting with
Dwight D. Eisenhower.
But the story goes back
even further than that --
Norm, can I have a sec, please?
Kevin, hey,
how's it going?
Uh, I'm sorry, I'm sure
this'll just be a moment.
Mr. Goodman,
I'm so sorry.
But I've just been reminded
that, in fact,
we have a two-year
waiting list.
Two years. Wow.
Maybe I could, uh,
go on the tour anyway,
I mean, 'cause I'm here,
just in case.
Well, unfortunately,
we suspended tours.
For the moment.
You're not even
giving tours?
I apologize
for the inconvenience.
We will be happy to call you
if the situation changes.
You left your number?Uh-huh.
Well, we'll be in touch.
If the situation changes.
Again, I-I'm sorry for your time
and trouble.
Uh, we just --
Oh, God.
We had a few
crossed wires.
Well...
okay then.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
One second.
Yes?
Um, just so I understand,
you were gonna give me a tour
and then you realized
you don't need new members?
We have a waiting list.
Okay, but you're
the membership director,
so you would have
known that before.
I know.It doesn't really add up.
I mean, I came in, and everyone
was rolling out the red carpet
and then, all of a sudden
something changed...
I don't...
Mr. Goodman,
I am the --
Goodman!
The name.
The second you heard it,
everything turned on a dime.
Waiting list?
I think you're talking about
an exclusion list.
It's okay. It's -- I should have
known because, I mean, look.
It's wall to wall mayonnaise
in here!
So, you know, listen,
if you're gonna be restricted,
have the courage
to say so.
There's no question of --Here it is, folks!
Anti-Semitism! Alive and well
right here in Albuquerque.
Sir, we have many
Jewish members --
Oh, good.
Well, you met your quota then.
Gold star for you.
Hold on!
That's gotta be the biggest
load of horse crap
I've ever heard
in my life.
Go crawl back in your hole,
McGill or Goodman,
whatever you're
calling yourself.
What're you up to,
anyway?
Ginning up another one
of your put-up job lawsuits,
you two-faced, blackmailing,
money-grubbing son-of-a-bitch --
"Money-grubbing!"
You're saying the quiet part
out loud, I think.
Gentlemen, can we just
keep the volume down?
You know damn well
that's not what I meant --
In this day and age?
I had hoped and prayed
we'd be beyond this.
You're 'bout as Jewish
as my Aunt Fannie --
Five thousand years
and it never ends.
Here it is --
violence!
It always comes to this!
Mr. Wachtell, please!
Come on, Kev.
Go to hell,
you lying sack of shit.
Sir, Mr. Goodman...
I don't know what to say.
That is not --I wouldn't be a member here.
I wouldn't walk through
those doors again
after what happened
to me here today.
Do you at least have a bathroom
that I could use,
seeing as how my --
Stress like that is hell
on my diverticulitis.
The men's locker room
is the closest.
It's straight
through there.
And I would be allowed
to go in there?
Yes. Of course.
I want you to know
I don't blame you personally.
I know you're just
following orders.
It's okay, folks!
I'm leaving.
All is well.
Good morning, sir.Morning.
Shit. Shit.
Shit. Shit. Shit.
I swear it's nothing I did, but,
uh, one of your toilets is --
I'll take care
of it, sir.
Okay.
It's the middle one.
You can't miss it.Yeah. No -- No problem, sir!
227.
I was losing, Howard.
You put me out of my misery.
Well,
you might not have lost.
Your swing was good.
No better than last time
we played.
Well, keep your head down,
you'll get better.
Anyway, on the topic
of your hiring binge --
Hardly a "binge."
What would you
call it?
I'd call it
"prudent expansion."
We're not headhunting
any of your associates,
if that's what
you're worried about.Okay.
Need a towel?Sure.
Hey.
Listen, on the QT,
I'd be particularly careful
with any lateral hires...
You talking
about what's-his-name,
the guy from Tennessee?
You hear something?
Nothing I'd care to repeat.
Just "trust, but verify."
Fair enough.
Howard...?
What?
Uh, this can't be...
Sure looks like it.
Really?
Not the first time I've seen
one of those. Unfortunately.
Well, where did it
come from?
Didn't it just fall
out of your locker?
I don't see how...
You don't think one of
the members could have...
Maybe somebody on staff.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Oh, my G--
Where were you?
I'll tell you later.
Here they come.
Did they find it?
Yes.
What if they figure out
it's baby powder?
They won't.
I think maybe
we outsmarted ourselves.
Maybe this was all...
too subtle.
Nope. Not too subtle.
Perfect.
Andale.Chop, chop.
We don't got all day, folks.
Dos mil.
I'm gonna need a minute.
Nobody's waiting for you,
big stuff.
Come on.
Be nice.
Hello. Casa Tranquila.
Buenas tardes,
recepción?
I'm sorry. Let me get someone
who speaks Spanish.
Oh, no, no.
No problem.
I would just like to speak
to one of your residents,
if I may.
Hector,
are you awake?
You have another
telephone call.
Hector?
Excuse me, I'm so sorry,
but Hector seems a little upset.
Yeah, sorry.
Um, I'm just --
I'm sharing a bit of family
news, some good, some bad.
Would you mind
putting him back on?
It'll only be a minute.
Of course.
Okay.
A, B, C...
L, M, N, Ñ...
I changed my mind.
I'm not going.
And?
And you give me back
my money.
There's no refunds,
asshole.
I told you.
Be nice.
Amigos...
Abuela...
Con cuidado.
of "Better Call Saul"...
You're the guy,
right?
What guy's that?
Salamanca's guy.
Are you building
some kind of case against Jimmy?
That's a lot big talk.
Prove it.
What Colonel Sanders is
to chicken,
Saul Goodman is
to the law.
It's just you
and me.
Anyone who goes after
him is gonna have
to come through me.
What happens now?
I need to know
everything he does
and everyone
he talks to.
"I'm Saul Goodman. Pow.
I fight for you."